<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T12:02:56.670Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI-powered impact: GitHub Social Impact’s year ahead]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73238</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-23-ai-powered-impact-github-social-impacts-year-ahead/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How GitHub Social Impact is working with nonprofit organizations, employees, and more to create positive, lasting change in global communities.
The post AI-powered impact: GitHub Social Impact’s year ahead appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sidney Espinosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 236: The new AI app stack]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2184</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/236"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently a16z released a diagram showing the “Emerging Architectures for LLM Applications.” In this episode, we expand on things covered in that diagram to a more general mental model for the new AI app stack. We cover a variety of things from model “middleware” for caching and control to app orchestration.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 2 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:
  
Emerging Architectures for LLM Applications
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:43) - Deep dive into LLMs
(02:25) - Emerging LLM app stack
(04:35) - Playgrounds
(08:07) - App Hosting
(10:46) - Stack orchestration
(15:50) - Maintenance breakdown
(19:08) - Sponsor: Changelog News
(20:43) - Vector databases
(22:36) - Embedding models
(24:27) - Benchmarks and measurements
(26:59) - Data & poor architecture
(29:42) - LLM logging
(33:01) - Middleware Caching
(37:32) - Validation
(40:53) - Key takeaways
(42:36) - Closing thoughts
(44:23) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modo Rua: Redefining App Development through User-Centered Iteration]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21287</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/modo-rua-redefining-app-development-through-user-centered-iteration/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T04:07:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Uncover the power of user-centricity and iterative refinement in creating an exceptional application experience.
The post Modo Rua: Redefining App Development through User-Centered Iteration appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BU Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Feedback Makes for Faster Reviews]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/08/testing-on-toilet-presents.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/08/testing-on-toilet-presents.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T18:40:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing on the Toilet Presents...
 Healthy Code on the Commode









Better Feedback Makes for Faster Reviews
by Felipe Sodré and Adam Bender





Have you ever received a code review with a comment like this?



server_is_alive = InitializeServer()



Comment:

This doesn’t make any sense. Why don't you use InitializeServerWithAFewExtraSteps() instead?






If so, it probably left you scratching your head. Why is the reviewer asking this question? Are they testing you? Did you make a big mistake? The problem is the comment is vague (and maybe even a bit rude). It also leaves out important context as to what the reviewer is thinking, making it difficult to respond to. Here are a few simple ways to ensure your review comments are effective, helpful, and clear. 

Be kind! People are more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 58: All your CAPTCHAs are belong to bots]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2183</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/58"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New research shows that CAPTCHAs are now utterly useless, hundreds of concerned technologists signed the OpenTF Manifesto to keep Terraform open source forever, Josh Collinsworth writes down all the things you forgot (or never knew) because of React, Mike Seidle shared some quick-but-powerful advice on building new software features & Erlend Sogge Heggen urges new open source projects to join the Fediverse (by way of Mastodon).
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – On September 7th, Sentry is hosting a discussion with the CEOs of three SaaS companies that adopt an open source strategy for their core product. Register to attend right here.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(01:09) - CAPTCHAs are now utterly useless
(02:10) - The OpenTF Manifesto
(03:06) - Things you forgot (or never knew) because of React
(04:53) - Sponsor: Sentry
(05:44) - Work, Like, Love
(06:31) - Greenfield OSS projects should join Mastodon
(07:37) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highlights from Git 2.42]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73759</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-21-highlights-from-git-2-42/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T17:45:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another new release of Git is here! Take a look at some of our highlights on what's new in Git 2.42.
The post Highlights from Git 2.42 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taylor Blau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and scalability for search]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T12:02:35.634Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we power real-time search for Tweets, Users, Direct Messages and more using Elasticsearch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A “Wicked Problem”: UX Research and the continuous search for framing the problem at Nubank]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21260</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/a-wicked-problem-ux-research-and-the-continuous-search-for-framing-the-problem-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T20:14:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Complexity and importance of understanding the problem, a task often more important than finding a solution.
The post A “Wicked Problem”: UX Research and the continuous search for framing the problem at Nubank appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel Bastos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 11: An aberrant generation of programmers]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2180</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/11"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our friend Justin Searls recently published a widely-read essay on enthusiast programmers, inter-generational conflict & what we do with this information. That seemed like a good conversation starter, so we grabbed Justin and Landon Gray to discuss. Let’s talk!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 7 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops requ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AVA Discovery View: Surfacing Authentic Moments]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/b8cd145491cc</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/ava-discovery-view-surfacing-authentic-moments-b8cd145491cc?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T22:07:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By: Hamid Shahid, Laura Johnson, Tiffany Low]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[mTLS: When certificate authentication is done wrong]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73738</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-17-mtls-when-certificate-authentication-is-done-wrong/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T21:22:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we'll deep dive into some interesting attacks on mTLS authentication. We'll have a look at implementation vulnerabilities and how developers can make their mTLS systems vulnerable to user impersonation, privilege escalation, and information leakages.
The post mTLS: When certificate authentication is done wrong appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Stepankin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 288: Refined thinking]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2174</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/288"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim (Hyphen) Nielsen joins Jerod & Nick for a fun conversation about language-level toll roads, when (and how) to quit, the stratification of social networking & the state of the world in publishing your thoughts on the internet.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 13 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!


Featuring:

Jim Nielsen – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Language-Level Toll Roads
The Art of Knowing When to Quit
Metalsmith
Gorilla is back
Subscribe Wherever You Get Your Content
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:55) - Hello, hello
(02:04) - Welcoming Jim to the show
(05:15) - The trough of AI disillusionment
(06:19) - The Thing of the Moment
(07:25) - Language-level Toll Roads
(22:15) - The art of knowing when to quit
(30:24) - Shout out to Metalsmith
(32:17) - But HOW do you quit?
(38:22) - Stratification of social networking
(43:49) - A podcaster's perspective
(53:13) - On Mastodon
(57:25) - RSS *is* the indie social web
(1:01:33) - Closing time
(1:03:05) - Next up on the pod (Changelog++!)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 553: 30 years of Debian]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2178</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/553"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking with Jonathan Carter who’s on his fourth term as Debian Project Lead (DPL) and we’re talking about 30 years of Debian!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 12 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – Watch Lazar Nikolov livestream on YouTube at youtube.com/@nikolovlazar. Use the code CHANGELOGMEDIA and get the team plan FREE for six (6) months.

Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Ethical Hackers Are Helping Security Leaders Navigate the Budget Crunch]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/ethical-hackers-help-ciso-budget</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/ethical-hackers-help-ciso-budget"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Security leaders are using ethical hackers to help address strains and challenges in their security programs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curbing Connection Churn in Zuul]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/2feb273a3598</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/curbing-connection-churn-in-zuul-2feb273a3598?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T17:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI-Powered Fuzzing: Breaking the Bug Hunting Barrier]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/ai-powered-fuzzing-breaking-bug-hunting.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/ai-powered-fuzzing-breaking-bug-hunting.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T17:02:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dongge Liu, Jonathan Metzman, Oliver Chang, Google Open Source Security Team 




Since 2016, OSS-Fuzz has been at the forefront of automated vulnerability discovery for open source projects. Vulnerability discovery is an important part of keeping software supply chains secure, so our team is constantly working to improve OSS-Fuzz. For the last few months, we’ve tested whether we could boost OSS-Fuzz’s performance using Google’s Large Language Models (LLM). 





This blog post shares our experience of successfully applying the generative power of LLMs to improve the automated vulnerability detection technique known as fuzz testing (“fuzzing”). By using LLMs, we’re able to increase the code coverage for critical projects using our OSS-Fuzz service without manually writing additional code. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward Quantum Resilient Security Keys]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/toward-quantum-resilient-security-keys.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/toward-quantum-resilient-security-keys.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T21:57:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elie Bursztein, cybersecurity and AI research director, Fabian Kaczmarczyck, software engineer




As part of our effort to deploy quantum resistant cryptography, we are happy to announce the release of the first quantum resilient FIDO2 security key implementation as part of OpenSK, our open source security key firmware. This open-source hardware optimized implementation uses a novel ECC/Dilithium hybrid signature schema that benefits from the security of ECC against standard attacks and Dilithium’s resilience against quantum attacks. This schema was co-developed in partnership with the ETH Zürich and won the ACNS secure cryptographic implementation workshop best paper.






Quantum processor





As progress toward practical quantum computers is accelerating, preparing for their advent i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build for today, transform for tomorrow at GitHub Universe 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73688</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-15-build-for-today-transform-for-tomorrow-at-github-universe-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T19:04:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get tickets to our global developer and customer event for 30% off during our Super-Early Bird special, only for a limited time. 
The post Build for today, transform for tomorrow at GitHub Universe 2023 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeimy Ruiz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · July 2023 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73630</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-15-release-radar-jul-23/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T18:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After the last Release Radar, I promised the next one wouldn’t be far away, so here it is. This is the low down on some of the best open source projects that shipped major version updates in July. There’s lots of cool stuff from natural language processing, to APIs, money, and SDKs. I won’t spoil […]
The post Release Radar · July 2023 Edition appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardening repositories against credential theft]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73675</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-15-hardening-repositories-against-credential-theft/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T16:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some best practices and important defenses to prevent common attacks against GitHub Actions that are enabled by stolen personal access tokens, compromised accounts, or compromised GitHub sessions.
The post Hardening repositories against credential theft appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Masarik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn as you search (and browse) using generative AI]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/search/google-search-generative-ai-learning-features/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/search/google-search-generative-ai-learning-features/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New updates to Search Generative Experience (SGE) help people easily learn new things and understand key concepts while searching online.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Twitter uses rasdaemon for hardware reliability]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T12:02:30.055Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[changes from before it was curl]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22890</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/08/15/changes-from-before-it-was-curl/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T06:29:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have the birthday of curl remembered and I often repeat that it was started on March 20 1998. But that’s just the first time we shipped a version of the tool using the name curl. The tool, the code and the idea started before. httpget Back in November 1996 I found the tool httpget … Continue reading changes from before it was curl →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 57: HashiCorp means business (source), why Tailwind won, WarpStream, managing difficult devs & an update on Go 2]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2181</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/57"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HashiCorp adopts a Business Source license, Matt Rickard hypothesizes why Tailwind CSS won, WarpStream sets out to make a Kafka-compatible offering directly on S3, Vadim Kravcenko publishes an excellent guide for managing difficult software engineers & Russ Cox gives an update on Go 2.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:38) - HashiCorp goes Business Source
(02:13) - Why Tailwind CSS won
(03:10) - Kafka is dead, long live Kafka
(04:21) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(05:32) - Managing difficult software engineers
(06:16) - An update on Go 2
(07:15) - Outro (Subscribe!)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are You Ready for the New NIST Control Around Public Disclosure Programs?]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/security-compliance/nist-vdp-control</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/security-compliance/nist-vdp-control"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new NIST control requires SaaS vendors to “establish a public reporting channel for receiving reports of vulnerabilities in organizational systems and system components.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Blake Entrekin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nine years of the GitHub Security Bug Bounty program]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73651</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-14-nine-years-of-the-github-security-bug-bounty-program/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T15:21:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was another record year for our Security Bug Bounty program! We're excited to highlight some achievements we’ve made together with the bounty community in 2022!
The post Nine years of the GitHub Security Bug Bounty program appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jill Moné-Corallo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The data platform cluster operator service for Hadoop cluster management]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/the-data-platform-cluster-operator-service-for-hadoop-cluster-management</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/the-data-platform-cluster-operator-service-for-hadoop-cluster-management"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T12:03:00.327Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As any team and its infrastructure grows, the risk of an unplanned service outage and potential data loss will grow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[COMMA_HACK 4]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/comma_hack_4/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/comma_hack_4/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-12T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[6pm Sept 29 – 6pm Oct 1, 2023 IRL in San Diego, CA]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 10: Kaizen! S3 R2 B2 D2]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2179</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/10"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gerhard joins us for the 11th Kaizen and this one might contain the most improvements ever. We’re on Fly Apps V2, we’ve moved from S3 to R2 & we have a status page now, just to name a few.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 5 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 288: A deep dive into Go's stack]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2170</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/288"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A technical dive into how the Go stack works and why we as programmers should care.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Yarden Laifenfeld – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub
David Chase – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub
Mat Ryer – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:35) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(04:12) - Meeting our guests
(05:45) - Growing lilies
(10:05) - Starting at the basics
(14:13) - Sponsor: Changelog News
(15:23) - When does the stack shrink
(17:59) - Working backwards with memory
(23:38) - Can you be good enough?
(35:59) - The stack vs the heap
(43:10) - When to care about the heap
(56:26) - Measure first, optimize after
(1:00:53) - Unpopular opinions!
(1:01:10) - Yarden's unpop
(1:05:08) - David's unpop
(1:10:24) - Wrapping up
(1:11:30) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 helpful ways to use Bard]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/bard/how-to-use-google-bard/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/bard/how-to-use-google-bard/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Check out 10 ways Bard can help you get things done, from brainstorming ideas to planning trip itineraries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 287: Take me to Val Town]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2121</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/287"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Val Town is a shiny, new social programming environment to write, run, deploy and share code. Steve Krouse –Val Town creator– joins Jerod & Amal to tell us all about it.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 5 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Steve Krouse – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

Val Town
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:55) - Welcoming Steve
(03:22) - A great concept
(13:36) - "Sent from my phone"
(17:24) - What does my code live?
(24:01) - Fraud & abuse
(25:24) - Sponsor: Changelog News
(26:32) - Smart people behind it
(28:33) - The business side of things
(34:01) - Getting your data
(36:58) - Sharing is caring
(38:56) - Discovering Vals
(40:57) - Large Val-based systems
(47:55) - The pricing story
(50:13) - Val's tech stack
(52:05) - Questions from the chat
(55:57) - Security concerns
(58:08) - Closing time
(59:06) - Next up on the pod]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Chrome more secure by bringing  Key Pinning to Android]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/making-chrome-more-secure-by-bringing.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/making-chrome-more-secure-by-bringing.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T16:01:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by David Adrian, Joe DeBlasio and Carlos Joan Rafael Ibarra Lopez, Chrome Security


Chrome 106 added support for enforcing key pins on Android by default, bringing Android to parity with Chrome on desktop platforms. But what is key pinning anyway?


One of the reasons Chrome implements key pinning is the “rule of two”. This rule is part of Chrome’s holistic secure development process. It says that when you are writing code for Chrome, you can pick no more than two of: code written in an unsafe language, processing untrustworthy inputs, and running without a sandbox. This blog post explains how key pinning and the rule of two are related.


The Rule of Two


write Chrome code in Rust, which is also memory-safe.


Much of Chrome is sandboxed, but the sandbox still requires a core hig…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 552: Thinking outside the box of code]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2106</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/552"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T21:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leslie Lamport is a computer scientist & mathematician who won ACM’s Turing Award in 2013 for his fundamental contributions to the theory and practice of distributed and concurrent systems. He also created LaTeX and TLA+, a high-level language for “writing down the ideas that go into the program before you do any coding.”
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 7 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.

Sentry – Watch Lazar Nikolov livestream on YouTube at youtube.com/@nikolovlazar. Use the code CHANGELOGMEDIA and get the team plan FREE for six (6) months.


Featuring:

Leslie Lamport – 
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

Leslie Lamport - A.M. Turing Award Laureate
The Man Who Revolutionized Computer Science With Math - YouTube
TLA+ Helps Programmers Squash Bugs Before Coding - IEEE Spectrum
The TLA+ Home Page
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:56) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(04:32) - Start the show!
(04:53) - Leslie & LaTeX
(07:03) - Separating the ideas
(10:54) - Thinking like a mathematician
(14:02) - Coding is like typing
(21:13) - "Let's get coding"
(25:01) - You don't know until you know
(28:35) - Thinking in algorithms
(34:14) - Sponsor: Sentry
(37:52) - What's different today?
(40:55) - What makes a system distributed
(43:53) - The movie metaphor
(49:51) - Stuttering insensitivity
(52:19) - The Bakery Algorithm
(58:21) - The day of discovery
(1:01:57) - Back to the editor
(1:03:56) - Leslie's work these days
(1:05:20) - Final words
(1:06:07) - Up next...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced push protection features for developers and organizations]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73603</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-09-enhanced-push-protection-features-for-developers-and-organizations/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T19:02:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing two new secret scanning push protection features that will enable individual developers to protect all their pushes and organizations to gain insights and trends across their repositories.
The post Enhanced push protection features for developers and organizations appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zain Malik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: July 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73614</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-09-github-availability-report-july-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T18:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In July, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.
The post GitHub Availability Report: July 2023 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 235: Blueprint for an AI Bill of Rights]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2177</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/235"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T16:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this Fully Connected episode, Daniel and Chris kick it off by noting that Stability AI released their SDXL 1.0 LLM!  They discuss its virtues, and then dive into a discussion regarding how the United States, European Union, and other entities are approaching governance of AI through new laws and legal frameworks.  In particular, they review the White House’s approach, noting the potential for unexpected consequences.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 2 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deplo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four tips to keep your GitHub Actions workflows secure]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73598</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-09-four-tips-to-keep-your-github-actions-workflows-secure/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T16:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers from Purdue and NCSU have found a large number of command injection vulnerabilities in the workflows of projects on GitHub. Follow these four tips to keep your GitHub Actions workflows secure.
The post Four tips to keep your GitHub Actions workflows secure appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaroslav Lobacevski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New SEC Cyber Rules Incentivize Proactive Security Measures]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/security-compliance/new-sec-cybersercurity-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/security-compliance/new-sec-cybersercurity-rules"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) recently finalized a regulation that imposes increased transparency related to cybersecurity risk management, governance, and incidents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ilona Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How AI is helping airlines mitigate the climate impact of contrails]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/ai-airlines-contrails-climate-change/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/ai-airlines-contrails-climate-change/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We used AI to help airlines choose routes that are less likely to cause contrails, minimizing the environmental impact of flights.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downfall and Zenbleed: Googlers helping secure the ecosystem]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/downfall-and-zenbleed-googlers-helping.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/downfall-and-zenbleed-googlers-helping.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T17:00:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tavis Ormandy, Software Engineer and Daniel Moghimi, Senior Research Scientist




Finding and mitigating security vulnerabilities is critical to keeping Internet users safe.  However, the more complex a system becomes, the harder it is to secure—and that is also the case with computing hardware and processors, which have developed highly advanced capabilities over the years. This post will detail this trend by exploring Downfall and Zenbleed, two new security vulnerabilities (one of which was disclosed today) that prior to mitigation had the potential to affect billions of personal and cloud computers, signifying the importance of vulnerability research and cross-industry collaboration. Had these vulnerabilities not been discovered by Google researchers, and instead by adversaries, they w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android 14 introduces first-of-its-kind cellular connectivity security features]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/android-14-introduces-first-of-its-kind.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/android-14-introduces-first-of-its-kind.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T15:59:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Roger Piqueras Jover, Yomna Nasser, and Sudhi Herle


Android is the first mobile operating system to introduce advanced cellular security mitigations for both consumers and enterprises. Android 14 introduces support for IT administrators to disable 2G support in their managed device fleet. Android 14 also introduces a feature that disables support for null-ciphered cellular connectivity.

Hardening network security on Android
False Base Stations (FBS) and Stingrays exploit weaknesses in cellular telephony standards to cause harm to users. Additionally, a smartphone cannot reliably know the legitimacy of the cellular base station before attempting to connect to it. Attackers exploit this in a number of ways, ranging from traffic interception and malware sideloading, to sophistica…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An update on Chrome Security updates – shipping security fixes to you faster]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/an-update-on-chrome-security-updates.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/an-update-on-chrome-security-updates.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T15:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Amy Ressler, Chrome Security Team


To get security fixes to you faster, starting now in Chrome 116, Chrome is shipping weekly Stable channel updates.


Chrome ships a new milestone release every four weeks. In between those major releases, we ship updates to address security and other high impact bugs. We currently schedule one of these Stable channel updates (or “Stable Refresh”) between each milestone. Starting in Chrome 116, Stable updates will be released every week between milestones.


This should not change how you use or update Chrome, nor is the frequency of milestone releases changing, but it does mean security fixes will get to you faster.

Reducing the Patch Gap
Chromium is the open source project which powers Chrome and many other browsers. Anyone can view the sourc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A guide to designing and shipping AI developer tools]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73573</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-08-a-guide-to-designing-and-shipping-ai-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T14:28:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub’s design experts share 10 tips and lessons for designing magical user experiences for AI applications and AI coding tools. 
The post A guide to designing and shipping AI developer tools appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicole Choi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mastering the curl command line]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22806</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/08/08/mastering-the-curl-command-line/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T12:38:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the firs time ever, I am going to present a single, very long, video class with the title shown above. This session will be streamed and recorded live on August 31, starting at 16:00 UTC (18:00 CEST, 09:00 PDT) and is expected to take about two and a half hours. Due to many uncertainties, … Continue reading Mastering the curl command line →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autogenerating Rust-JS bindings with UniFFI]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48021</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2023/08/autogenerating-rust-js-bindings-with-uniffi/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T11:15:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post will walk through how we developed UniFFI: a Rust library for auto-generating foreign language bindings. We will walk through some of the issues that arose along the way and how we handled them.
The post Autogenerating Rust-JS bindings with UniFFI appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Dean-Kawamura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 56: The open source licensing war is over, Tailwind components for your AI app, Mac mini modded to use PoE, Apple joins OpenUSD alliance & picking the worst tool for the job]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2176</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/56"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Asay thinks the open source licensing war is over, LangUI is an open source Tailwind component library for your AI chat app, Ivan Kuleshov modded a Mac mini to run via PoE, Apple joins Pixar and others in the Alliance for OpenUSD & John D. Cook says sometimes you shouldn’t pick the best tool for the job.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – Watch Lazar Nikolov livestream on YouTube at youtube.com/@nikolovlazar. Use the code CHANGELOGMEDIA and get the team plan FREE for six (6) months.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(01:14) - Open source licensing war is over
(02:38) - LangUI for your AI
(03:13) - Mac mini modded with PoE
(04:07) - Alliance for OpenUSD
(05:28) - Sponsor: Sentry
(06:18) - The worst tool for the job
(07:11) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne and the OWASP Top 10 for LLM: A Powerful Alliance for Secure AI]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/owasp-llm-vulnerabilities</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/owasp-llm-vulnerabilities"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is HackerOne’s perspective on the Top 10 list for LLM vulnerabilities and how organizations can prevent these critical security risks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manjesh S.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter’s Blobstore Hardware Lifecycle Monitoring and Reporting Service]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/twitters-blobstore-hardware-lifecycle-monitoring-and-reporting-service</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/twitters-blobstore-hardware-lifecycle-monitoring-and-reporting-service"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T12:02:32.342Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we scaled Reads On the Twitter Users Database]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-we-scaled-reads-on-the-twitter-users-database</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-we-scaled-reads-on-the-twitter-users-database"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T12:02:32.263Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraint Management for cluster operation safety and reliability at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/constraint-management-for-cluster-operation-safety-and-reliability-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/constraint-management-for-cluster-operation-safety-and-reliability-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T12:02:32.252Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As any team and its infrastructure grows, the risk of an unplanned service outage and potential data loss will grow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring the impact of Twitter network latency with CausalImpact]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T12:02:32.232Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share how we adopted the CausalImpact package from Google on a Twitter edge network experiment to measure the impact of improving Twitter's latency on customer engagement and revenue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kerberizing Hadoop Clusters at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/kerberizing-hadoop-clusters-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/kerberizing-hadoop-clusters-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T12:02:32.213Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter's Recommendation Algorithm]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2023/twitter-recommendation-algorithm</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2023/twitter-recommendation-algorithm"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T12:02:32.071Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter aims to deliver you the best of what’s happening in the world right now. This blog is an introduction to how the algorithm selects Tweets for your timeline.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel Binary Transparency: verifiable security for Pixel devices]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/pixel-binary-transparency-verifiable.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/pixel-binary-transparency-verifiable.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T17:49:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Hou, Software Engineer, TrustFabric (transparency.dev) 




Pixel Binary Transparency
With Android powering billions of devices, we’ve long put security first. There’s the more visible security features you might interact with regularly, like spam and phishing protection, as well as less obvious integrated security features, like daily scans for malware. For example, Android Verified Boot strives to ensure all executed code comes from a trusted source, rather than from an attacker or corruption. And with attacks on software and mobile devices constantly evolving, we’re continually strengthening these features and adding transparency into how Google protects users. This blog post peeks under the hood of Pixel Binary Transparency, a recent addition to Pixel security that puts you in cont…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A checklist and guide to get your repository collaboration-ready]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73519</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-04-a-checklist-and-guide-to-get-your-repository-collaboration-ready/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T16:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the world of software development, collaboration can make the difference between a brittle last-minute release and a reliable, maintainable, pain-free project. Whether you’ve been coding for a day or a decade, your colleagues are there to help strengthen your work. But they can only help if you’ve given them the tools to do so.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Peck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clojure’s journey at Nubank: a look into the future]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21242</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/clojures-journey-at-nubank-a-look-into-the-future/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T14:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tech team thanks Rich Hickey for leadership as he retires from his position at Nu. 
The post Clojure’s journey at Nubank: a look into the future appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Quality Automation at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T12:02:24.897Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we share how Twitter implemented a Data Quality Platform that gave customers the ability to have automated data quality checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 551: DX on DX]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2169</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/551"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Adam is joined by Abi Noda, founder and CEO of DX to talk about DX AKA DevEx (or the long-form Developer Experience). Since the dawn of software development there has been this push to understand what makes software teams efficient, but more importantly what does it take to understand developer productivity? That’s what Abi has been focused on for the better part of the last 8 years of his career. He started a company called Pull Panda that was acquired by GitHub, spent a few years there on this problem before going out on his own to start DX which helps startups to the fortune 500 companies gather real insights that leads to real improvement.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 33 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing code referencing for GitHub Copilot]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73497</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-03-introducing-code-referencing-for-github-copilot/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T16:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re announcing a private beta of GitHub Copilot with code referencing that includes a filter to detect code suggestions matching public code on GitHub.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan J. Salva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 286: An intimate conversation about careers]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2166</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/286"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KBall and Amal go deep on careers. They share their career journeys, talk through learnings and mishaps that happened along the way, and break down key factors to understand about big role transitions like “Senior->Staff” as well as “Engineer->Manager”.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 2 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Kevin Ball – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

From engineering to product (JSParty #203)
Bocoup
Amal on The Changelog talking about bossing up
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:40) - Helloooooo!
(02:18) - KBall's career journey
(10:44) - Hiding the ugly bits
(12:56) - Work-life balance
(17:30) - Amal's career journey
(36:18) - Sponsor: Changelog News
(38:19) - Transitions
(41:12) - Leadership duties
(47:36) - Going beyond senior
(50:27) - The 3 things a staff eng does
(52:41) - When is it time?
(58:42) - Driving impact
(1:00:28) - Take care, y'all
(1:00:54) - Next up on the pod]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Company Update]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/ceo/company-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/ceo/company-update"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T03:20:41.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Mårten Mickos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best practices for organizations and teams using GitHub Enterprise Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73480</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-02-best-practices-for-organizations-and-teams-using-github-enterprise-cloud/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T19:55:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how you can structure your enterprise to get the most value out of GitHub and provide the best experience for your developers!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Losert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new fund for women creating AI startups in Asia Pacific]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/new-ai-women-fund/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/new-ai-women-fund/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T19:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Google for Startups Women Founders Fund will provide equity-free funding and Google support to women-led AI startups in India, Japan and Korea.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 287: Building world-class developer experiences]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2130</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/287"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we’re talking with Alice Merrick & Andy Walker about building a world-class developer experience. You know it when you see it, things just feel right. But it’s more than just a pleasant UI or lipstick on a pig (which is a saying), it really matters.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 5 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Alice Merrick – Twitter, LinkedIn
Andy Walker – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Mat Ryer – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

Charm on GitHub
Use system fonts
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:45) - Introducing the guests
(04:01) - What is the dev experience
(07:14) - Multimodal experience
(10:22) - Change aversion
(12:44) - Measuring time to fluency
(17:27) - Fonts
(23:28) - Cookie consent forms
(26:29) - Interactive docs
(32:17) - In-browser playground
(35:44) - Short comings of the playground
(40:51) - Sponsor: Changelog News
(42:54) - Patterns we don't like
(52:23) - Unpopular opinions!
(52:54) - Alice's unpop
(1:07:25) - Andy's unpop
(1:09:33) - Kris' unpop
(1:18:55) - Outro (BONUS++)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with openpilot]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/gettingstarted/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/gettingstarted/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“How do I get started with openpilot?” is a question we get asked a lot. So in this blog post we’ll answer that. We want to make it as easy as possible for people to experiment with, and potentially contribute to the openpilot ecosystem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MTE As Implemented, Part 3: The Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/mte-as-implemented-part-3-kernel.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/mte-as-implemented-part-3-kernel.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T16:30:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@import url(https://themes.googleusercontent.com/fonts/css?kit=4mNYFHt_IKFsPe52toizH6nwuZUPj2AFYBEz-aMyENVctA_KpTDBIb9wIwVqFCm-);.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-3>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-3}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-1.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-1 0}.lst-kix_8lngbvh6wilc-4>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_8lngbvh6wilc-4}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-0{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-2{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-2>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-2}.lst-kix_8lngbvh6wilc-5>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_8lngbvh6wilc-5}ol.lst-kix_cp4qttrp12lb-6.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_cp4qttrp12lb-6 0}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-1{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-4{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-3{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_8lngbvh6w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MTE As Implemented, Part 2: Mitigation Case Studies]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/mte-as-implemented-part-2-mitigation.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/mte-as-implemented-part-2-mitigation.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T16:30:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@import url(https://themes.googleusercontent.com/fonts/css?kit=4mNYFHt_IKFsPe52toizH6nwuZUPj2AFYBEz-aMyENXbDjL3Cv1g7CpfdyRoONLEXShKQSnoFmUtAspFfwQKag);ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-8.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-8 0}.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-3>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-3}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-1.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-1 0}.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-8>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-8}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-0{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-2{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-2>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_46kwnuz47r-2}ol.lst-kix_cp4qttrp12lb-6.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_cp4qttrp12lb-6 0}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-1{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-4{list-style-type:none}ol.lst-kix_46kwnuz47r-3{list-style-type:none}.ls…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MTE As Implemented, Part 1: Implementation Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/mte-as-implemented-part-1.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/mte-as-implemented-part-1.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T16:30:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@import url(https://themes.googleusercontent.com/fonts/css?kit=cGvuclDC_Z1vE_cnVEU6AbvdjsQquauI-GoInd1DzsRjfxSl7duaBsON8MRB32eGNP6BCxV-AQSEvP01Vpd9xT0e5qzIIUg9OvSRGeMDk3I);.lst-kix_exl34y7adtul-6>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_exl34y7adtul-6}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-4>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-6>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_w66ctsc8735u-5>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_w66ctsc8735u-5}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-3>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-7>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_7336pfhg38rf-8>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_7336pfhg38rf-8}ol.lst-kix_w66ctsc8735u-1.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_w66ctsc8735u-1 0}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-5>li:before{content:"-  "}ol.lst-kix_pmivlm2h8rwq-6.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_pmivlm2h8rwq-6 0}.lst-kix_cm1sbgja1sfy-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary: MTE As Implemented]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/summary-mte-as-implemented.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/08/summary-mte-as-implemented.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@import url(https://themes.googleusercontent.com/fonts/css?kit=DFQxm4rd7fRHgM9OTejWVT5Vho6BE7M80rHXEVKqXWdbV0WvE1cEyAoIq5yYZlSc);.lst-kix_exl34y7adtul-6>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_exl34y7adtul-6}.lst-kix_kzys3uxts4nk-6>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_kzys3uxts4nk-6,decimal) ". "}.lst-kix_kzys3uxts4nk-8>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_kzys3uxts4nk-8,lower-roman) ". "}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-4>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-6>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_kzys3uxts4nk-7>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_kzys3uxts4nk-7,lower-latin) ". "}.lst-kix_w66ctsc8735u-5>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_w66ctsc8735u-5}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-3>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_s8b3u49h11dr-7>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_7336pfhg38rf-8>li{counter-increment:…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lab Sessions: A new series of experimental AI collaborations]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/lab-sessions/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/lab-sessions/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lab Sessions is a series of experimental AI collaborations with everyone from artists to academics, scientists to students.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things we always remind ourselves while coding]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/posts/2617</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/posts/things-we-always-remind-ourselves-while-coding"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T14:48:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our Frontend Feud game show series forces me to survey JS Party listeners frequently to get their thoughts on software, development, life, and software development life.
Each question has to be accompanied by an <input type=text> because providing choices ruins the entire point of the game. So, before we play I compile all the answers in an SQLite database, group similar responses, and put the most popular ones on the game board.
That “grouping similar responses” step is the hardest part and can be somewhat controversial during the games. I’ve gotten better over the years at crafting the questions to constrain the responses.
For example, instead of asking: “How do you feel about GitHub Copilot?”
We ask: “In one word, how does GitHub Copilot make you feel?”
"Anxious" works better in a `GROU…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we build containerized services at GitHub using GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73456</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-02-how-we-build-containerized-services-at-github-using-github/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T12:31:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about how we build containerized services that power microservices on the GitHub.com platform and many internal tools.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>MV Karan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 234: Vector databases (beyond the hype)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2173</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/234"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s so much talk (and hype) these days about vector databases. We thought it would be timely and practical to have someone on the show that has been hands on with the various options and actually tried to build applications leveraging vector search. Prashanth Rao is a real practitioner that has spent and huge amount of time exploring the expanding set of vector database offerings. After introducing vector database and giving us a mental model of how they fit in with other datastores, Prashanth digs into the trade offs as related to indices, hosting options, embedding vs. query optimization, and more.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, sec…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl write-out to files]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22786</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/08/01/curl-write-out-to-files/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T06:21:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The curl option –write-out is one of my personal favorites and offers users an excitingly powerful way to output information from a transfer. Over time, it has been extended to provide more and more features. It was for example not that long ago we added the ability to output the content of specific headers with … Continue reading curl write-out to files →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 55: Stack Underflow, LLM Attacks, web DRM by Google, unlocking Python & no one wants to talk to your chatbot]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2172</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/55"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Something interesting is going on at Stack Overflow, researches dig up some new (and potentially unavoidable) LLM attacks, Google proposes a new API that Ron Amadeo calls a DRM gatekeeper for the web, the Python Steering Council affirms PEP 703 & Lucas McGregor writes why no one wants to talk to your chatbot.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(01:01) - The fall of Stack Overflow
(01:58) - LLM Attacks
(03:25) - Web DRM by Google
(04:34) - Unlocking Python
(05:34) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(06:43) - No one wants to talk to your chatbot
(07:48) - Outro (Shout outs++)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[introducing curl command line variables]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22692</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/07/31/introducing-curl-command-line-variables/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T09:53:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you are anything like me, you appreciate solving your every day simple tasks directly from the command line. Creating crafty single shot command lines or a small shell script to solve that special task you figured out you needed and makes your day go a little smoother. A fellow command line cowboy. Video presentation … Continue reading introducing curl command line variables →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 9: Homelab nerds, unite!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2171</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/9"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ok Homelabbers, it’s time to unite! Join Adam and his new friend Techno Tim for 1.5 hours of homelab goodness. From networking and WiFi, virtualizing Ubuntu running Docker containers, to Home Assistant and automation, building a Kubernetes cluster, to gutting a perfectly good machine just to build exactly what you need to run the ultimate Plex server — that’s what homelab is about. Let’s do this.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and datab…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smarter, more efficient coding: GitHub Copilot goes beyond Codex with improved AI model]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73440</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-07-28-smarter-more-efficient-coding-github-copilot-goes-beyond-codex-with-improved-ai-model/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T19:24:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're thrilled to announce two major updates to GitHub Copilot code Completion's capabilities that will help developers work even more efficiently and effectively.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuyin Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 550: From Docker to Dagger]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2105</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/550"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Solomon Hykes, the creator of Docker. Now he’s back with his next big thing called Dagger — CI/CD as code that runs anywhere. We’re users of Dagger so check out our codebase if you want to see how it works. On today’s show Solomon takes us back to the days of Docker, what it was like on that 10 year journey, his transition from Docker to Dagger, Dagger’s community-led growth model, their focus on open source and community, how it works, and even a cameo from Kelsey Hightower to explain how Dagger works.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by buil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 285: Frontend Feud: CSS Pod vs Whiskey Web and Whatnot]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2110</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/285"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una & Adam from The CSS Podcast defend their Frontend Feud title against challengers Chuck & Robbie from Whiskey Web and Whatnot. Let’s get it on!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Una Kravets – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Adam Argyle – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Chuck Carpenter – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Robbie Wagner – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

The CSS Podcast
Whiskey Web and Whatnot
More dev game shows!
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:32) - Welcoming our contestants
(01:47) - Terry the intern's interview questions
(03:11) - How the game works
(04:40) - Round 1: Favorite language
(09:41) - Round 2: !Favorite language
(13:57) - Round 3: Monitor size
(19:18) - Round 4: Work benefits
(32:24) - Round 5: Must-have SaaS
(36:29) - Round 6: Copilot feels
(43:10) - End Game
(44:01) - Interviewing the champs
(45:46) - Chuck & Robbie's show
(46:43) - The final word
(48:29) - Closing time
(48:58) - Outro (moar game shows!)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Closing vulnerabilities in Decidim, a Ruby-based citizen participation platform]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73405</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-07-28-closing-vulnerabilities-in-decidim-a-ruby-based-citizen-participation-platform/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T13:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post describes two security vulnerabilities in Decidim, a digital platform for citizen participation. Both vulnerabilities were addressed by the Decidim team with corresponding update releases for the supported versions in May 2023.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Stöckli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speaking robot: Our new AI model translates vision and language into robotic actions]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-deepmind-rt2-robotics-vla-model/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-deepmind-rt2-robotics-vla-model/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google DeepMind introduces a new vision-language-action model for improving robotics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Offering free AI training for everyone in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/united-kingdom/google-ai-skills-training-course-uk/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/united-kingdom/google-ai-skills-training-course-uk/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonny Cottom knows the juggle involved with running a start-up single handedly. Since launching BreakBottle, an eco-friendly water bottle brand, last year, he has been s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smarter banking: how intelligent suggestions in the Nubank app empower customers]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21218</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/smarter-banking-how-intelligent-suggestions-in-the-nubank-app-empower-customers/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T20:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contextual recommendations for better financial outcomes: how this feature optimizes your choices.
The post Smarter banking: how intelligent suggestions in the Nubank app empower customers appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BU Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[So you want to build your own open source chatbot…]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48012</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2023/07/so-you-want-to-build-your-own-open-source-chatbot/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T17:52:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence may well prove one of the most impactful and disruptive technologies to come along in years. We want to understand, support, and contribute to these efforts because we believe that they offer one of the best ways to help ensure that the AI systems that emerge are truly trustworthy. With this in mind, a small team within Mozilla’s innovation group recently undertook a hackathon at our headquarters in San Francisco. Our objective: build a Mozilla internal chatbot prototype.
The post So you want to build your own open source chatbot… appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Hood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 emerging practices for responsible generative AI]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-responsible-generative-ai-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-responsible-generative-ai-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For our midyear update, we’d like to share three of our best practices based on this guidance and what we’ve done in our pre-launch design, reviews and development of ge…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ups and Downs of 0-days: A Year in Review of 0-days Exploited In-the-Wild in 2022]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/07/the-ups-and-downs-of-0-days-year-in.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/07/the-ups-and-downs-of-0-days-year-in.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T16:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maddie Stone, Security Researcher, Threat Analysis Group (TAG)


This is Google’s fourth annual year-in-review of 0-days exploited in-the-wild [2021, 2020, 2019] and builds off of the mid-year 2022 review. The goal of this report is not to detail each individual exploit, but instead to analyze the exploits from the year as a whole, looking for trends, gaps, lessons learned, and successes. 
Executive Summary
41 in-the-wild 0-days were detected and disclosed in 2022, the second-most ever recorded since we began tracking in mid-2014, but down from the 69 detected in 2021.  Although a 40% drop might seem like a clear-cut win for improving security, the reality is more complicated. Some of our key takeaways from 2022 include:





N-days function like 0-days on Android due to long patching time…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling merge-ort across GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73390</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-07-27-scaling-merge-ort-across-github/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub switched to performing merges and rebases using merge-ort. Come behind the scenes to see why and how we made this change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cooper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strengthening the SDLC with Security Advisory Services (SAS)]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/security-advisory-services-sdlc</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/security-advisory-services-sdlc"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We see untapped potential in how customers use our HackerOne solutions every day, which inspired the creation of our latest offering: HackerOne Security Advisory Services (SAS).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michiel Prins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[openpilot 0.9.4]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/094release/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/094release/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Navigate on openpilot comes to Experimental mode!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new partnership to promote responsible AI]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/google-microsoft-openai-anthropic-frontier-model-forum/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/google-microsoft-openai-anthropic-frontier-model-forum/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, Google, Microsoft, OpenAI and Anthropic published a joint announcement establishing the Frontier Model Forum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get AI regulation right for open source]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73374</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-07-26-how-to-get-ai-regulation-right-for-open-source/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T07:01:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing our coalition paper to inform the final negotiation of the EU AI Act.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Cihon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl 8.2.1]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22839</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/07/26/curl-8-2-1/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T06:16:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome. Due to some annoying regressions in the previous release we think we owned it to everyone to do a quick patch follow-up. Download curl 8.2.1 from https://curl.se. Release presentation Numbers the 221st release0 changes7 days (total: 9,259)27 bug-fixes (total: 9,194)37 commits (total: 30,646)0 new public libcurl function (total: 91)0 new curl_easy_setopt() option (total: 303)0 … Continue reading curl 8.2.1 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>