<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-09-29T12:03:09.391Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 294: Reports of Node's death are greatly exaggerated]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2216</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/294"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amal, KBall & Chris convene a “semi-emergency” pod to discuss the recent (deserved) hype over Bun and what it all means for Node’s community, maintainers & users.
They’re joined by Node Technical Steering Committee members Matteo Collina & James Snell who are here to dispel Bun antagonism rumors, discuss the pros & cons of each runtime, explain how Node continues to thrive & even announce a VERY big upcoming feature!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Convex – Convex is a better type of backend — the full-stack TypeScript development platform that lets you replace your database, server functions, and glue code. Get started at convex.dev

Appwrite – Build Fast. Scale Big. All in One Place. Appw…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An update on web publisher controls]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/an-update-on-web-publisher-controls/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/an-update-on-web-publisher-controls/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re announcing Google-Extended, a new control that web publishers can use to manage whether their sites help improve Bard and Vertex AI generative APIs, including futu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Learning Pathways: Learn from the best]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74356</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-28-github-learning-pathways-learn-from-the-best/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T17:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gain expertise and insights from top organizations through guided tutorials, boosting productivity, enhancing security, and enabling seamless collaboration.
The post GitHub Learning Pathways: Learn from the best appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robb Mapp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 559: Vibes from Strange Loop]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2220</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/559"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on The Changelog we’re taking you to the hallway track of the final Strange Loop conference. First up is AnnMarie Thomas — an engineering, business, and education professor. AnnMarie gave one of the opening keynotes titled “Playing with Engineering.” We also caught up with many first-time and multi-time attendees who shared their favorite moments from Strange Loop over the years. You’ll hear from Richard Feldman, Colin Dean, and Taylor Troesch. Last up we talk with Pokey Rule. He gave a talk about his project called Cursorless which is a spoken language for structural code editing.
Changelog++ subscribers get a super extended version of this episode which includes everything we recorded at Strange Loop. Become a Changelog++ subscriber
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SMS Security & Privacy Gaps Make It Clear Users Need a Messaging Upgrade]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/09/sms-security-privacy-gaps-make-it-clear.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/09/sms-security-privacy-gaps-make-it-clear.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T16:50:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Eugene Liderman and Roger Piqueras Jover 


SMS texting is frozen in time.


People still use and rely on trillions of SMS texts each year to exchange messages with friends, share family photos, and copy two-factor authentication codes to access sensitive data in their bank accounts. It’s hard to believe that at a time where technologies like AI are transforming our world, a forty-year old mobile messaging standard is still so prevalent.


Like any forty-year-old technology, SMS is antiquated compared to its modern counterparts. That’s especially concerning when it comes to security.


The World Has Changed, But SMS Hasn’t Changed With It


According to a recent whitepaper from Dekra, a safety certifications and testing lab, the security shortcomings of SMS can notably lead to: 
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I used GitHub Copilot Chat to build a ReactJS gallery prototype]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74315</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-27-how-i-used-github-copilot-chat-to-build-a-reactjs-gallery-prototype/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T16:24:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Chat can help developers create prototypes, understand code, make UI changes, troubleshoot errors, make code more accessible, and generate unit tests. 
The post How I used GitHub Copilot Chat to build a ReactJS gallery prototype appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Senna Parsa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 292: Zero Trust & Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2188</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/292"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Quiqley from NetFoundry joins Natalie to discuss Zero Trust concepts, why they are important for secure systems & how to implement them in Go.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!


Featuring:

Michael Quigley – GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

BeyondCorp initiative by Google
Tor
Istio
Ngrok
OpenZiti and zrok
QUIC and [quic-go](https://github.com/quic-go/quic-go  : http alternative
bbolt (part of k8s)
Transwarp/Dilithium - better than tcp (in some cases)
OpenZiti Test Kitchen Repos
Open Source LLM: Karen The Editor
FabLab
zrok SDK “pastebin” example: A buffer for moving buffers between machines
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:45) - Michael Quigley
(01:09) - Zero Trust
(02:51) - Early adoption
(09:59) - Go
(14:45) - Traditional Zero Trust
(16:53) - Misconceptions of Zero Trust
(20:38) - Generics
(21:24) - AI
(28:08) - Identity and access management
(31:33) - FabLab
(33:01) - Good metrics
(36:37) - Contributions
(40:15) - Michael's favorite protocol
(44:14) - UTP for Zero Trust
(46:10) - Unpopular opinions!
(46:42) - Michael's unpop
(49:02) - Natalie's unpop
(50:01) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Google.org grants to introduce 300,000 students to robotics and AI]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/google-grants-robotics-ai-education/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/google-grants-robotics-ai-education/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For Google’s 25th birthday, Google.org is providing $10 million in grant funding to support robotics programs and AI education.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitHub uses GitHub Actions and Actions larger runners to build and test GitHub.com]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74251</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-26-how-github-uses-github-actions-and-actions-larger-runners-to-build-and-test-github-com/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T17:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, we’ve been working to make our CI experience better by leveraging the newly released GitHub feature, Actions larger runners, to run our CI. 
The post How GitHub uses GitHub Actions and Actions larger runners to build and test GitHub.com appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Wagner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your ultimate guide to the GitHub Universe ‘23 agenda]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74261</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-26-your-ultimate-guide-to-the-github-universe-23-agenda/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T16:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get a sneak peek into the must-attend sessions, speakers, workshops, and GitHub certifications available at our global developer event.
The post Your ultimate guide to the GitHub Universe ‘23 agenda appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeimy Ruiz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our 10 biggest AI moments so far]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-ai-ml-timeline/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-ai-ml-timeline/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A round-up of our top 10 AI moments of the last 25 years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting RCE in Chrome with incorrect side effect in the JIT compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74273</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-26-getting-rce-in-chrome-with-incorrect-side-effect-in-the-jit-compiler/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T15:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, I'll exploit CVE-2023-3420, a type confusion in Chrome that allows remote code execution (RCE) in the renderer sandbox of Chrome by a single visit to a malicious site.
The post Getting RCE in Chrome with incorrect side effect in the JIT compiler appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Man Yue Mo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The birth of the Dark Mode: a journey into Nubank’s app evolution]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21382</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/the-birth-of-the-dark-mode-a-journey-into-nubanks-app-evolution/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T13:49:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Dark Mode's development process has been marked by a commitment to continuous improvement based on user feedback.
The post The birth of the Dark Mode: a journey into Nubank’s app evolution appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BU Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 63: The missing sync layer for modern apps]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2218</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/63"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T19:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ElectricSQL is a project that offers a local-first sync layer for web and mobile apps, Ned Batchelder writes about the myth of the myth of “learning styles”, Carl Johnson thinks XML is better than YAML, Berkan Sasmaz defines and describes “idempotency” & HyperDX is an open source alternative Datadog or New Relic.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:48) - ElectricSQL
(01:29) - Learning styles myth x2
(02:45) - XML is better than YAML
(03:34) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(04:27) - Idempotency
(05:15) - HyperDX
(06:04) - Follow-up
(07:44) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling all teachers! Learn how to build new commands on the GitHub Classroom CLI]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74237</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-25-calling-all-teachers-learn-how-to-build-new-commands-on-the-github-classroom-cli/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T16:08:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this step-by-step tutorial, we’ll dive into how you can become the next open source contributor to the GitHub Classroom CLI, building commands that you can use to improve your workflow as an educator!
The post Calling all teachers! Learn how to build new commands on the GitHub Classroom CLI appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zenara Daley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 ways AI can help communities adapt to climate change in Africa]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/3-ways-ai-can-help-africans-adapt-to-climate-change/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/3-ways-ai-can-help-africans-adapt-to-climate-change/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week at the inaugural Africa Climate Summit (ACS) in Nairobi, Kenya, we joined African leaders and shared our commitment to advance AI solutions to address the clim…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why This Moment In Cybersecurity Needs Hackers To Protect All Software]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/ceo/why-moment-cybersecurity-needs-hackers-protect-all-software</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/ceo/why-moment-cybersecurity-needs-hackers-protect-all-software"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>alice@hackerone.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Security Lab’s journey to disclosing 500 CVEs in open source projects]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74213</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-21-the-github-security-labs-journey-to-disclosing-500-cves-in-open-source-projects/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T20:56:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Security Lab audits open source projects for security vulnerabilities and helps maintainers fix them. Recently, we passed the milestone of 500 CVEs disclosed. Let’s take a trip down memory lane with a review of some noteworthy CVEs!
The post The GitHub Security Lab’s journey to disclosing 500 CVEs in open source projects appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xavier René-Corail</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 293: Web dev security school]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2205</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/293"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week, we’re joined by Ron Perris, a Security Engineer at Reddit and software security enthusiast. Together, we dive into best practices and common pitfalls, covering topics from dangerous URLs to JSON injection attacks. Tune in for an educational conversation, and don’t forget to bring your notebooks!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 4 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Convex – Convex is a better type of backend — the full-stack TypeScript development platform that lets you replace your database, server functions, and glue code. Get started at convex.dev

Appwrite – Build Fast. Scale Big. All in One Place. Appwrite is a backend platform for developing Web, Mobile, and Flutter applications. Built with the open source community …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Passkeys are generally available]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74169</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-21-passkeys-are-generally-available/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T16:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All GitHub.com users can now register a passkey to sign in without a password.
The post Passkeys are generally available appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hirsch Singhal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling Rust Adoption Through Training]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/09/scaling-rust-adoption-through-training.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/09/scaling-rust-adoption-through-training.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T16:00:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Martin Geisler, Android team



Android 14 is the third major Android release with Rust support. We are already seeing a number of benefits:



Productivity: Developers quickly feel productive writing Rust. They report important indicators of development velocity, such as confidence in the code quality and ease of code review.

Security: There has been a reduction in memory safety vulnerabilities as we shift more development to memory safe languages.



These positive early results provided an enticing motivation to increase the speed and scope of Rust adoption. We hoped to accomplish this by investing heavily in training to expand from the early adopters.

Scaling up from Early Adopters
Training Engineers
Quickly ramp up engineers: It is hard to take people away from their regul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the GitHub Innovation Graph]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74175</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-21-announcing-the-github-innovation-graph/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T15:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore a universe of data about how the world is building software together on GitHub.
The post Announcing the GitHub Innovation Graph appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Linksvayer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communicate Design Tradeoffs Visually]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/09/communicate-design-tradeoffs-visually.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/09/communicate-design-tradeoffs-visually.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T12:28:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office.



By Tim Lyakhovetskiy





A goal of any written design or project proposal is to present and evaluate alternatives. However, documents that include multiple solutions can be difficult to read when the qualities of each solution are not clearly expressed.
A common approach to simplifying proposals is to use “pros and cons” for each alternative, but this leads to biased writing since the pros and cons may be weighed differently depending on the reader’s priorities.
In this example, can you quickly tell how this option would measure up against others?



Option 1 - Optimize Shoelace Untangling Wizard in Sh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and scalability for search]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T12:02:34.343Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we power real-time search for Tweets, Users, Direct Messages and more using Elasticsearch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Chat beta now available for all individuals]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74156</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-20-github-copilot-chat-beta-now-available-for-all-individuals/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T17:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All GitHub Copilot for Individuals users now have access to GitHub Copilot Chat beta, bringing natural language-powered coding to every developer in all languages.
The post GitHub Copilot Chat beta now available for all individuals appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuyin Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Learning Paths on Global Campus]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74129</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-20-introducing-learning-paths-on-global-campus/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T16:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guiding student developers through skill building foundations, a building block in their learning journey with GitHub Education.
The post Introducing Learning Paths on Global Campus appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Morgan Ersery</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 239: Automate all the UIs!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2215</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/239"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dominik Klotz from askui joins Daniel and Chris to discuss the automation of UI, and how AI empowers them to automate any use case on any operating system.  Along the way, the trio explore various approaches and the integration of generative AI, large language models, and computer vision.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Statsig – Build faster with confidence. Startups to Fortune 500s rely on Statsig to make data-driven decisions. Ship smarter and faster with the unified platform for feature flags, experimentation, and analytics. Our listeners get free white-glove onboarding, migration support, and 5 million free events per month.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, en…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing general availability of GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74138</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-20-announcing-general-availability-of-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T15:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps is now generally available. Enable secret scanning, dependency scanning, and code scanning on your organization directly in Azure DevOps configuration settings. 
The post Announcing general availability of GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Walker Chabbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XML is better than YAML. Hear me out...]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/posts/2620</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/posts/xml-better-than-yaml"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T14:57:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a fancified excerpt of Carl M. Johnson’s unpopular opinion on the Go Time podcast. Click here to listen along while you read or watch the video on YouTube. Jump to the end for the poll results. 📊
My spicy take is that XML is better than YAML, because there are situations where XML is appropriate, but there’s no situation where YAML is appropriate.
Johnny Boursiquot: Dang. Shots fired! 🤣
Let’s talk about XML first
So, XML got a really bad reputation. The reason it got a really bad reputation is because people were using it for things that it should never have been used for. XML stands for Extensible Markup Language. And if you’re using it as an extensible markup language, it’s actually really great.
Let’s say you’re working on something and you’re like:
“I’m making a new kind of b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carl Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How AI is generating change in newsrooms worldwide]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/how-ai-is-generating-change-in-newsrooms-worldwide/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/how-ai-is-generating-change-in-newsrooms-worldwide/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our recent research report, Generating Change, shares what newsrooms are doing with AI today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 558: Open source is at a crossroads]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2187</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/558"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Steve O’Grady, Principal Analyst & Co-founder at RedMonk. The topic today is the definition of open source, the constant pressure on the true definition of the term, and the seemingly small but vocal minority that aim to protect that definition. In Steve’s post Why Open Source Matters, he says “open source is at a crossroads” and there are some seeking to break the definition of open source to one that is more permissive to their desires, and they are closer than ever to achieving that goal. Today’s conversation goes deep on this subject.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 12 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Convex – Convex is a better type of backend — the full-stack TypeScript development platform that le…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analyzing a Modern In-the-wild Android Exploit]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/09/analyzing-modern-in-wild-android-exploit.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2023/09/analyzing-modern-in-wild-android-exploit.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T16:01:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Seth Jenkins, Project Zero

Introduction

In December 2022, Google’s Threat Analysis Group (TAG) discovered an in-the-wild exploit chain targeting Samsung Android devices. TAG’s blog post covers the targeting and the actor behind the campaign. This is a technical analysis of the final stage of one of the exploit chains, specifically CVE-2023-0266 (a 0-day in the ALSA compatibility layer) and CVE-2023-26083 (a 0-day in the Mali GPU driver) as well as the techniques used by the attacker to gain kernel arbitrary read/write access.

Notably, all of the previous stages of the exploit chain used n-day vulnerabilities:


CVE-2022-4262, a vulnerability patched in Chrome that was unpatched in the Samsung browser (i.e. a "Chrome n-day"), was used to achieve RCE.


CVE-2022-3038, another Chrome n-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using data and AI to track progress toward the UN Global Goals]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-ai-data-un-global-goals/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-ai-data-un-global-goals/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Commons works with the UN and ONE to track progress toward the SDGs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 62: Death by a thousand microservices]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2214</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/62"/>
        <updated>2023-09-18T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrei Taranchenko says the software industry is learning once again that complexity kills, Casey Muratori outlines a long list of Unity alternatives, Filip Szkandera builds a functioning (macro) processor for RISC-V & Matt Basta tells the tale of the time he built a web-based Excel clone inside Uber only to have it discarded a week later.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – Learn the basics of frontend application performance monitoring with Sentry in this upcoming livestream. Sign up here.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:44) - Death by a thousand microservices
(02:25) - Game development post-Unity
(03:34) - Sponsor: Sentry
(04:26) - Pineapple ONE
(05:52) - No sacred masterpieces
(06:59) - Pagefind
(08:07) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching from Bitbucket Server and Bamboo to GitHub just got easier]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74107</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-18-switching-from-bitbucket-server-and-bamboo-to-github-just-got-easier/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-18T16:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting today, GitHub Enterprise Importer supports repository migrations from Bitbucket Server and Bitbucket Data Center, and GitHub Actions Importer offers CI/CD migrations from Bitbucket and Bamboo.
The post Switching from Bitbucket Server and Bamboo to GitHub just got easier appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melody Mileski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 14: What do we want from a web browser?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2185</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/14"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A hoy hoy! Our old friend Nick Nisi does his best to bring up TypeScript, Vim & Tmux as many times as possible while we discuss a new batch of web browsers, justify why we like the ones we do & try to figure out what it’d take to disrupt the status quo of Big Browser.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 8 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Statsig – Build faster with confidence. Startups to Fortune 500s rely on Statsig to make data-driven decisions. Ship smarter and faster with the unified platform for feature flags, experimentation, and analytics. Our listeners get free white-glove onboarding, migration support, and 5 million free events per month.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital exper…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capslock: What is your code really capable of?]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/09/capslock-what-is-your-code-really.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/09/capslock-what-is-your-code-really.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T18:10:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jess McClintock and John Dethridge, Google Open Source Security Team, and Damien Miller, Enterprise Infrastructure Protection Team






When you import a third party library, do you review every line of code? Most software packages depend on external libraries, trusting that those packages aren’t doing anything unexpected. If that trust is violated, the consequences can be huge—regardless of whether the package is malicious, or well-intended but using overly broad permissions, such as with Log4j in 2021. Supply chain security is a growing issue, and we hope that greater transparency into package capabilities will help make secure coding easier for everyone.





Avoiding bad dependencies can be hard without appropriate information on what the dependency’s code actually does, and reviewing…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strange Loop's greatest hits]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/posts/2619</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/posts/strange-loops-greatest-hits"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T12:12:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The LAST Strange Loop conference is right around the corner!
The conference has accumulated 673 videos on its YouTube channel, which means there’s gold in them hills, but finding the gold might consume some of your precious time. Good news!
I was hanging out in the conference’s Slack when someone asked:
What are some of y’all’s favorite past Strange Loop talks? As someone who knows the conf by reputation but hasn’t been before, I’m curious what some of your favorites are!
A barrage of YouTube links followed, so I scooped them up to share here so everyone can enjoy these golden Strange Loop talks ✨
🎥 Stop Writing Dead Programs by Jack Rusher (2022)
Most new programming languages are accidentally designed to be backwards compatible with punchcards. This talk argues that it would be better t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Twitter uses rasdaemon for hardware reliability]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T12:02:33.222Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing auto-triage rules for Dependabot]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74069</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-14-introducing-auto-triage-rules-for-dependabot/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T17:34:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Make quick work of alerts with preset and custom rules.
The post Introducing auto-triage rules for Dependabot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin Havens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 292: Type War (what is it good for?)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2208</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/292"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Love it or hate it, TypeScript is here to stay for the foreseeable future.  But, what happens when widely adopted packages go completely Type free or remove TypeScript in favor of JS with type annotations? Join us to unpack these recent events with Rich Harris, creator of Svelte, as he walks us through the nuanced decision his team made for the Svelte project, and ofc, lots of laughs along the way.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 7 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Convex – Convex is a better type of backend — the full-stack TypeScript development platform that lets you replace your database, server functions, and glue code. Get started at convex.dev

Caisy – Caisy is the headless CMS that gives developers endless possibilities. L…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The data platform cluster operator service for Hadoop cluster management]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/the-data-platform-cluster-operator-service-for-hadoop-cluster-management</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/the-data-platform-cluster-operator-service-for-hadoop-cluster-management"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T12:02:46.700Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As any team and its infrastructure grows, the risk of an unplanned service outage and potential data loss will grow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 557: Attack of the Canaries!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2192</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/557"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Haroon Meer from Thinkst — the makers of Canary and Canary Tokens. Haroon walks us through a network getting compromised, what it takes to deploy a Canary on your network, how they maintain low false-positive numbers, their thoughts and principles on building their business (major wisdom shared!), and how a Canary helps surface network attacks in real time.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 4 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Statsig – Build faster with confidence. Startups to Fortune 500s rely on Statsig to make data-driven decisions. Ship smarter and faster with the unified platform for feature flags, experimentation, and analytics. Our listeners get free white-glove onboarding, migration support, and 5 m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: August 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74067</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-13-github-availability-report-august-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T19:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In August, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services. 
The post GitHub Availability Report: August 2023 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apply now for GitHub Universe 2023 micro-mentoring]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74051</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-13-apply-now-for-github-universe-2023-micro-mentoring/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T16:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of our ongoing commitment to accelerate human progress through Social Impact initiatives, we’re offering students 30-minute, 1:1 micro-mentoring sessions with GitHub employees ahead of Universe.
The post Apply now for GitHub Universe 2023 micro-mentoring appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Camaley Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Commons is using AI to make the world’s public data more accessible and helpful]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-data-commons-ai/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-data-commons-ai/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A look at Data Commons, Google’s initiative to make publicly available data more useful for people working on solutions to societal challenges.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 291: Go templating using Templ]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2175</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/291"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Go’s known for it’s fantastic standard library, but there are some places where the libraries can be challenging to use. The html/template package is one of those places. So what alternatives do we have? On today’s episode we’re talking about Templ, an HTML templating language for Go that has great developer tooling. Co-hosts Kris Brandow and Jon Calhoun are joined by Adrian Hesketh, the creator of Templ, and Joe Davidson, one of the maintainers on the project.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 2 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Else Nuances]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/09/else-nuances.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/09/else-nuances.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T14:51:00.008Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is another post in our Code Health series. A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office.

By Sam Lee and Stan Chan

If your function exits early in an if statement, using or not using an else clause is equivalent in terms of behavior. However, the proper use of else clauses and guard clauses (lack of else) can help emphasize the intent of the code to the reader.
Consider the following guidelines to help you structure your functions:

Use a guard clause to handle special cases upfront, so that the rest of the code can focus
on the core logic. A guard clause checks a criterion and fails fast or returns early if it is not
met, which reduces nesting …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NuStories: embracing transitions to own your career journey]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21356</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/nustories-embracing-transitions-to-own-your-career-journey/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T13:41:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's delve into the journeys of three Nubankers who embody our core values every step of the way.
The post NuStories: embracing transitions to own your career journey appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl 8.3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22926</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/09/13/curl-8-3-0/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T06:26:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to this new curl release! Release video Numbers the 251st release9 changes49 days (total: 9,308)174 bug-fixes (total: 9,415)296 commits (total: 30,942)1 new public libcurl function (total: 92)0 new curl_easy_setopt() option (total: 303)2 new curl command line option (total: 257)80 contributors, 50 new (total: 2,977)40 authors, 20 new (total: 1,193)1 security fixes (total: 146) Numbers … Continue reading curl 8.3.0 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeQL team uses AI to power vulnerability detection in code]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=74030</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-12-codeql-team-uses-ai-to-power-vulnerability-detection-in-code/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T16:48:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how GitHub’s CodeQL leveraged AI modeling and multi-repository variant analysis to discover a new CVE in Gradle.
The post CodeQL team uses AI to power vulnerability detection in code appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Walker Chabbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ethical Hacking: Unveiling the Power of Hacking for Good in Cybersecurity]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/thought-leadership/aws-podcast-ethical-hacking-cybersecurity</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/thought-leadership/aws-podcast-ethical-hacking-cybersecurity"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T16:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne CEO Marten Mickos joins the Amazon Web Services podcast, Conversations With Leaders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marten Mickos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 projects using AI to reach the UN’s Global Goals]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/httpsbloggoogleoutreach-initiativesgoogle-orgunited-nations-global-goals-google-ai-/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/httpsbloggoogleoutreach-initiativesgoogle-orgunited-nations-global-goals-google-ai-/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google.org is funding 15 projects that will use AI to make progress on the UN’s Sustainable Development Goals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 61: Bun 1.0 is here & Mojo is ready for download]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2207</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/61"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bun 1.0 is out of the oven, Mojo is now available for local download, Vince Lwt asked 60+ LLMs a set of 20 questions & published the answers, Textual Web turns TUIs in to web applications & James Haydon dives deep to discover the bug that the UK air traffic control meltdown.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(01:05) - Bun 1.0 is here
(02:08) - Mojo is ready for download
(02:57) - 20 questions for 60 LLMs
(04:01) - Textual Web
(05:03) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(06:00) - The UK air traffic meltdown
(07:43) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 13: Doomed to discuss AI]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2186</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/13"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author, journalist, travel writer & software engineer Jon Evans joins us to weigh in on the cultural history (and present-day sentiment) of AI doom. Along the way, we talk plausible Sci-Fi, ultrasound drug delivery, the maybe-evolving laws of physics & even weirder stuff.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 8 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 291: A view to a transitions API]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2201</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/291"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jerod & the gang discuss the news (Astro 3.0, Vercel + Astro, Python in Excel) then play eight crazy rounds of HeadLIES! Headline or headLIE? You decide…
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Convex – Convex is a better type of backend — the full-stack TypeScript development platform that lets you replace your database, server functions, and glue code. Get started at convex.dev

Caisy – Caisy is the headless CMS that gives developers endless possibilities. Learn more at caisy.io

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hacker Perspective on Generative AI and Cybersecurity]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/thought-leadership/generative-ai-cybersecurity-hacker-perspective</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/thought-leadership/generative-ai-cybersecurity-hacker-perspective"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T17:10:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne spoken with several experienced hackers in the space to get their perspectives on the most important considerations for Generative AI and cybersecurity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michiel Prins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 290: Prototyping with Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2197</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/290"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T13:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V Körbes returns to talk prototyping with Natalie, Johnny & Kris. Is Go good for prototyping? What makes a language prototypable, anyway? How does space radiation fit in to all this? Tune in and ride along to find out!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

V Körbes – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:35) - Sponsor: Tailscale
(03:11) - V Körbes
(05:01) - Java for prototyping
(05:37) - What makes a language prototypable
(11:59) - Individual prototyping
(25:47) - The rest of the stack
(29:35) - Is Go a great prototyping tool?
(34:17) - Bad considerations
(43:34) - Prototype less fluent
(44:41) - Johnny's rebuttal
(52:33) - Space radiation
(57:07) - Unpopular opinions!
(57:25) - Kris' unpop
(59:23) - V Körbes' unpop
(1:02:30) - Johnny's unpop
(1:03:11) - Natalie's unpop
(1:03:48) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to build an enterprise LLM application: Lessons from GitHub Copilot]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73994</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-06-how-to-build-an-enterprise-llm-application-lessons-from-github-copilot/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T19:04:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The team behind GitHub Copilot shares its lessons for building an LLM app that delivers value to both individuals and enterprise users at scale. 
The post How to build an enterprise LLM application: Lessons from GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuyin Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 556: OpenTF for an open Terraform]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2190</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/556"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking about the launch of OpenTF and what it’s going to take to successfully fork HashiCorp’s Terraform. We’re joined by Josh Padnick to discuss what exactly happened, how HashiCorp’s license change changes things, who has been impacted by this change, and ultimately what they are doing about it.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 6 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Simple, secure networks for teams of any scale. Built on WireGuard.

Sentry – Scheduled jobs are supposed to be predictable, but sometimes, predictable != reliable. Sentry Cron Monitoring (Beta) helps you monitor the uptime and performance of any scheduled or recurring job in Sentry. Learn more by attending this FREE webinar!

Fastly – Our ba…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 238: Fine-tuning vs RAG]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2203</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/238"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode we welcome back our good friend Demetrios from the MLOps Community to discuss fine-tuning vs. retrieval augmented generation. Along the way, we also chat about OpenAI Enterprise, results from the MLOps Community LLM survey, and the orchestration and evaluation of generative AI workloads.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!


Featuring:

Demetrios Brinkmann – Twitter
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

MLOps Community
LLM survey report
LLMs in Production Event - Part III
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:43) - Practical AI & Friends
(02:01) - Look into MLOps community
(04:19) - Changes in the AI community
(07:34) - Finding the norm
(08:30) - Matching models & uses
(11:21) - Stages of debugging
(13:10) - Layer orchestration
(16:26) - Practical hot takes
(21:46) - Fine-tuning is more work
(24:13) - Retrieval augmented generation
(31:23) - MLOps survey
(38:09) - The next survey
(41:50) - Enterprise hypetrain
(42:39) - OpenAI & your data
(43:19) - AI vendor lock-in?
(47:44) - Now what do we do?
(48:58) - Hype in the AI life
(56:35) - Goodbye
(57:23) - Outro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Abstraction to Improve Function Readability]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/09/use-abstraction-to-improve-function.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/09/use-abstraction-to-improve-function.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T12:29:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is another post in our Code Health series. A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office.


By Palak Bansal and Mark Manley


 Which version of the createPizza function below is easier to understand?



func createPizza(order *Order) *Pizza {  
  pizza := &Pizza{Base: order.Size,
                  Sauce: order.Sauce,
                  Cheese: “Mozzarella”}

  if order.kind == “Veg” {
    pizza.Toppings = vegToppings
  } else if order.kind == “Meat” {
    pizza.Toppings = meatToppings
  }

  oven := oven.New()
  if oven.Temp != cookingTemp { 
    for (oven.Temp < cookingTemp) {
      time.Sleep(checkOvenInterval)
      oven.Temp = getOvenTemp(oven)…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions, shrugs and what comes next: A quarter century of change]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/inside-google/message-ceo/google-25th-birthday-sundar-pichai/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/inside-google/message-ceo/google-25th-birthday-sundar-pichai/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T22:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since Google was founded, we’ve worked to answer hard questions, help people get answers to theirs, and move technology forward for the world.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 60: A portrait of the best worst programmer]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2204</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/60"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dan North tells the tale of Tim, the worst programmer he’s worked with (who also is a heck of a programmer), Kevin Lin declares that OpenTelemetry delivers on its promise for open observability, Justin Garrison details Terraform vs GitOps vs System Initiative, Inc. writes how Apple beats burnout & Aline Lerner’s advice on how (not) to sabotage your salary negotiations before you even start.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Warp – Warp is a modern, Rust-based terminal with AI built in so you and your team can build great software faster. Download it today


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:28) - The best worst programmer
(01:46) - OpenTelemetry in 2023
(02:50) - Terraform v GitOps v System Initiative
(04:03) - Sponsor: Warp
(04:54) - How Apple beats burnout
(06:10) - How to sabotage your salary negotiations
(06:46) - Outro (Shout outs++)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bogus CVE follow-ups]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=22993</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/09/05/bogus-cve-follow-ups/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T17:07:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On August 26 I posted details here on my blog about the bogus curl issue CVE-2020-19909. Luckily, it got a lot of attention and triggered discussions widely. Maybe I helped shed light on the brittleness of this system. This was not a unique instance and it was not the first time it happened. This has … Continue reading Bogus CVE follow-ups →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Faster Vue.js Execution in Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48028</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2023/09/faster-vue-js-execution-in-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T16:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox performance on Vue.js has improved significantly throughout the year. Most recently, we sped up reactivity with Proxy optimizations. This change landed in Firefox 118, so it’s currently on Beta and will ride along to Release by the end of September.
The post Faster Vue.js Execution in Firefox appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Grinstead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring the impact of Twitter network latency with CausalImpact]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T12:02:32.376Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share how we adopted the CausalImpact package from Google on a Twitter edge network experiment to measure the impact of improving Twitter's latency on customer engagement and revenue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kerberizing Hadoop Clusters at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/kerberizing-hadoop-clusters-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/kerberizing-hadoop-clusters-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T12:02:32.354Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraint Management for cluster operation safety and reliability at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/constraint-management-for-cluster-operation-safety-and-reliability-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/constraint-management-for-cluster-operation-safety-and-reliability-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T12:02:32.323Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As any team and its infrastructure grows, the risk of an unplanned service outage and potential data loss will grow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we scaled Reads On the Twitter Users Database]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-we-scaled-reads-on-the-twitter-users-database</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-we-scaled-reads-on-the-twitter-users-database"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T12:02:32.309Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter’s Blobstore Hardware Lifecycle Monitoring and Reporting Service]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/twitters-blobstore-hardware-lifecycle-monitoring-and-reporting-service</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/twitters-blobstore-hardware-lifecycle-monitoring-and-reporting-service"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T12:02:32.292Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter's Recommendation Algorithm]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2023/twitter-recommendation-algorithm</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2023/twitter-recommendation-algorithm"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T12:02:32.033Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter aims to deliver you the best of what’s happening in the world right now. This blog is an introduction to how the algorithm selects Tweets for your timeline.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Quality Automation at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T12:02:43.449Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we share how Twitter implemented a Data Quality Platform that gave customers the ability to have automated data quality checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The curl-wget Venn diagram]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=23032</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/09/04/the-curl-wget-venn-diagram/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T08:10:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my view, wget is not a curl competitor. It is a companion tool that has a feature overlap with curl. Use the tool that does the job. Getting the job done is the key. If that means using wget instead of curl, then that is good and I don’t mind. Why would I? To … Continue reading The curl-wget Venn diagram →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 12: You call it tech debt I call it malpractice]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2193</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/12"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time panelist (and semi-professional unpopular opinion maker) Kris Brandow joins us to discuss his deep-dive on the waterfall paper, his dislike of the “tech debt” analogy, why documentation matters so much & how everything is a distributed system.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops requir…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[De-risking Real-time ML Projects: Addressing Common Failure Modes]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21313</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/de-risking-real-time-ml-projects-addressing-common-failure-modes/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T18:35:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post we list practices to substantially reduce the risk of failure in real-time machine learning projects.
The post De-risking Real-time ML Projects: Addressing Common Failure Modes appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felipe Almeida - Machine Learning Engineer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 290: Modernizing packages to ESM]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2194</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/290"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Erikson (web dev professor/historian, OSS Maintainer & engineer at Replay) joins us to talk about the shift from CommonJS to ESM. We discuss the history of module patterns in JS and the grueling effort to push the world’s biggest developer ecosystem forward. Get ready to go to school kids, this one’s deep!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 5 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You iterlly can’t get any faster!

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Mark Erikson – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

My Experience Modernizing Packages to ESM - Mark’s epic blog post
History and Timeline of ES Modules
Node API Reference for ESM
Andrew Branch’s WIP TypeScript module processing documentation
Sindre Sorhus: Pure ESM packages
Modern Guide to Packaging a JS Library
Guide for shipping ESM and CJS in one Package
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!
Timestamps:
(00:56) - Welcoming back Mark
(03:28) - A history lesson
(10:36) - UMDs were hot ...
(11:49) - History continued
(16:59) - Enter TypeScript
(21:28) - Publish as a Service
(22:51) - Common pain points
(31:30) - Sponsor: Changelog News
(32:42) - Recapping the post
(44:22) - Running multiple tests
(51:51) - We need standards
(59:07) - Parting thoughts
(1:03:03) - Closing time
(1:04:06) - Next up on the pod (Changelog++!)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with edge computing]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73957</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-09-01-getting-started-with-edge-computing/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T15:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Edge computing practitioners answer your questions about when and why to build applications at the edge.
The post Getting started with edge computing appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klint Finley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You're Doing Pentesting Wrong]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/penetration-testing/youre-doing-pentesting-wrong</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/penetration-testing/youre-doing-pentesting-wrong"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T16:42:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leveraging the power of the pentester community and the efficiency of a Pentest as a Service (PTaaS) platform, pentesting can add real value to your organization.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Spencer Chin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You're Doing Pentesting Wrong]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/youre-doing-pentesting-wrong</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/youre-doing-pentesting-wrong"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T16:42:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leveraging the power of the pentester community and the efficiency of a Pentest as a Service (PTaaS) platform, pentesting can add real value to your organization.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Spencer Chin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitHub reduces costs with upgraded Codespaces]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=73937</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-08-31-how-github-reduces-costs-with-upgraded-codespaces/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T15:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[See how much more you can get out of GitHub Codespaces by taking advantage of the improved processing power and increased headroom the RAM provides.
The post How GitHub reduces costs with upgraded Codespaces appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Craig Peters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing generative AI in Search to more people around the world]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/search/google-search-generative-ai-india-japan/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/search/google-search-generative-ai-india-japan/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re bringing generative AI capabilities in Search (SGE) to more people, making  Search Labs available in India and Japan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>