<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-05-07T12:03:35.694Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 93: Why your framework doesn't matter]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2423</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/93"/>
        <updated>2024-05-06T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bahaa Zidan says your web framework doesn’t matter, DHH writes about magic machines, Dylan Huang reviews thousands of opinions on HTMX, Tim Ottinger says programming is thinking & Tim Spann says small language models (SLM) for the win.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create a home for your community with GitHub Discussions]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77863</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-05-06-create-a-home-for-your-community-with-github-discussions/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-06T18:43:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Community-in-a-box provides the tooling, resources, and knowledge you need to build internal communities of learning at scale with GitHub Discussions.
The post Create a home for your community with GitHub Discussions appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Ossowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 102: Managing Meta's millions of machines]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/2406</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/102"/>
        <updated>2024-05-04T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anita Zhang is here to tell us how Meta manages millions of bare metal Linux hosts and containers. We also discuss the Twine white paper and how AI is changing their requirements.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 8 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals

Sentry – Code breaks, fix it faster. Don’t just observe. Take action. Sentry is the only app monitoring platform built for developers that gets to the root cause for every issue. 90,000+ growing teams use sentry to find problems fast. Use the code CHANGELOG when you sign up to get $100 OFF the team plan.


Featuring:

Anita Zhang – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Justin Garrison – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Autumn Nash – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
Links of the week
Decoder podcast with Drew Houston
Twine: A Unified Cluster Management System for Shared Infrastructure
Faux or fo sho
Attention is all you need
Probabilistic Inference in Language Models via Twisted Sequential Monte Carlo
Causally Abstracted Multi-armed Bandits
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 42: The Wu-Tang way]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2421</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/42"/>
        <updated>2024-05-03T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our friend Ron Evans is a technologist for hire, an open source developer, an author, a speaker, an iconoclast, and one of our favorite people in tech. This conversation with Ron goes everywhere: from high-altitude weather balloons, to life on Mars, to Zeno’s paradox applied to ML, to what open source devs should learn from the Wu-Tang Clan & more.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Cloudflare – Read the Developer Week 2024 wrap-up or tune into Developer Week on Cloudflare TV.

Sentry – Code breaks, fix it faster. Don’t just observe. Take action. Sentry is the only app monitoring platform built for developers that gets to the root cause for every issue. 90,000+ growing teams use sentry to find problems fast. Use the code CHANGELOG when you sign up to get $100 OFF the team plan.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Ron Evans – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website

Show Notes:

Book: A City on Mars
Bio-Dome - Wikipedia
Zeno’s paradoxes
TinyGo on Hackaday
ggerganov/llama.cpp: LLM inference in C/C++
What exactly is Open Source AI? with Stefano Maffulli
On the dangers of stochastic parrots | The Alan Turing Institute
2053: A Go Odyssey (Go Time #235)
Getting started with TinyGo
Looking back at Go from 2053 with Ron Evans - YouTube
The Hybrid Group
Ali Spagnola - YouTube
GopherCon 2024 - Register Now
FOSDEM 2024 - Home
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependabot on GitHub Actions and self-hosted runners is now generally available]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77824</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-05-02-dependabot-on-github-actions-and-self-hosted-runners-is-now-generally-available/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-02T16:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quick guide on the advantages of Dependabot as a GitHub Actions workflow and the benefits this unlocks, including self-hosted runner support.
The post Dependabot on GitHub Actions and self-hosted runners is now generally available appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlin Cherry</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Artifact Attestations–now in public beta]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77830</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-05-02-introducing-artifact-attestations-now-in-public-beta/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-02T16:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generate and verify signed attestations for anything you make with GitHub Actions.
The post Introducing Artifact Attestations–now in public beta appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Trevor Rosen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 321: SSR web components for all]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2402</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/321"/>
        <updated>2024-05-02T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brian LeRoux joins Jerod to share how the Enhance team are bringing server side rendered web components to everyone. With Enhance WASM, you author components in friendly, standards based syntax and reuse them across multiple languages, frameworks & servers.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 10 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Speakeasy – Instantly create SDKs that make API integration easy for your users. Create your first SDK for free! today.

Clerk – Clerk is a complete suite of embeddable UIs, flexible APIs, and admin dashboards to authenticate and manage your users.

Sentry – Code breaks, fix it faster. Don’t just observe. Take action. Sentry is the only app monitoring platform built for developers that gets to the root cause for every issue. 90,000+ growing teams use sentry to find problems fast. Use the code CHANGELOG when you sign up to get $100 OFF the team plan.


Featuring:

Brian Leroux – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

Enhance
Enhance WASM
Extism
Begin
Architect
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating 1 year of A11y Design Bootcamp: Takeaways and tips]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77819</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-05-02-celebrating-1-year-of-a11y-design-bootcamp-takeaways-and-tips/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-02T15:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A11y Design Bootcamp is a live educational program that consists of exercises, discussions, and knowledge shares to raise awareness of web accessibility best practices, the role designers play in creating accessible products, and how to advocate for accessibility with cross-functional partners.
The post Celebrating 1 year of A11y Design Bootcamp: Takeaways and tips appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexis Lucio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Google Account allows you to create passkeys on your phone, computer and security keys]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/05/passkeys-on-your-phone-computer-and-security-keys.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/05/passkeys-on-your-phone-computer-and-security-keys.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-02T11:59:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sriram Karra and Christiaan Brand, Google product managers


Last year, Google launched passkey support for Google Accounts. Passkeys are a new industry standard that give users an easy, highly secure way to sign-in to apps and websites. Today, we announced that passkeys have been used to authenticate users more than 1 billion times across over 400 million Google Accounts.





As more users encounter passkeys, we’re often asked questions about how they relate to security keys, how Google Workspace administrators can configure passkeys for the user accounts that they manage, and how they relate to the Advanced Protection Program (APP). This post will seek to clarify these topics.





Passkeys and security keys
Passkeys are an evolution of security keys, meaning users get the same security…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Empowering accessibility: GitHub’s journey building an in-house Champions program]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77810</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-05-01-empowering-accessibility-githubs-journey-building-an-in-house-champions-program/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-01T17:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of GitHub's dedication to accessibility, we expanded our internal accessibility program and scaled up our internal auditing process to help remove or lower barriers for users with disabilities. Then, we empowered employees from various disciplines to drive accessibility efforts within their teams.
The post Empowering accessibility: GitHub’s journey building an in-house Champions program appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carie Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 tips to supercharge your developer career in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77775</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-05-01-5-tips-to-supercharge-your-developer-career-in-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-01T16:10:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From mastering prompt engineering to leveraging AI for code security, here’s how you can excel in today's competitive job market.  
The post 5 tips to supercharge your developer career in 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeimy Ruiz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 589: Castro leans into indie]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2420</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/589"/>
        <updated>2024-05-01T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Dustin Bluck to discuss his acquisition of the well known (and beloved) Castro podcast app to take it indie-focused once again. As previous users of Castro, we were excited to dig into the details behind this popular podcast client to see what’s next, how the deal was done, a peek into the code, and where exactly this indie and creator focused podcast app can go.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 3 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – Code breaks, fix it faster. Don’t just observe. Take action. Sentry is the only app monitoring platform built for developers that gets to the root cause for every issue. 90,000+ growing teams use sentry to find problems fast. Use the code CHANGELOG when you sign up to get $100 OFF the team plan.

Cloudflare – Read the Developer Week 2024 wrap-up or tune into Developer Week on Cloudflare TV.

Notion – Notion is a place where any team can write, plan, organize, and rediscover the joy of play. It’s a workspace designed not just for making progress, but getting inspired. Notion is for everyone — whether you’re a Fortune 500 company or freelance designer, starting a new startup or a student juggling classes and clubs.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Dustin Bluck – GitHub, Website
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

A Fresh Start for Castro
Podcast app Castro now owned by indie developer Bluck Apps
I am the owner of Castro Podcasts. Ask me anything!
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 314: Go workshops that work]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2416</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/314"/>
        <updated>2024-04-30T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes a good, bad, and truly great workshop? How do you put together a Go workshop that works, and how do you get the most out of workshops you attend?
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 8 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals

Speakeasy – Instantly create SDKs that make API integration easy for your users. Create your first SDK for free! today.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Angelica Hill – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

Go Bridge
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 267: Private, open source chat UIs]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2419</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/267"/>
        <updated>2024-04-30T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We recently gathered some Practical AI listeners for a live webinar with Danny from LibreChat to discuss the future of private, open source chat UIs. During the discussion we hear about the motivations behind LibreChat, why enterprise users are hosting their own chat UIs, and how Danny (and the LibreChat community) is creating amazing features (like RAG and plugins).
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Danny Avila – Twitter
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Register for our next webinar (similar to this one) focused on multimodal AI
LibreChat
Prediction Guard
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where does your software (really) come from?]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77757</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-30-where-does-your-software-really-come-from/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-30T16:35:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub is working with the OSS community to bring new supply chain security capabilities to the platform.
The post Where does your software (really) come from? appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Trevor Rosen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting browser data theft using Windows Event Logs]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/detecting-browser-data-theft-using.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/detecting-browser-data-theft-using.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-30T16:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by  Will Harris, Chrome Security Team




    
.code {
    font-family: "Courier New", Courier, monospace;
    font-size: 11.8px;
    font-weight: bold;
    background-color: #f4f4f4;
    padding: 2px;
    border: 1px solid #ccc;
    border-radius: 2px;
    white-space: pre-wrap;
    display: inline-block;
    line-height: 12px;
}
.highlight {
    color: red;
}
    






Chromium's sandboxed process model defends well from malicious web content, but there are limits to how well the application can protect itself from malware already on the computer. Cookies and other credentials remain a high value target for attackers, and we are trying to tackle this ongoing threat in multiple ways, including working on web standards like
  DBSC
  that will help disrupt the cookie theft industry …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Art and Science of Product Management: An In-Depth Interview with Jag Duggal]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=29049</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/the-art-and-science-of-product-management-an-in-depth-interview-with-jag-duggal/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-30T13:28:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read on for valuable tips and best practices to take your product management skills to the next level.
The post The Art and Science of Product Management: An In-Depth Interview with Jag Duggal appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 92: Good ideas in computer science]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2417</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/92"/>
        <updated>2024-04-29T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Hooper lists out all the good ideas in computer science, Jeff Geerling declares 2024 the year corporate open source dies, Jared Turner says all kinds of works-in-progress are waste, Daroc Alden covers the leadership crisis in the Nix community & John Hawthorn explains why Ruby may be faster than you think.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
CrabNebula Cloud – CrabNebula Cloud is here! Distribute Tauri apps and Electron apps with best in class updater. At the heart of CrabNebula Cloud is a purpose-built CDN ready for global scale, and secure updates as a first-class citizen. Learn more at crabnebula.dev/cloud


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highlights from Git 2.45]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77738</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-29-highlights-from-git-2-45/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-29T17:14:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 2.45 is here with experimental support for reftables, and SHA-256 interoperability. Get our take on the latest here.
The post Highlights from Git 2.45 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taylor Blau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Workspace: Welcome to the Copilot-native developer environment]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77597</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-29-github-copilot-workspace/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-29T16:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re redefining the developer environment with GitHub Copilot Workspace - where any developer can go from idea, to code, to software all in natural language. 
The post GitHub Copilot Workspace: Welcome to the Copilot-native developer environment appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Dohmke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we fought bad apps and bad actors in 2023]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/how-we-fought-bad-apps-and-bad-actors-in-2023.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/how-we-fought-bad-apps-and-bad-actors-in-2023.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-29T15:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Steve Kafka and Khawaja Shams (Android Security and Privacy Team), and Mohet Saxena (Play Trust and Safety)


A safe and trusted Google Play experience is our top priority. We leverage our SAFE (see below) principles to provide the framework to create that experience for both users and developers. Here's what these principles mean in practice:
(S)afeguard our Users. Help them discover quality apps that they can trust.

(A)dvocate for Developer Protection. Build platform safeguards to enable developers to focus on growth.

(F)oster Responsible Innovation. Thoughtfully unlock value for all without compromising on user safety.

(E)volve Platform Defenses. Stay ahead of emerging threats by evolving our policies, tools and technology.



With those principles in mind, we’ve made recen…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeQL zero to hero part 3: Security research with CodeQL]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77703</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-29-codeql-zero-to-hero-part-3-security-research-with-codeql/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-29T08:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to use CodeQL for security research and improve your security research workflow.
The post CodeQL zero to hero part 3: Security research with CodeQL appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sylwia Budzynska</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 101: Let's go back to AOL chat rooms]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/2405</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/101"/>
        <updated>2024-04-27T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode Justin and Autumn are joined by Mandi Walls to take you back to a time before the cloud. Before Kubernetes. When a/s/l was common and servers were made of metal. Back to the days of AOL to discuss how chat rooms worked.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively inte…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 41: The ol' hot & juicy]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2414</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/41"/>
        <updated>2024-04-26T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frequent guest (and almost real-life-friend) Adam Jacob returns to share his spicy takes on all the recent “open source meets business” drama. We also take some time to catch up on the state of his open source-based business, System Initiative.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 11 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Cloudflare – Read the Developer Week 2024 wrap-up or tune into Developer Week on Cloudflare TV.

imgproxy – imgproxy is open source an optimizes images for the web on the fly. It makes websites and apps blazing fast while saving storage and SaaS costs. It uses the world’s fastest image processing library under the hood — libvips. It is screaming fast and has a tiny memory footprint.

Sentry – Code breaks, fix it faster. Don’t just observe. Take action. Sentry is the only app monitoring platform built for developers that gets to the root cause for every issue. 90,000+ growing teams use sentry to find problems fast. Use the code CHANGELOG when you sign up to get $100 OFF the team plan.


Featuring:

Adam Jacob – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website

Show Notes:

IBM to Acquire HashiCorp, Inc.
Matt Asay on OpenTofu
System Initiative
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerating incident response using generative AI]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/accelerating-incident-response-using.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/accelerating-incident-response-using.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-26T17:27:00.023Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lambert Rosique and Jan Keller, Security Workflow Automation, and Diana Kramer, Alexandra Bowen and Andrew Cho, Privacy and Security Incident Response








Introduction
As security professionals, we're constantly looking for ways to reduce risk and improve our workflow's efficiency. We've made great strides in using AI to identify malicious content, block threats, and discover and fix vulnerabilities. We also published the Secure AI Framework (SAIF), a conceptual framework for secure AI systems to ensure we are deploying AI in a responsible manner. 





Today we are highlighting another way we use generative AI to help the defenders gain the advantage: Leveraging LLMs (Large Language Model) to speed-up our security and privacy incidents workflows.





Incident management is a team spo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Actions, Arm64, and the future of automotive software development]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77619</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-26-github-actions-arm64-and-the-future-of-automotive-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-26T15:33:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how GitHub's Enterprise Cloud, GitHub Actions, and Arm's latest Automotive Enhanced processors, work together to usher in a new era of efficient, scalable, and flexible automotive software creation.
The post GitHub Actions, Arm64, and the future of automotive software development appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clay Nelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 320: A Solid primer on Signals]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2413</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/320"/>
        <updated>2024-04-25T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Carniato joins Amal & Nick to discuss Solid with a major focus on Signals, which are the cornerstone of reactivity in Solid.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 11 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Clerk – Clerk is a complete suite of embeddable UIs, flexible APIs, and admin dashboards to authenticate and manage your users.

CrabNebula Cloud – CrabNebula Cloud is here! Distribute Tauri apps and Electron apps with best in class updater. At the heart of CrabNebula Cloud is a purpose-built CDN ready for global scale, and secure updates as a first-class citizen. Learn more at crabnebula.dev/cloud

Speakeasy – Instantly create SDKs that make API integration easy for your users. Create your first SDK for free! today.


Featuring:

Ryan Carniato – Twitter, GitHub
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Solid JS
Solid/Signals
The Signals Proposal
Solid’s Discord
Ryan’s YouTube
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a global product powerhouse]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=29032</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/building-a-global-product-powerhouse/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-25T17:32:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Insights from Jag Duggal, Nubank's CPO, on the Product Thinking Podcast: charting the path to 90 million customers and beyond
The post Building a global product powerhouse appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Llamafile’s progress, four months in]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48149</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2024/04/llamafiles-progress-four-months-in/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-25T15:34:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Mozilla’s Innovation group first launched the llamafile project late last year, we were thrilled by the immediate positive response from open source AI developers. It’s become one of Mozilla’s top three most-favorited repositories on GitHub, attracting a number of contributors, some excellent PRs, and a growing community on our Discord server.
The post Llamafile’s progress, four months in appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Hood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[isBooleanTooLongAndComplex]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2024/04/isbooleantoolongandcomplex.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2024/04/isbooleantoolongandcomplex.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-25T13:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@media only screen and (max-width: 600px) {
  .body {
    overflow-x: auto;
  }
}
  
@media (max-width: 480px), (max-height: 480px) {
.post-content table, .post-content td {
   width: auto !important;
   white-space: nowrap;
}



This is another post in our Code Health series. A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office.


By Yiming Sun



You may have come across some complex, hard-to-read Boolean expressions in your codebase and wished they were easier to understand. For example, let's say we want to decide whether a pizza is fantastic:



// Decide whether this pizza is fantastic.
if ((!pepperoniService.empty() || sausages.size() > 0)
    && (useO…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 266: Mamba & Jamba]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2412</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/266"/>
        <updated>2024-04-24T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First there was Mamba… now there is Jamba from AI21. This is a model that combines the best non-transformer goodness of Mamba with good ‘ol attention layers. This results in a highly performant and efficient model that AI21 has open sourced! We hear all about it (along with a variety of other LLM things) from AI21’s co-founder Yoav.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Yoav Shoham – Twitter, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Jamba - A Groundbreaking SSM - Transformer Open Model
AI21 Labs
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing millions of developers through 2FA]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77576</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-24-securing-millions-of-developers-through-2fa/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-24T15:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve dramatically increased 2FA adoption on GitHub as part of our responsibility to make the software ecosystem more secure. Read on to learn how we secured millions of developers and why we’re urging more organizations to join us in these efforts.
The post Securing millions of developers through 2FA appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Hanley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 588: Run Gleam run]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2382</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/588"/>
        <updated>2024-04-24T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Louis Pilfold, the creator of the Gleam programming language. For the uninitiated, Gleam is a functional programming language for building type-safe systems that compiles to Erlang and JavaScript and it’s written in Rust. We discuss the inspiration and development of Gleam, how it compares to other languages, where it shines, the overwhelming amount of support Louis is getting through GitHub sponsors, what’s next for Gleam and their near-term plans for a language server.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 12 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 313: What's new in Go's cryptography libraries: Part 3]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2356</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/313"/>
        <updated>2024-04-23T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 3 Musketeers return! Filippo Valsorda, Roland Shoemaker & Nicola Murino continue their deep-dive conversation with Natalie about Go’s crypto libraries.
Also listen to Part 1 and Part 2!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 9 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident manage…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Porting a cross-platform GUI application to Rust]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48127</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2024/04/porting-a-cross-platform-gui-application-to-rust/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-23T19:08:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we delve into the motivations for choosing Rust for our crash reporter, outline the unique challenges of designing an application that operates when the main browser has failed, and discuss the new architecture we've implemented. We also share insights into the technical nuances of the implementation, demonstrating how Rust's features are leveraged to handle crashes more effectively and securely.
The post Porting a cross-platform GUI application to Rust appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Franchuk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncovering potential threats to your web application by leveraging security reports]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/uncovering-potential-threats-to-your.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/uncovering-potential-threats-to-your.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-23T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Yoshi Yamaguchi, Santiago Díaz, Maud Nalpas,  Eiji Kitamura, DevRel team


The Reporting API is an emerging web standard that provides a generic reporting mechanism for issues occurring on the browsers visiting your production website. The reports you receive detail issues such as security violations or soon-to-be-deprecated APIs, from users’ browsers from all over the world.


Collecting reports is often as simple as specifying an endpoint URL in the HTTP header; the browser will automatically start forwarding reports covering the issues you are interested in to those endpoints. However, processing and analyzing these reports is not that simple. For example, you may receive a massive number of reports on your endpoint, and it is possible that not all of them will be helpful in i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software-driven Data Privacy: an innovative project journey]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=29011</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/software-driven-data-privacy-an-innovative-project-journey/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-22T22:11:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover how Nubank's TGIF sessions led to a groundbreaking data privacy solution, blending technology & customer-centricity with legal expertise.
The post Software-driven Data Privacy: an innovative project journey appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 91: The threat to open source comes from within]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2411</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/91"/>
        <updated>2024-04-22T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forrest Brazeal is concerned about the open source threat from within, Vicki Boykis explains why Redis is forked, John O’Nolan and the Ghost team plan to federate over ActivityPub, Llama 3 is now available for “businesses of all sizes” & nolen writes up questions to ask when you don’t want to work.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 2 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using open source to help the earth]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77565</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-22-using-open-source-to-help-the-earth/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-22T15:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Earth Day, we discuss how tech and open source are helping two organizations combat the effects of a changing climate.
The post Using open source to help the earth appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paull Young</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A short guide to mastering keyboard shortcuts on GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77552</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-19-a-short-guide-to-mastering-keyboard-shortcuts-on-github/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-19T16:37:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Say goodbye to constant mouse clicking and hello to seamless navigation with GitHub shortcuts. 
The post A short guide to mastering keyboard shortcuts on GitHub appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sara Verdi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 40: Rug pull, not cool!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2410</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/40"/>
        <updated>2024-04-19T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If Changelog News had an extended edition, this might be it! Jerod & Adam discuss Hashicorp’s Cease and Desist letter, Redis getting forked, Boston Dymanics’ scary cool new robot, Justin Searls’ extensive use of the Apple Vision Pro, Thorston Ball moving from Vim to Zed, Firefox becoming hard to use, Beeper joining Automattic & more.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 3 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Cloudflare – Read the Developer Week 2024 wrap-up or tune into Developer Week on Cloudflare TV.

FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. S…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 100: Bluesky apps]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/2334</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/100"/>
        <updated>2024-04-19T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Frazee joins the show to tell us all about how Bluesky builds, tests, and deploys mobile and web applications from the same code base.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals

Notion – Notion is a place where any team can write, plan, organize, and rediscover the joy of play. It’s a workspace designed not just for making progress, but getting inspired. Notion is for everyone — whether you’re a Fortune 500 company or freelance designer, starting a new startup or a student juggling classes and clubs.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Paul Frazee✌️ – Twitter, GitHub
Justin Garrison – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Autumn Nash – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
Links of the week
How does bluesky work
Twitter’s clumsy pivot to x.com is a gift to phishers
Justin on Bluesky
Autumn on Bluesky
Interview
Paul on Bluesky
Fresh OSS
Ozone
Bluesky social app
Personal Data Server
PRs
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 319: The boring JavaScript stack]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2395</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/319"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kelvin Omereshone is here to get you excited about boring, reliable tech. He believes a combination of Sails, Inertia, Tailwind & your frontend rendering library of choice are a great combo for building web apps. Tune in to find out why.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 10 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Speakeasy – Instantly create SDKs that make API integration easy for your users. Create your first SDK for free! today.

Clerk – Clerk is a complete suite of embeddable UIs, flexible APIs, and admin dashboards to authenticate and manage your users.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Kelvin Omereshone – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

The Boring JavaScript Stack
Sails.js
Screencasts for the modern Sails developer
Hagfish - Where creators do invoices
Inertia
Sailsconf
The Boring JavaScript Stack (keynote)
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A policy proposal on our approach to deepfake tools and responsible AI]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77541</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-18-a-policy-proposal-on-our-approach-to-deepfake-tools-and-responsible-ai/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T17:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re asking for feedback on a proposed Acceptable Use Policy update to address the use of synthetic and manipulated media tools for non-consensual intimate imagery and disinformation while protecting valuable research.
The post A policy proposal on our approach to deepfake tools and responsible AI appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jesse Geraci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Windows Registry Adventure #2: A brief history of the feature]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/04/the-windows-registry-adventure-2.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/04/the-windows-registry-adventure-2.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T16:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@import url(https://themes.googleusercontent.com/fonts/css?kit=lhDjYqiy3mZ0x6ROQEUoUw);ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-8{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-7{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-6{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-5{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-4{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-3{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-2{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-1{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_qqcc7cub1y3f-1>li:before{content:"\0025cb   "}ul.lst-kix_isoepzyy3bf4-0{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_qqcc7cub1y3f-0>li:before{content:"\0025cf   "}.lst-kix_qqcc7cub1y3f-5>li:before{content:"\0025a0   "}.lst-kix_qqcc7cub1y3f-3>li:before{content:"\0025cf   "}.lst-kix_qqcc7cub1y3f-7>li:before{content:"\0025cb   "}.lst-kix_qqcc7c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Windows Registry Adventure #1: Introduction and research results]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/04/the-windows-registry-adventure-1.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/04/the-windows-registry-adventure-1.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ul.lst-kix_c4pdvykpeuss-3{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_c4pdvykpeuss-2{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_c4pdvykpeuss-1{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_c4pdvykpeuss-0{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_2wnifzn4nxg9-1>li:before{content:"\0025cb   "}ul.lst-kix_5uedwcx8bazf-3{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_5uedwcx8bazf-4{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_2wnifzn4nxg9-0>li:before{content:"\0025cf   "}.lst-kix_2wnifzn4nxg9-2>li:before{content:"\0025a0   "}.lst-kix_4m34njm6c6og-6>li:before{content:"\0025cf   "}ul.lst-kix_5uedwcx8bazf-5{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_5uedwcx8bazf-6{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_2wnifzn4nxg9-3>li:before{content:"\0025cf   "}.lst-kix_4m34njm6c6og-7>li:before{content:"\0025cb   "}ul.lst-kix_5uedwcx8bazf-7{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_5uedwcx8bazf-8{list-style-type:none}…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevent Generative AI Data Leaks with Chrome Enterprise DLP]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/prevent-generative-ai-data-leaks-with.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/prevent-generative-ai-data-leaks-with.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T16:07:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted Kaleigh Rosenblat, Chrome Enterprise Senior Staff Software Engineer, Security Lead 


Generative AI has emerged as a powerful and popular tool to automate content creation and simple tasks. From customized content creation to source code generation, it can increase both our productivity and creative potential.


Businesses want to leverage the power of LLMs, like Gemini, but many may have security concerns and want more control around how employees make sure of these new tools. For example, companies may want to ensure that various forms of sensitive data, such as Personally Identifiable Information (PII), financial records and internal intellectual property, is not to be shared publicly on Generative AI platforms. Security leaders face the challenge of finding the right balance — e…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Learned To Stop Writing Brittle Tests and Love Expressive APIs]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2024/04/how-i-learned-to-stop-writing-brittle.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2024/04/how-i-learned-to-stop-writing-brittle.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T12:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@media only screen and (max-width: 600px) {
  .body {
    overflow-x: auto;
  }
}
  
@media (max-width: 480px), (max-height: 480px) {
.post-content table, .post-content td {
   width: auto !important;
   white-space: nowrap;
}



This article was adapted from a Google Testing on the Toilet (TotT) episode. You can download a printer-friendly version of this TotT episode and post it in your office.


By Titus Winters



A valuable but challenging property for tests is “resilience,” meaning a test should only fail when something important has gone wrong. However, an opposite property may be easier to see: A “brittle” test is one that fails not for real problems that would break in production, but because the test itself is fragile for innocuous reasons. Error messages, changing the order of m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 312: Local cert management for mere mortals]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2373</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/312"/>
        <updated>2024-04-17T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, Ben Burkert & Chris Stolt join Johhny to explore the ups & downs of trying to get secure local development environments set up, why it’s hard & what you can do about it.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals

Notion – Notion is a place where any team can write, plan, organize, and rediscover the joy of play. It’s a workspace designed not just for making progress, but getting inspired. Notion is for everyone — whether you’re a Fortune 500 company or freelance designer, starting a new startup or a student juggling classes and clubs.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Ben Burkert – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Chris Stolt – Twitter
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

lcl.host
anchor on GitHub
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 587: Leading and building Raycast]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2403</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/587"/>
        <updated>2024-04-17T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Adam is joined by Thomas Paul Mann, Co-founder and CEO of Raycast, to discuss being productive on a Mac, going beyond their free tier, the extensions built by the community, the Raycast Store, how they’re executing on Raycast AI chat which aims to be a single interface to many LLMs. Raycast has gone beyond being an extendable launcher – they’ve gone full-on productivity mode with access to AI paving the way of their future.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 11 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 265: Udio & the age of multi-modal AI]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2401</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/265"/>
        <updated>2024-04-16T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2024 promises to be the year of multi-modal AI, and we are already seeing some amazing things. In this “fully connected” episode, Chris and Daniel explore the new Udio product/service for generating music. Then they dig into the differences between recent multi-modal efforts and more “traditional” ways of combining data modalities.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 26 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.


Featuring:

Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Udio
CLIP
BridgeTower
LLaVA
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s fair of software: Join us at GitHub Universe 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77511</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-16-the-worlds-fair-of-software-join-us-at-github-universe-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-16T16:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s the 10th anniversary of our global developer event! Celebrate with us by picking up in-person tickets today. It’s bound to be our best one yet.
The post The world’s fair of software: Join us at GitHub Universe 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeimy Ruiz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Nubank was listed among Brazil’s LinkedIn Top Companies in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=28975</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/why-nubank-was-listed-among-brazils-linkedin-top-companies-in-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-16T14:07:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The list celebrates companies that empower and elevate their workforce for sustained career growth
The post Why Nubank was listed among Brazil’s LinkedIn Top Companies in 2024 appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 90: Devin's Upwork "side hustle" exposed]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2400</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/90"/>
        <updated>2024-04-15T18:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[YouTuber “Internet of Bugs” breaks down why AI “software engineer” Devin is no Upwork hero, Redka is Anton Zhiyanov’s attempt to reimplement Redis with SQLite, OpenTofu issues its response to Hashicorp’s Cease and Desist letter, Brian LeRoux introduces Enhance WASM & PumpkinOS is not your average PalmOS emulator.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Tailscale – Adam loves Tailscale! Tailscale is programmable networking software that’s private and secure by default. It’s the easiest way to connect devices and services to each other, wherever they are. Secure, remote access to production, databases, servers, kubernetes, and more. Try Tailscale for free for up to 100 devices and 3 users at changelog.com/tailscale, no credit card required.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 39: More BMC goodness]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2399</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/39"/>
        <updated>2024-04-13T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our beat freak in residence returns, this time to discuss the shiny new Dance Party album! We deconstruct its nostalgic mix, break down some of our favorite tracks & even learn that BMC is writing a mysterious book…
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 9 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on what matters. Manage coverage requests and on-call notifications effortlessly within Slack. But here’s the game-changer…Signals natively integrates with FireHydrant’s full incident management suite, so as soon as you’re alerted you can seamlessly kickoff and manage your entire incident inside a single platform. Learn more or switch today at firehydrant.com/signals

Tailscale – Adam loves Tailscale! Tailscale is programmable networking software that’s private and secure by default. It’s the easiest way to connect devices and services to each other, wherever they are. Secure, remote access to production, databases, servers, kubernetes, and more. Try Tailscale for free for up to 100 devices and 3 users at changelog.com/tailscale, no credit card required.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Breakmaster Cylinder – Twitter, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website

Show Notes:

Dance Party
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 99: From Kubernetes to Nix]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/2386</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/99"/>
        <updated>2024-04-13T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would you want to switch your developer environments from containers to nix? Ádám from LastPass has a few reasons.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 9 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Synadia – Take NATS to the next level via a global, multi-cloud, multi-geo and extensible service, fully managed by Synadia. They take care of all the infrastructure, management, monitoring, and maintenance for you so you can focus on building exceptional distributed applications.

Sentry – AI-powered Autofix debugs & fixes your code in minutes. Give it a try… oh, and don’t forget to use code CHANGELOG when you sign up for Sentry to get $100 off their team plan. ✊

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Ádám Szücs-Mátyás – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Justin Garrison – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Autumn Nash – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
Links of the week
Software needs to be more expensive
NASA moon rover lunar terrain vehicle proposals
Interview
Devenv
Remote dev environments
Amazon Workspaces
VScode code-server
Gitpod
Codespaces
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 586: Replacing Git with Git]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2398</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/586"/>
        <updated>2024-04-12T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking to Scott Chacon, one of the co-founders of GitHub, to discuss the history and future of Git and Scott’s new project Git Butler, a branch manager tool that’s aiming to improve the developer experience of Git using Git. We also touch on the contentious topic of open source licensing and the challenges of defining “Open Source”, FSL vs GPL, and more.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 2 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
FireHydrant – The alerting and on-call tool designed for humans, not systems. Signals puts teams at the center, giving you ultimate control over rules, policies, and schedules. No need to configure your services or do wonky work-arounds. Signals filters out the noise, alerting you only on wha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 318: Off to see the Wiz]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2392</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/318"/>
        <updated>2024-04-11T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How does Google build Search? What about YouTube and Google Drive? We rely on Chrome’s Lighthouse scores when optimizing our websites, but what does Google prioritize? Recently the Angular and Wiz teams announced their intention to responsibly merge their internal frontend framework, Wiz, with Angular to bring some of Wiz’s best ideas to Angular. We’re chatting with Minko from Angular and Jatin from the Wiz team to learn about how Wiz has been used in Google historically, what it’s good at, and why it’s worth bringing some of its ideas to Angular.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 11 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
CrabNebula Cloud – CrabNebula Cloud is here! Distribute Tauri apps and Electron apps with best in class updater. At the heart of CrabNebula Cloud is a purpose-built CDN ready for global scale, and secure updates as a first-class citizen. Learn more at crabnebula.dev/cloud

Clerk – Clerk is a complete suite of embeddable UIs, flexible APIs, and admin dashboards to authenticate and manage your users.

Speakeasy – Instantly create SDKs that make API integration easy for your users. Create your first SDK for free! today.


Featuring:

Minko Gechev – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jatin Ramanathan – Twitter, LinkedIn
Kevin Ball – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jessica Sachs – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Angular and Wiz Are Better Together
Deferrable Views
JSParty 312 - Angular Moves fast without breaking things
JSAction
JSParty 237 - Qwik is a new kind of web framework
HTTP Archive
Angular primitives directory
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All In Africa: New cohort now open!]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77473</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-11-all-in-africa-new-cohort-now-open/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-11T16:13:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As we’re opening up the doors to our final class of this programmatic year, we’re also looking back at our recent graduates and the partners that helped make them a success.
The post All In Africa: New cohort now open! appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Oyetubo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prototype even faster with the Gradio UI for Figma component library]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48138</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2024/04/prototype-even-faster-with-the-gradio-ui-for-figma-component-library/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-11T15:13:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the fast-paced world of generative AI, staying ahead means moving swiftly and smartly. That's why we've embraced Gradio, the low-code prototyping toolkit from Hugging Face, as our go-to for bringing new ideas to life. 
The post Prototype even faster with the Gradio UI for Figma component library appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Thermidor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helping policymakers weigh the benefits of open source AI]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77448</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-10-helping-policymakers-weigh-the-benefits-of-open-source-ai/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-10T22:53:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub enables developer collaboration on innovative software projects, and we’re committed to ensuring policymakers understand developer needs when crafting AI regulation.
The post Helping policymakers weigh the benefits of open source AI appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Cihon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: March 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77425</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-10-github-availability-report-march-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-10T20:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In March, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services. 
The post GitHub Availability Report: March 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 264: RAG continues to rise]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2391</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/264"/>
        <updated>2024-04-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel & Chris delight in conversation with “the funniest guy in AI”, Demetrios Brinkmann.  Together they explore the results of the MLOps Community’s latest survey. They also preview the upcoming AI Quality Conference.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
The Hacker Mindset – “The Hacker Mindset” written by Garrett Gee, a seasoned white hat hacker with over 20 years of experience, is available for pre-order now. This book reveals the secrets of white hat hacking and how you can apply them to overcome obstacles and achieve your goals. In a world where hacking often gets a bad rap, this book shows you the white hat side – the side focused on innovation, problem-solving, and ethical principles.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Demetrios Brinkmann – Twitter
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

MLOps Community
AI Quality Conference
Evaluation Survey
RAG failover talk from Jerry Lui
Prompt Templates the Song
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making of VES: the Cosmos Microservice for Netflix Video Encoding]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/946b9b3cd300</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/the-making-of-ves-the-cosmos-microservice-for-netflix-video-encoding-946b9b3cd300?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2024-04-09T22:12:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liwei Guo, Vinicius Carvalho, Anush Moorthy, Aditya Mavlankar, Lishan Zhu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mastering Databricks performance with Spark UI]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=28950</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/mastering-databricks-performance-with-spark-ui/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-09T21:25:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with large datasets, Spark UI offers clarity by presenting operation data in a comprehensible manner.
The post Mastering Databricks performance with Spark UI appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 311: Ship software, not code]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2362</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/311"/>
        <updated>2024-04-09T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Natalie is joined by Carlos Becker (a Brazil-based software developer who maintains GoReleaser and other OSS software) to discuss how GOOS and GOARCH spark joy.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Boot.dev – Learn backend development the smart way. Boot.dev is the most captivating, finger-flying, addictive way to learn to code.

Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Carlos Becker – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

GoReleaser
K3s
Pprof
testscript
uber-go/goleak
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 ways GitHub engineers use GitHub Copilot]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77334</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-09-4-ways-github-engineers-use-github-copilot/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-09T19:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot increases efficiency for our engineers by allowing us to automate repetitive tasks, stay focused, and more.
The post 4 ways GitHub engineers use GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Holger Staudacher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explore the seasons of software development with four full years of data]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=77332</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2024-04-09-explore-the-seasons-of-software-development-with-four-full-years-of-data/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-09T15:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover the latest trends and insights on public software development activity on GitHub with the release of Q4 2023 data for the Innovation Graph.
The post Explore the seasons of software development with four full years of data appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 89: HashiCorp strikes back]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2397</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/89"/>
        <updated>2024-04-08T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HashiCorp sends OpenTufu a nasty-gram in the wake of Matt Asay’s infringement claims, Polar is like Patreon but for software creators, a Common Corpus of LLM data is released on HuggingFace & Loki is an open source tool for fact verification.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Synadia – Take NATS to the next level via a global, multi-cloud, multi-geo and extensible service, fully managed by Synadia. They take care of all the infrastructure, management, monitoring, and maintenance for you so you can focus on building exceptional distributed applications.

Tailscale – Adam loves Tailscale! Tailscale is programmable networking software that’s private and secure by default. It’s the easiest way to connect devices and services to each other, wherever they are. Secure, remote access to production, databases, servers, kubernetes, and more. Try Tailscale for free for up to 100 devices and 3 users at changelog.com/tailscale, no credit card required.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we built the new Find My Device network with user security and privacy in mind]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/find-my-device-network-security-privacy-protections.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/04/find-my-device-network-security-privacy-protections.html"/>
        <updated>2024-04-08T16:00:00.011Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Dave Kleidermacher, VP Engineering, Android Security and Privacy


the new Find My Device, which uses a crowdsourced device-locating network to help you find your lost or misplaced devices and belongings quickly – even when they’re offline. We gave careful consideration to the potential user security and privacy challenges that come with device finding services. 
During development, it was important for us to ensure the new Find My Device was secure by default and private by design. To build a private, crowdsourced device-locating network, we first conducted user research and gathered feedback from privacy and advocacy groups. Next, we developed multi-layered protections across three main areas: data safeguards, safety-first protections, and user controls. This approach provides …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>