<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T12:02:38.029Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Democratizing access to AI-enabled coding with Colab]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/democratizing-access-to-ai-enabled-coding-with-colab/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/democratizing-access-to-ai-enabled-coding-with-colab/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of how we're expanding code assistance features to all Colab users.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 250: Open source, on-disk vector search with LanceDB]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2291</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/250"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T19:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prashanth Rao mentioned LanceDB as a stand out amongst the many vector DB options in episode #234. Now, Chang She (co-founder and CEO of LanceDB) joins us to talk through the specifics of their open source, on-disk, embedded vector search offering. We talk about how their unique columnar database structure enables serverless deployments and drastic savings (without performance hits) at scale. This one is super practical, so don’t miss it!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You literally can’t get any faster!


Featuring:

Chang She – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

LanceDB
Episode #234 “Vector DBs beyond the hype”
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we organize and get things done with SERVICEOWNERS]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75858</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-19-how-we-organize-and-get-things-done-with-serviceowners/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T18:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take CODEOWNERS and GitHub teams to the next level. Learn about how GitHub engineering solves the age old problem of who owns what.
The post How we organize and get things done with SERVICEOWNERS appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Beizer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unlocking Trust in AI: The Ethical Hacker's Approach to AI Red Teaming]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/ai/ethical-hackers-ai-red-teaming</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/ai/ethical-hackers-ai-red-teaming"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T17:15:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne offers robust AI Red Teaming services that help organizations bolster the security, fairness, and reliability of their AI deployments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ilona Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From migration tools to updates to Enterprise Managed Users, what’s new in GitHub Enterprise]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75778</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-19-from-migration-tools-to-updates-to-enterprise-managed-users-whats-new-in-github-enterprise/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T17:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read a round-up of the exciting, new innovation coming from GitHub Enterprise.
The post From migration tools to updates to Enterprise Managed Users, what’s new in GitHub Enterprise appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Van Ly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · End of 2023 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75615</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-19-release-radar-dec-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T16:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hacktoberfest has wrapped up, GitHub Universe has come to a close, and our community has been super hard at work. All the while people enjoyed turkey over Thanksgiving in the United States and Canada and expressed gratitude for those around them. In this edition, we’d like to thank the open source community for all the […]
The post Release Radar · End of 2023 Edition appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 75: The code, prose & conversations that shaped 2023]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2290</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/75"/>
        <updated>2023-12-18T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This episodes diverges from our traditional fare. I’ve reviewed the 50 previous editions and picked (IMHO) the coolest code, best prose & my favorite podcast episode from each month!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 25: #define: game theory, dude]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2289</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/25"/>
        <updated>2023-12-17T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What happens when you take four grizzled #define veterans and throw an Emma Bostian into the mix? Find out on this episode because our award-worthy game of fake definitions is back and this time it’s even better!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 17 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

Socket – Secure your supply chain and ship with confidence. Install the GitHub app, book a demo or learn more

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Lars Wikman – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Taylor Troesh – GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Emma Bostian – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website

Show Notes:

Join Changelog++ for bonus rounds!
I hereby pardon all junior engineers
wigwam.directory
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The data platform cluster operator service for Hadoop cluster management]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/the-data-platform-cluster-operator-service-for-hadoop-cluster-management</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/the-data-platform-cluster-operator-service-for-hadoop-cluster-management"/>
        <updated>2023-12-17T12:02:44.013Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As any team and its infrastructure grows, the risk of an unplanned service outage and potential data loss will grow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Twitter uses rasdaemon for hardware reliability]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability"/>
        <updated>2023-12-17T12:02:43.999Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 570: ANTHOLOGY — The technical bits]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2274</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/570"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re taking you to the hallway track of All Things Open 2023 in Raleigh, NC. Today’s episode features: Heikki Linnakangas (Co-founder of Neon and Postgre hacker), Robert Aboukhalil (Bioinformatics software engineer) working on bringing desktop apps to the web with WASM, and Scott Ford who loves taking a codebase from brown to green at Corgibytes.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 12 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

Sentry – Get $100 towards your error monitoring with Sentry! Use the code changelog.

Socket – Secure your supply chain and ship with confidence. Install the GitHub app, book a demo or learn more

Typesense – Lightning fast, globally distributed Search-as-a-Service that runs in memory. You literally can’t get any faster!


Featuring:

Heikki Linnakangas – GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Robert Aboukhalil – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Scott Ford – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

Neon
Sandbox.bio
Corgibytes
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NixOS has one fatal flaw]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/posts/2622</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/posts/nixos-fatal-flaw"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T17:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jerod’s Note: The short embedded below of Tammer Saleh on Ship It! created a firestorm of comments from folks who were unsatisfied with the lack of explanation behind his conclusion.

  
I caught up with Tammer at KubeCon NA 2023 and took the opportunity to ask him to clarify and defend the comment. This post is a fancied-up transcript of his response.
It’s better in audio where I read him some comments & we all have a good laugh. Play the audio.
NixOS has one fatal flaw, which is the usability of Nix.
(By the way, I really do love the passion in the Nix community. They created that, right? They created those comments. But Nix does have that fatal flaw of a really horrible learning curve  and user experience.)
I’ve never talked to a single Nix advocate… for example, some of the people insi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammer Saleh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2023 Ambassador World Cup Final: Results, Impact, and Looking Ahead]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/lhe/awc-finals-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/lhe/awc-finals-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T19:12:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The final round of the 2023 Ambassador World Cup was an immense success.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ariel Garcia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our First Netflix Data Engineering Summit]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/f326b0589102</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/our-first-netflix-data-engineering-summit-f326b0589102?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T16:54:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Holden Karau Elizabeth Stone Pedro Duarte Chris Stephens Pallavi Phadnis Lee Woodridge Mark Cho Guil Pires Sujay Jain Tristan Reid…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling vulnerability management across thousands of services and more than 150 million findings]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75802</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-14-scaling-vulnerability-management-across-thousands-of-services-and-more-than-150-million-findings/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T14:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about how we run a scalable vulnerability management program built on top of GitHub. 
The post Scaling vulnerability management across thousands of services and more than 150 million findings appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephan Miehe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: November 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75821</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-13-github-availability-report-november-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T20:48:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In November, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services. 
The post GitHub Availability Report: November 2023 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Your Bug Bounty Budget Efficiently]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/bug-bounty-budget-efficiency</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/bug-bounty-budget-efficiency"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T17:51:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Organizations of all sizes and budgets experience some of the same challenges when managing their bug bounty budgets.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Crystal Hazen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing our home labs: Frigate code review]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75762</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-13-securing-our-home-labs-frigate-code-review/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T17:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post describes two linked vulnerabilities found in Frigate, an AI-powered security camera manager, that could have enabled an attacker to silently gain remote code execution.
The post Securing our home labs: Frigate code review appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Logan MacLaren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Default setup now includes scheduled scans and supports all languages covered by CodeQL]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75769</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-13-default-setup-now-includes-scheduled-scans-and-supports-all-languages-covered-by-codeql/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T16:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve added new improvements to default setup, including automatically scheduling scans on repositories and support for all CodeQL covered languages.
The post Default setup now includes scheduled scans and supports all languages covered by CodeQL appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Walker Chabbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s time for developers and enterprises to build with Gemini Pro]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/gemini-api-developers-cloud/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/gemini-api-developers-cloud/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gemini Pro is now available for developers and enterprises to build AI applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gemini API and more new AI tools for developers and enterprises]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-gemini-pro-imagen-duet-ai-update/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-gemini-pro-imagen-duet-ai-update/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Launching Gemini Pro via the Gemini API and four more AI tools: Imagen 2, MedLM, and Duet AI for Developers and Duet AI in Security Operations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making it harder to do wrong]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=23562</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/12/13/making-it-harder-to-do-wrong/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T09:01:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know I spend all my days working on curl and related matters. I also spend a lot of time thinking on the project; like how we do things and how we should do things. The security angle of this project is one of the most crucial ones and an area where I spend a … Continue reading Making it harder to do wrong →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 298: What's new in Go's cryptography libraries: Part 2]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/2251</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/298"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T21:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Filippo Valsorda & Roland Shoemaker from the Go Team return & bring Nicola Murino with them to continue catching us up on what’s new in Go’s crypto libraries.
This is everything we didn’t cover + deep dives from Part 1!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Filippo Valsorda – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, Website
Roland Shoemaker – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Nicola Murino – GitHub
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

What’s new in Go’s cryptography libraries: Part 1
NIST
FIPS
Diffie–Hellman key exchange
FIPS standard 140
github.com/quic-go/quic-go
tip.golang.org/src/crypto/tls/quic.go
pkg.go.dev/crypto/x509
MultiAlgorithmSigner
OpenSSH format keys
Kerberos edge case, use the correct token from the client
defer channel window adjustment
Improved test cases (removed t.Fatal calls from goroutines), added test against SSH CLI
Agent compatibility
github.com/drakkan/sftpgo
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 249: The state of open source AI]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2287</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/249"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new open source AI book from PremAI starts with “As a data scientist/ML engineer/developer with a 9 to 5 job, it’s difficult to keep track of all the innovations.” We couldn’t agree more, and we are so happy that this week’s guest Casper (among other contributors) have created this resource for practitioners.
During the episode, we cover the key categories to think about as you try to navigate the open source AI ecosystem, and Casper gives his thoughts on fine-tuning, vector DBs & more.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Casper da Costa-Luis – GitHub
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:
State of Open Source AI Book - 2023 Edition
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Career Growth: Insights from Tiffany Jones, VP of Go to Market Operations and Strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/culture-and-talent/career-growth-insights-tiffany-jones-vp-go-market-operations-and-strategy</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/culture-and-talent/career-growth-insights-tiffany-jones-vp-go-market-operations-and-strategy"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T17:46:12.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Debbie Cotton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardening cellular basebands in Android]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/12/hardening-cellular-basebands-in-android.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/12/hardening-cellular-basebands-in-android.html"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Ivan Lozano and Roger Piqueras Jover


Android’s defense-in-depth strategy applies not only to the Android OS running on the Application Processor (AP) but also the firmware that runs on devices. We particularly prioritize hardening the cellular baseband given its unique combination of running in an elevated privilege and parsing untrusted inputs that are remotely delivered into the device.


This post covers how to use two high-value sanitizers which can prevent specific classes of vulnerabilities found within the baseband. They are architecture agnostic, suitable for bare-metal deployment, and should be enabled in existing C/C++ code bases to mitigate unknown vulnerabilities. Beyond security, addressing the issues uncovered by these sanitizers improves code health and overall s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Puppeteer Support for the Cross-Browser WebDriver BiDi Standard]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48070</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2023/12/puppeteer-webdriver-bidi/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T16:14:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Puppeteer now supports the next-generation, cross-browser WebDriver BiDi standard. This new protocol makes it easy for web developers to write automated tests that work across multiple browser engines.
The post Puppeteer Support for the Cross-Browser WebDriver BiDi Standard appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpret the 2023 GigaOm PTaaS Radar Report with HackerOne]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/penetration-testing/hackerone-named-leader-penetration-testing-service-ptaas-gigaom-radar-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/penetration-testing/hackerone-named-leader-penetration-testing-service-ptaas-gigaom-radar-report"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne has been named a "Leader" and a "Fast Mover" in the 2023 GigaOm PTaaS Radar Report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Naz Bozdemir</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 74: Open source LLMs are catching up]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2286</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/74"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group of researchers set out to test claims that its open source rivals had achieved parity (or even better) with ChatGPT on certain tasks, Richard Hipp and his team have rewritten SQLite’s text-based JSON functions, Ratatui is a Rust crate for cooking up TUIs, Morris Brodersen built a complex app in vanilla JS as a case study & Headscale is Kristoffer Dalby’s open source, self-hosted implementation of the Tailscale control server.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Socket – Secure your supply chain and ship with confidence. Install the GitHub app, book a demo or learn more


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Do You Know Ethical Hackers Can Be Trusted?]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/clear-and-gateway</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/clear-and-gateway"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T17:34:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne has rolled out new updates that make our human-powered security program the most trusted in the industry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michiel Prins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 24: HATEOAS corpus]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2283</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/24"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jerod is back with another “It Depends” episode! This time he’s joined by Kris Brandow from Go Time and they’re talking all things API design. What makes a good API? Is GraphQL a solid choice? Why do we do REST wrong? And WTF does HATEOAS mean, anyway?
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 10 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

Sentry – Get $100 towards your error monitoring with Sentry! Use the code changelog.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

PHP: a fractal of bad design
PostGraphile Instant GraphQL API
HATEOAS
The Tech Behind the New Grooveshark
OpenAPI Spec
HTTP Specifications
Roy Fielding Dissertation on REST
Mike Amundsen
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NotebookLM adds more than a dozen new features]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/notebooklm-new-features-availability/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/notebooklm-new-features-availability/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now available in the U.S., NotebookLM has new features to help you easily read, take notes and organize your writing projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading GitHub.com to MySQL 8.0]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75736</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-07-upgrading-github-com-to-mysql-8-0/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T22:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub uses MySQL to store vast amounts of relational data. This is the story of how we seamlessly upgraded our production fleet to MySQL 8.0.
The post Upgrading GitHub.com to MySQL 8.0 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiaqi Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 Live Hacking Events]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/lhe/2024-lhe-invitations</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/lhe/2024-lhe-invitations"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T21:06:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2024 HackerOne Live Hacking Events are here and better than ever!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From macOS runners to secure deployments, what’s new from GitHub Actions]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75749</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-07-from-macos-runners-to-secure-deployments-whats-new-from-github-actions/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T21:01:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read a roundup of the exciting, new innovation coming from GitHub Actions.
The post From macOS runners to secure deployments, what’s new from GitHub Actions appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Siemens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 304: From WebGL to WebGPU]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2202</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/304"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T17:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gregg Tavares (author of WebGL/WebGPU Fundamentals) joins Jerod & Amal to give us a tour of these low-level technologies that are pushing the web forward into the world of video games, machine learning & other exciting rich applications.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 16 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Socket – Secure your supply chain and ship with confidence. Install the GitHub app, book a demo or learn more

React Jam – React Jam is an online event where React developers come together to create games in 10 days. Let’s do this!

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Gregg Tavares – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub

Show Notes:

WebGL Fundamentals
WebGPU Fundamentals
WebGPU - Wikipedia
“webgpu” | Can I use…
Download the latest indie games - itch.io
PlayCanvas WebGL Game Engine
PICO-8 Fantasy Console
Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow: A Novel
Changelog++
Zelda, Tears of the Kingdom - Disappointing
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Innovation Graph Q2 2023 Data Release]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75729</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-07-github-innovation-graph-q2-2023-data-release/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T16:37:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover the latest trends and insights on public software development activity on GitHub with the release of Q2 2023 data for the Innovation Graph.
The post GitHub Innovation Graph Q2 2023 Data Release appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter’s Blobstore Hardware Lifecycle Monitoring and Reporting Service]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/twitters-blobstore-hardware-lifecycle-monitoring-and-reporting-service</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/twitters-blobstore-hardware-lifecycle-monitoring-and-reporting-service"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T12:03:00.445Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraint Management for cluster operation safety and reliability at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/constraint-management-for-cluster-operation-safety-and-reliability-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/constraint-management-for-cluster-operation-safety-and-reliability-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T12:03:00.429Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As any team and its infrastructure grows, the risk of an unplanned service outage and potential data loss will grow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring the impact of Twitter network latency with CausalImpact]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T12:03:00.423Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share how we adopted the CausalImpact package from Google on a Twitter edge network experiment to measure the impact of improving Twitter's latency on customer engagement and revenue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we scaled Reads On the Twitter Users Database]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-we-scaled-reads-on-the-twitter-users-database</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-we-scaled-reads-on-the-twitter-users-database"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T12:03:00.413Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kerberizing Hadoop Clusters at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/kerberizing-hadoop-clusters-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/kerberizing-hadoop-clusters-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T12:03:00.406Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter's Recommendation Algorithm]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2023/twitter-recommendation-algorithm</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2023/twitter-recommendation-algorithm"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T12:03:00.386Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter aims to deliver you the best of what’s happening in the world right now. This blog is an introduction to how the algorithm selects Tweets for your timeline.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 569: Hare aims to be a 100 year language]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2273</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/569"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on The Changelog we’re joined by Drew DeVault, talking about the Hare programming language. From the website, Hare is a systems programming language designed to be simple, stable, and robust. When we asked Drew why he credted it, he said “[because] I wanted it to exist, and it did not exist.” Wise words.
Hare aims to be a 100 year language (which we get into on the show), why he’s so possionate about all things open source, the state of the language, fostering a culture that values stability, and oddly enough — what it takes to make a peanut butter and jelly sandwhich.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 10 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

Sentry – On Thursday, December 14th Sentry is doing a FREE web browser performance webinar. Sign up and bring your questions! There will be a Q&A at the end of the stream. ✌️

.Tech Domains – They’re giving selected startups guest spots on the biggest podcasts, conferences, and billboards in the tech game. Apply at startups.tech/changelog

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Drew DeVault – GitHub, Website
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

sourcehut - the hacker’s forge!
The Hare programming language
Himitsu
SourceHut’s 2022 Financial report
Can I be on your podcast
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cueing up a calculator: an introduction to exploit development on Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75690</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-06-cueing-up-a-calculator-an-introduction-to-exploit-development-on-linux/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T17:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using CVE-2023-43641 as an example, I’ll explain how to develop an exploit for a memory corruption vulnerability on Linux. The exploit has to bypass several mitigations to achieve code execution.
The post Cueing up a calculator: an introduction to exploit development on Linux appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Backhouse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re experimenting with LLMs to evolve GitHub Copilot]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75682</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-06-how-were-experimenting-with-llms-to-evolve-github-copilot/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T16:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how we’re experimenting with generative AI models to extend GitHub Copilot across the developer lifecycle.
The post How we’re experimenting with LLMs to evolve GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sara Verdi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn more about Gemini, our most capable AI model]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/gemini-collection/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/gemini-collection/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore our collection to find out more about Gemini, the most capable and general model we’ve ever built.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Gemini: our largest and most capable AI model]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-gemini-ai/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-gemini-ai/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gemini is our most capable and general model, built to be multimodal and optimized for three different sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bard gets its biggest upgrade yet with Gemini]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/bard/google-bard-try-gemini-ai/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/bard/google-bard-try-gemini-ai/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re starting to bring Gemini’s advanced capabilities into Bard.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel 8 Pro — the first smartphone with AI built in — is now running Gemini Nano, plus more AI updates coming to the Pixel portfolio]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/pixel/pixel-feature-drop-december-2023/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/pixel/pixel-feature-drop-december-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Feature Drop brings updates to your Pixel hardware. Plus, Gemini Nano now powers on-device generative AI features for Pixel 8 Pro.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Quality Automation at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T12:02:57.215Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we share how Twitter implemented a Data Quality Platform that gave customers the ability to have automated data quality checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl 8.5.0]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=23543</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/12/06/curl-8-5-0/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T07:25:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Release presentation Today, December 6 at 09:00 UTC (10:00 CET), I will live-stream the curl 8.5.0 release presentation over at Twitch. After the fact, the release video will be made available on YouTube. Numbers the 253rd release2 changes56 days (total: 9,392)188 bug-fixes (total: 9,734)266 commits (total: 31,427)0 new public libcurl function (total: 93)0 new curl_easy_setopt() … Continue reading curl 8.5.0 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Enterprise Server 3.11 is now generally available]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75650</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-05-github-enterprise-server-3-11-is-now-generally-available/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T23:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Customers using GitHub Enterprise Server can gain more insight and understanding into the security of their code.
The post GitHub Enterprise Server 3.11 is now generally available appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Jarzebowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Addressing post-quantum cryptography with CodeQL]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75655</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-05-addressing-post-quantum-cryptography-with-codeql/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T22:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how researchers and security experts at GitHub, Microsoft, and Santander came together to address the challenges presented by the post-quantum cryptography world.  
The post Addressing post-quantum cryptography with CodeQL appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Walker Chabbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 248: Suspicion machines ⚙️]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2282</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/248"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T21:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this enlightening episode, we delve deeper than the usual buzz surrounding AI’s perils, focusing instead on the tangible problems emerging from the use of machine learning algorithms across Europe. We explore “suspicion machines” — systems that assign scores to welfare program participants, estimating their likelihood of committing fraud. Join us as Justin and Gabriel share insights from their thorough investigation, which involved gaining access to one of these models and meticulously analyzing its behavior.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Gabriel Geiger – Twitter
Justin-Casimir Braun – Twitter
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Article - “Inside the suspicion machine”
The methodology behind Justin and Gabriel’s report
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintaining the Intelligence Edge in Cybersecurity]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/ceo/maintaining-intelligence-edge-cybersecurity</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/ceo/maintaining-intelligence-edge-cybersecurity"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T18:19:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A message from HackerOne's CEO about the power of both artificial and human intelligence.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marten Mickos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exceptional Exception Handling]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/12/exceptional-exception-handling.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/12/exceptional-exception-handling.html"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T13:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@media only screen and (max-width: 600px) {
  .body {
    overflow-x: auto;
  }
}



This is another post in our Code Health series. A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office.


by Yiming Sun


Have you ever seen huge exception-handling blocks? Here is an example. Let's assume we are calling bakePizza() to bake a pizza, and it can be overbaked, throwing a PizzaOverbakedException.




class PizzaOverbakedException extends Exception {};


void bakePizza () throws PizzaOverbakedException {};


try {
  // 100+ lines of code to prepare pizza ingredients.
  ...
  bakePizza();
  // Another 100+ lines of code to deliver pizza to a customer.
  ...
} catch (Exception e) {
  throw new IllegalStateException(); // Root cause ignored while throwing new exception.
}



Here are the problems with the above code:

Obscuring the logic. The method bakePizza(), is obscured by the additional lines of code of preparation and delivery, so unintended exceptions from preparation and delivery may be caught.
Catching the general exception. catch (Exception e) will catch everything, despite that we might only want to handle PizzaOverbakedException here.
Rethrowing a general exception, with the original exception ignored. This means that the root cause is lost - we don't know what exactly goes wrong with pizza baking while debugging.

Here is a better alternative, rewritten to avoid the problems above.



class PizzaOverbakedException extends Exception {};

void bakePizza () throws PizzaOverbakedException {};

// 100+ lines of code to prepare pizza ingredients.
...
try {
  bakePizza();
} catch (PizzaOverbakedException e) {  // Other exceptions won’t be caught.
  // Rethrow a more meaningful exception; so that we know pizza is overbaked.
  throw new IllegalStateException(“You burned the pizza!”, e);  
}
// Another 100+ lines of code to deliver pizza to a customer.
...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 73: Leaked GPT prompts & Firefox on the brink]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2281</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/73"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T21:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT’s new GPTs feature leak their prompts, Firefox’s share of the browser market will soon drop below 2%, Robin Berjon tries to formalize a name for those who can’t be named, Amy Lai tells the tale of the weirdest bug she’s ever seen & Facundo Olano trumps the “code is read more than written” cliche with his own: “code is run more than read.”
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Sentry – On Thursday, December 14th Sentry is doing a FREE web browser performance webinar. Sign up and bring your questions! There will be a Q&A at the end of the stream. ✌️


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hack My Career: Meet Kayla Underkoffler]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/culture-and-talent/hack-my-career-meet-kayla-underkoffler</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/culture-and-talent/hack-my-career-meet-kayla-underkoffler"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T17:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne's Kayla Underkoffler shares her career journey and how she arrived at her current role.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Briones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The ultimate gifts for the developer in your life this holiday season]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75633</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-12-04-the-ultimate-gifts-for-the-developer-in-your-life-this-holiday-season/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T16:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're on the hunt for the perfect holiday gifts for the developer who has it all, look no further. We’ve curated a list of 10 must-have items (plus a few more) that strike the perfect balance between practicality and style.
The post The ultimate gifts for the developer in your life this holiday season appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lavinia Sfetcu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog & Friends 23: The state of the 2023 tech market]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/17/2280</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/friends/23"/>
        <updated>2023-12-01T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gergely Orosz is back for our annual year-end update on the tech market, writ large. How is hiring? Has AI really changed the game? What about that OpenAI fiasco?
We also talk in-depth about Gergely’s self-published book, The Software Engineer’s Guidebook, which has been four years in the making.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 19 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

Socket – Secure your supply chain and ship with confidence. Install the GitHub app, book a demo or learn more

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Gergely Orosz – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website

Show Notes:

The Pragmatic Engineer Newsletter
The Software Engineer’s Guidebook
Anthropic
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nubank launches reward program for ethical hackers in partnership with BugCrowd]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=17727</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/nubank-launches-reward-program-for-ethical-hackers/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-01T13:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Bug Bounty program rewards cybersecurity researchers who find potential vulnerabilities in our systems.
The post Nubank launches reward program for ethical hackers in partnership with BugCrowd appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 568: Gleaming the KubeCon]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2272</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/568"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re gleaming the KubeCon. Ok, some people say CubeCon, while others say KubeCon…we talk with Solomon Hykes about all things Dagger, Tammer Saleh and James McShane about going beyond cloud native with SuperOrbital, and Steve Francis and Spencer Smith about the state of Talos Linux and what they’re working on at Sidero Labs.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 12 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

.Tech Domains – They’re giving selected startups guest spots on the biggest podcasts, conferences, and billboards in the tech game. Apply at startups.tech/changelog

Traceroute – Listen and follow Season 3 of Traceroute starting November 2 on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts!

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Tammer Saleh – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
James McShane – Twitter, GitHub
Steve Francis – GitHub, LinkedIn
Spencer Smith – GitHub, LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Gerhard Lazu – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

SOTL 2023
dagger.io
SuperOrbital
Talos Linux
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 303: Art of the state machine]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2234</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/303"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amal, Nick & special guest Laura Kalbeg geek out over the remarkable growth and evolution of the XState project and its team in recent years. Laura also tells everyone about Stately.ai, a SaaS platform that uses AI to create seamless state management solutions compatible with various tools like XState, Redux & zustand.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 6 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Changelog News – A podcast+newsletter combo that’s brief, entertaining & always on-point. Subscribe today.

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Laura Kalbag – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

XState JS Party debut w/ David “Piano” - X’ gon State it to ya (#191)
Stately
XState
Jump straight into the Stately editor - via state.new (fancy!)
Laura’s talk where she demoed state machines and the outputted state machine
All the public machines that folks have made using Stately (must be logged in)
An intro to state machines and statecharts (with puppies!)
Laura’s awesome book via Book Apart - Accessibility for Everyone
NodeConf EU
NodeConf EU talks from 2023 (workshops were live only)
The amazing NodeConf EU venue we were ooo’ing and aaah’ing about 😍
Laura’s NodeConf Talk
Accessibility for Everyone
Migrate to XState 5
Actor Model
Model-based testing
Playwright
Stately Discord
Redux Toolkit
zustand
And here’s the state chart for the JS Danger game!


Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Developer Edition and Beta: Try out Mozilla’s .deb package!]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48067</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2023/11/firefox-developer-edition-and-beta-try-out-mozillas-deb-package/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T19:55:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A month ago, we introduced our Nightly package for Debian-based Linux distributions. Today, we are proud to announce we made our .deb package available for Developer Edition and Beta!
The post Firefox Developer Edition and Beta: Try out Mozilla’s .deb package! appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Johan Lorenzo (Mozilla)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Members of Fort Peck Tribes and Googlers meet to learn, celebrate and support socially beneficial technology]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-fort-peck-tribes/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-fort-peck-tribes/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A team of Googlers focused on responsible innovation visited the Fort Peck Tribes in Montana to engage in relationship-building and bidirectional learning.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the pages of our Insider newsletter: How to use GitHub Copilot]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75582</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-11-30-from-the-pages-of-our-insider-newsletter-how-to-use-github-copilot/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T17:35:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore July 2023’s Insider newsletter, featuring prompts, tips, and use cases for GitHub Copilot. 
The post From the pages of our Insider newsletter: How to use GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sara Verdi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing our home labs: Home Assistant code review]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75549</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-11-30-securing-our-home-labs-home-assistant-code-review/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T13:52:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Security Lab examined the most popular open source software running on our home labs, with the aim of enhancing its security. Here's what we found and what you can do to better protect your own smart home.
The post Securing our home labs: Home Assistant code review appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alvaro Munoz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[xCurl]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=23546</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/11/30/xcurl/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T07:58:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is often said that Imitation is the Sincerest Form of Flattery. Also, remember libcrurl? That was the name of the thing Google once planned to do: reimplement the libcurl API on top of their Chrome networking library. Flattery or not, it never went anywhere. The other day I received an email asking me about … Continue reading xCurl →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All of Netflix’s HDR video streaming is now dynamically optimized]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/e9e0cb15f2ba</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/all-of-netflixs-hdr-video-streaming-is-now-dynamically-optimized-e9e0cb15f2ba?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T21:26:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[by  Aditya Mavlankar, Zhi Li, Lukáš Krasula and Christos Bampis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing llamafile]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=48061</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2023/11/introducing-llamafile/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T18:46:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're thrilled to announce the first release of llamafile, inviting the open source community to join this groundbreaking project. 
With llamafile, you can effortlessly convert large language model (LLM) weights into executables. Imagine transforming a 4GB file of LLM weights into a binary that runs smoothly on six different operating systems, without requiring installation. 
The post Introducing llamafile appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Hood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 247: The OpenAI debacle (a retrospective)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2279</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/247"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel & Chris conduct a retrospective analysis of the recent OpenAI debacle in which CEO Sam Altman was sacked by the OpenAI board, only to return days later with a new supportive board.  The events and people involved are discussed from start to finish along with the potential impact of these events on the AI industry.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 3 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Traceroute – Listen and follow Season 3 of Traceroute starting November 2 on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts!

Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

OpenAI | Wikipedia
How OpenAI’s origins explain the Sam Altman drama
OpenAI chaos: A timeline of firings, interim CEOs, re-hirings and other twists
OpenAI researchers warned board of AI breakthrough ahead of CEO ouster, sources say
Everyone’s talking about OpenAI’s Q*. Here’s what you need to know about the mysterious project.
It is Time to Profit off of the OpenAI Drama
Yann LeCun | LinkedIn
Advent of GenAI Hackathon
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving Text Classification Resilience and Efficiency with RETVec]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2023/11/improving-text-classification.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2023/11/improving-text-classification.html"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elie Bursztein, Cybersecurity & AI Research Director, and Marina Zhang, Software Engineer




Systems such as Gmail, YouTube and Google Play rely on text classification models to identify harmful content including phishing attacks, inappropriate comments, and scams. These types of texts are harder for machine learning models to classify because bad actors rely on adversarial text manipulations to actively attempt to evade the classifiers. For example, they will use homoglyphs, invisible characters, and keyword stuffing to bypass defenses. 





To help make text classifiers more robust and efficient, we’ve developed a novel, multilingual text vectorizer called RETVec (Resilient & Efficient Text Vectorizer) that helps models achieve state-of-the-art classification performance and drasticall…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A conversation with Refik Anadol on creativity and AI]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/artist-refik-anadol-ai-creativity-google/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/artist-refik-anadol-ai-creativity-google/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mira Lane explores how AI is empowering creativity with pioneering artist Refik Anadol.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mercado Libre’s Journey to a Public Bug Bounty Program]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/customer-stories/mercado-libre-public-bug-bounty</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/customer-stories/mercado-libre-public-bug-bounty"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T17:21:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne is delighted to announce the launch of Mercado Libre’s Public Bug Bounty Program.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clean Up Code Cruft]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/11/clean-up-code-cruft.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2023/11/clean-up-code-cruft.html"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is another post in our Code Health series. A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office.


By Per Jacobsson

The book Clean Code discusses a camping rule that is good to keep in the back of your mind when writing code:



Leave the campground cleaner than you found it



So how does that fit into software development? The thinking is this: When you make changes to code that can potentially be improved, try to make it just a little bit better.
This doesn't necessarily mean you have to go out of your way to do huge refactorings. Changing something small can go a long way:

Rename a variable to something more descriptive. 

Break apart a huge functi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix Original Research: MIT CODE 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/9340b879176a</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/netflix-original-research-mit-code-2023-9340b879176a?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T20:59:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix was thrilled to be the premier sponsor for the 2nd year in a row at the 2023 Conference on Digital Experimentation (CODE@MIT).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hammock’s third episode: journeys in code, Clojure, Datomic, and personal growth]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=21532</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/the-hammocks-third-episode-journeys-in-code-clojure-datomic-and-personal-growth/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T20:13:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A deep dive into Episode 3 of ‘The Hammock’ podcast with Enzzo Cavallo: from the dynamics of Clojure to the intricacies of Datomic and beyond
The post The Hammock’s third episode: journeys in code, Clojure, Datomic, and personal growth appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News 72: Was Jamstack a zero interest rate phenomenon?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/16/2278</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/news/72"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zach Leatherman on the tension and future of the Jamstack community, Chenxin Li helps you avoid 13 bad practices in data visualization, Laravel Pulse is coming real soon, Max Chernyak develops a new way to accomplish long term refactors & Spencer Baugh makes the case for more libraries and less services in our software stacks.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Changelog Sponsorships – Podcast + newsletter sponsorships are an excellent way to bring awareness to your company and the awesome work you’re doing. And who better to partner with? Our audience is brimming with forward-looking, influential, smart people. Learn more here. We’d love to work with you!


Featuring:

Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:
All links mentioned in this episode of Changelog News (and more) are in its companion newsletter.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“you have hacked into my devices”]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=23397</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/11/26/you-have-hacked-into-my-devices/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-26T13:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve shown you email examples many times before. Today I received this. I don’t know this person. Clearly a troubled individual. I suspect she found my name and address somewhere and then managed to put me somewhere in the middle of the conspiracy against her. The entire mail is written in a single paragraph and … Continue reading “you have hacked into my devices” →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Causal Machine Learning for Creative Insights]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/4b0ce22a8a96</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/causal-machine-learning-for-creative-insights-4b0ce22a8a96?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-11-25T01:27:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A framework to identify the causal impact of successful visual components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 302: What's new in CSS land]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/2225</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/302"/>
        <updated>2023-11-24T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una Kravets, developer advocate at Google & web platform ambassador, joins Amal & Nick to take them CSS to school as they start this podcast in CSS kindergarten and end it with a Level-Up CSS Diploma. (LUCD?)
We explore all the amazing features which have recently landed in CSS — enabling super-charged user experiences with no JavaScript. Don’t forgot to check out all the epic links & demos in the show notes — and hold on to your butts, kids, this one is a ride!
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Interviews 567: Bringing Dev Mode to Figma]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/2244</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/567"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T16:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on we’re joined by Emil Sjölander from Figma — talking about bringing Dev Mode to Figma. Dev Mode is their new workspace in Figma that’s designed to bring developers and design to the same tool.
The question they’re trying to answer is “How do you create a home for developers in a design tool?” We go way back to Emil’s startup that was acquired by Figma called Visly, how we iterated to here from 20 years ago (think PSD > HTML days), what they did to build Dev Mode, what they’re doing around codegen, the popularity of design systems, and what it takes to go from zero to Dev Mode.
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members get a bonus 5 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Neon – The fully managed serverless Postgres with a generous free tier. We separate storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage.

Socket – Secure your supply chain and ship with confidence. Install the GitHub app, book a demo or learn more

Traceroute – Listen and follow Season 3 of Traceroute starting November 2 on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts!

Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.


Featuring:

Emil Sjölander – Twitter, GitHub
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn

Show Notes:

Dev Mode: Building a design tool that works harder for developers
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and scalability for search]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T12:02:57.808Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we power real-time search for Tweets, Users, Direct Messages and more using Elasticsearch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 246: Generating product imagery at Shopify]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/2267</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/246"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shopify recently released a Hugging Face space demonstrating very impressive results for replacing background scenes in product imagery. In this episode, we hear the backstory technical details about this work from Shopify’s Russ Maschmeyer. Along the way we discuss how to come up with clever AI solutions (without training your own model).
Leave us a comment
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors:

  
Advent of GenAI Hackathon – Join us for a 7-day journey into the world of Generative AI with the Advent of GenAI Hackathon. Learn more here!

Traceroute – Listen and follow Season 3 of Traceroute starting November 2 on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts!


Featuring:

Russ Maschmeyer – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website

Show Notes:

Advent of GenAI Hackathon
Shopify’s HF Space for background replacement
Shopify Magic
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inaugural Glass Firewall Conference Invites Women to Learn About Cybersecurity]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/community/glass-firewall-conference</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/community/glass-firewall-conference"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T17:31:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The inaugural Glass Firewall Conference: Breaking Bytes and Barriers was sponsored by Capital One, GitHub, and HackerOne.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Debbie Cotton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Good First Issue: Introducing a new way to contribute]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=75489</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-11-21-for-good-first-issue-introducing-a-new-way-to-contribute/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T17:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For Good First Issue is a curated list of open source projects that are also digital public goods and need the help of developers.
The post For Good First Issue: Introducing a new way to contribute appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sidney Espinosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[URL parser performance]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=23435</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/11/21/url-parser-performance/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T11:58:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[URLs is a dear subject of mine on this blog, as readers might have noticed. “URL” is this mythical concept of a string that identifies a resource online and yet there is no established standard for its syntax. There are instead multiple ones out of which one is on purpose “moving” so it never actually … Continue reading URL parser performance →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Processing using Netflix Maestro and Apache Iceberg]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/b8ba072ddeeb</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/incremental-processing-using-netflix-maestro-and-apache-iceberg-b8ba072ddeeb?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T05:49:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[by Jun He, Yingyi Zhang, and Pawan Dixit]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>