<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-05-25T12:22:36.218Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model-based candidate generation for account recommendations]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/model-based-candidate-generation-for-account-recommendations</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/model-based-candidate-generation-for-account-recommendations"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T12:22:20.025Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we share how we improved account recommendations with a model-based candidate generation framework.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Investing in privacy enhancing tech to advance transparency in ML]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/investing-in-privacy-enhancing-tech-to-advance-transparency-in-ML</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/investing-in-privacy-enhancing-tech-to-advance-transparency-in-ML"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T12:22:20.008Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re investing in privacy-enhancing technologies (PET) to pioneer new methods of public accountability and access to data in a manner that respects and protects the privacy of people on Twitter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Ways I Provide Value as a PullRequest Reviewer When I Start Reviewing a New Project]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/application-security/5-ways-i-provide-value-pullrequest-reviewer-when-i-start-reviewing-new-project</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/application-security/5-ways-i-provide-value-pullrequest-reviewer-when-i-start-reviewing-new-project"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Important reviewer traits for providing a great code review include prior knowledge and experience, expertise, background context, attention to detail, and written communication skills. As a reviewer on PullRequest, I need to quickly gain context when I’m reviewing a project for the first time. But as is the case for any engineer new to a team, some context is gained over time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>William Barrett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved REST API documentation]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65096</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-24-improved-rest-api-documentation/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T16:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to announce some big improvements to our REST API documentation. We know developers rely on this documentation to integrate with GitHub, and we are committed to making it trustworthy, easy to find, and easy to use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachael Sewell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A text-to-image diffusion model with an unprecedented degree of photorealism]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9l5N</id>
        <link href="https://gweb-research-imagen.appspot.com/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T15:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google researchers are giving DALL-E a run for its money:
Our key discovery is that generic large language models (e.g. T5), pretrained on text-only corpora, are surprisingly effective at encoding text for image synthesis: increasing the size of the language model in Imagen boosts both sample fidelity and image-text alignment much more than increasing the size of the image diffusion model.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The original Pong video game had no code]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/aQ11</id>
        <link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EngineeringPorn/comments/ul49zt/the_original_pong_video_game_had_no_code_and_was/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T14:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TIL that Pong was built using hardware circuitry. Fascinating! Here’s the original schematics from Atari 👇

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nubank announces hires to strengthen tech team]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18427</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/nubank-hires-engineers-of-parkside/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T14:10:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The international talents are coming from Parkside Technologies, a North American company that already uses the same functional programming languages
The post Nubank announces hires to strengthen tech team appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Sponsors launches in India]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65180</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-23-github-sponsors-launches-in-india/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T03:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Sponsors is now available to all developers in India – no more waitlist, you can sign up right away!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Lord</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fluent GraphQL library for Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Z3VN</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/mergestat/fluentgraphql"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T21:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This package wraps the graphql-go/graphql implementation to provide a “fluent” pattern for constructing GraphQL queries in Go. This can be valuable in situations where dynamic queries are desired: when the fields of a GraphQL query (or mutation) are not known until runtime. For most other use cases, plain query strings or a helper library such as this should be sufficient.
I wonder if this would change Mislav’s unpopular GraphQL/Go opinion…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we test microservices locally at Nylas]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/N5Ye</id>
        <link href="https://www.nylas.com/blog/how-we-test-microservices-locally-at-nylas/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T20:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing microservice architecture locally is difficult. At Nylas, we’ve created a local development environment using Minikube and Tilt. In this article, I walk you through how we do it.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhi Qu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eight years of the GitHub Security Bug Bounty program]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65156</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-23-eight-years-of-the-github-security-bug-bounty-program/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T17:54:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was another record year for our Security Bug Bounty program. We're excited to highlight some achievements we’ve made together with the bounty community from 2021!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jill Moné-Corallo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl offers repeated transfers at slower pace]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18925</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/23/curl-offers-repeated-transfers-at-slower-pace/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T16:06:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[curl --rate is your new friend. This option is for when you use curl to do many requests in a single command line, but you want curl to not do them as quickly as possible. You want curl to do them no more often than at a certain interval. This is a way to slow … Continue reading curl offers repeated transfers at slower pace →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make resilient web apps with progressive enhancement]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/EQ0R</id>
        <link href="https://austingil.com/resilient-applications-progressive-enhancement/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T14:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ignoring progressive enhancement could be seriously hurting your conversions. This article will show you how to build resiliency into your apps.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The mindless tyranny of 'what if it changes?' as a software design principle]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/GbjA</id>
        <link href="https://chriskiehl.com/article/the-tyranny-of-what-if-it-changes"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T13:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chris Kiehl hits his hammer right on the head of this common sentiment in software circles:
Developers from certain languages [Java] have learned to wield this design principle with more power than many others. It’s how we end up with so much stuff in code bases that’s just… there. Existing. Superficially it appears unused, but silently and stoically, we know it protects us from the turbulent future change which lurks ever ahead.
The antithesis of one of my favorite design principles: YAGNI
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Vélez, CEO of Nubank, joins the TIME100 list of most influential people in the world]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18415</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/david-velez-time-100-most-influential-people/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T12:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The list, published annually and in its 19th edition, recognizes people who are making an impact in the world.
The post David Vélez, CEO of Nubank, joins the TIME100 list of most influential people in the world appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Survey of Causal Inference Applications at Netflix]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/b62d25175e6f</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/a-survey-of-causal-inference-applications-at-netflix-b62d25175e6f?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-05-21T15:02:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Netflix, we want to entertain the world through creating engaging content and helping members discover the titles they will love. Key to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Investors fearful of a possible recession]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/investors-fearful-of-a-possible-recession</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/investors-fearful-of-a-possible-recession"/>
        <updated>2022-05-21T14:16:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new fear in a tough year]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A book-in-progress about the Linux kernel and its insides]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/O27w</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/0xAX/linux-insides"/>
        <updated>2022-05-21T11:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve ever wondered how the Linux kernel does its thing:
The goal is simple - to share my modest knowledge about the insides of the linux kernel and help people who are interested in linux kernel insides, and other low-level subject matter. Feel free to go through the book Start here
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 490: Schneier on security for tomorrow’s software]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1650</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/490"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking with Bruce Schneier — cryptographer, computer security professional, privacy specialist, and writer (of many books). He calls himself a “public-interest technologist”, a term he coined himself, and works at the intersection of security, technology, and people.
Bruce has been writing about security issues on his blog since 2004, his monthly newsletter has been going since 1998, he’s a fellow and lecturer at Harvard’s Kennedy School, a board member of the EFF, and the Chief of Security Architecture at Inrupt. Long story short, Bruce has credentials to back up his opinions and on today’s show we dig into the state of cyber-security, security and privacy best practices, his thoughts on Bitcoin (and other crypto-currencies), Tim Berners-Lee’s Solid project, and of course…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nubank opens applications for the 2nd edition of We Code]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18404</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/nubank-we-code-2nd-edition-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T18:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Applications for the recruitment program of Black people in the software engineering industry are open until May 22nd. Check out how you can join.
The post Nubank opens applications for the 2nd edition of We Code appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 53: Securing K8s releases (KubeCon EU 2022)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1636</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/53"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T17:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are at KubeCon CloudNativeCon EU 2022, talking to Adolfo García Veytia about securing Kubernetes releases. Adolfo is a Staff Software Engineer at Chainguard, and one of the technical leads for SIG release, meaning that he helps ship Kubernetes. You most likely know him as Puerco, and have seen first-hand his passion for securing software via SBOMs, cosign and SLSA. Puerco’s love for bikes and Chainguard are a great match 🚴‍♂️
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
MongoDB – An integrated suite of cloud database and services — They have a FREE forever tier, so you can prove to yourself and to your team that they have everything you need. Check it out today at mongodb.com/changelog

    …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 226: The third year of the third age of JS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1652</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/226"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, Shawn (swyx) Wang wrote:
Every 10 years there is a changing of the guard in JavaScript. I think we have just started a period of accelerated change that could in thge future be regarded as the Third Age of JavaScript.
We’re now in year three of this third age and Swyx joins us to look back at what he missed, look around at what’s happening today, and look forward at what might be coming next.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn continuously about their applications - from t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · April 2022 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65072</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-20-release-radar-apr-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T16:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Each month, we highlight open source projects that have shipped major updates. These include everything from world-changing technology to developer tooling, and weekend projects. Here are our top staff picks on projects that shipped major version releases in April. Flyte 1.0 I was lucky enough to discover Flyte during Hacktoberfest last year. Now, Flyte has […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne Announces a New Customer Pentest Setup that's More Efficient and Speeds Time to Launch]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/assessments/hackerone-announces-new-customer-pentest-setup-thats-more-efficient-and-speeds-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/assessments/hackerone-announces-new-customer-pentest-setup-thats-more-efficient-and-speeds-time"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This improved experience reduces time to launch, which is vital when your organization is up against an urgent timeline to complete a pentest due to a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ryan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action needed by GitHub Connect customers using GHES 3.1 and older to adopt new authentication token format updates]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65110</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-20-action-needed-by-github-connect-customers-using-ghes-3-1-and-older-to-adopt-new-authentication-token-format-updates/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T15:27:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade to GHES 3.2 or newer by June 3rd to continue using GitHub Connect.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Boyle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add motion to your web apps with a single line of code]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/maJP</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/formkit/auto-animate"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AutoAnimate is a zero-config, drop-in animation utility that adds smooth transitions to your web app. You can use it with Vue, React, or any other JavaScript application.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTTP Cats (this is exactly what you hope it's going to be)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/wkgR</id>
        <link href="https://http.cat/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T13:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How can you tell it’s Friday? I’m posting something ridiculous (but cool) to the news feed. These are some high quality cat pics! 302, 403, and  405 are all great… but 414 is the best.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 230: Revisiting Caddy]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1620</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/230"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Holt & Mohammed S. Al Sahaf sit down with Natalie & Jon to discuss every gopher’s favorite open source web server with automatic HTTPS!
In addition to laying out what Caddy is and why it’s interesting, we dive deep into how you can (and why you might want to) extend Caddy as a result of its modular architecture.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Chronosphere – Chronosphere is the observability platform for cloud-native teams operating at scale. When it comes to observability, teams need a reliable, scalable, and efficient solution so they can know about issues well before their customers do. Teams choose Chronosphere to help them move faster than the competition. Learn more and get a d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automate all the boring Kubernetes operations with Python]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/4E6D</id>
        <link href="https://martinheinz.dev/blog/73"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T19:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article we take look at how you can use Python’s Kubernetes Client library to automate all the boring Kubernetes tasks and operations, such as creating/patching resources, watching events, accessing containers and more.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Heinz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SQLite and Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/lbzy</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RqubKSF3wig"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T18:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Crawshaw gave an excellent talk (at Go Northwest in 2018) on using SQLite (so hot right now) together with Go and how enjoyable/productive the combo is. Quite worthy of its ~30 minutes runtime.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the potential of JavaScript-based containers]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/03bZ</id>
        <link href="https://tinyclouds.org/javascript_containers"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T18:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Dahl describes the JavaScript sandbox as a higher level container for server software:
This container isn’t meant to address the same breadth of problems that Linux containers target. Its emergence is a result of its simplicity. It minimizes the boilerplate for web service business logic. It shares concepts with the browser and reduces the concepts that the programmer needs to know.
People like Ryan and his colleagues at Deno are exploring this future, but it’s not quite here yet.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Math support in Markdown]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65023</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-19-math-support-in-markdown/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T17:41:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematical expressions are key to information sharing amongst engineers, scientists, data scientists, and mathematicians. Today we are pleased to announce that math expressions can be rendered in Markdown on GitHub using $$ as a delimiter for code blocks with math content or the $ delimiter for inline math expressions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Woodward</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[case insensitive string comparisons in C]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19143</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/19/case-insensitive-string-comparisons-in-c/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T17:29:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2008, I had a revelation when it dawned on me that the POSIX function called strcasecmp() compares strings case insensitively, but locale dependent. Because of this, “file” and “FILE” is not actually a case insensitive match in Turkish but is a match in most other locales. curl would sometimes fail in mysterious ways … Continue reading case insensitive string comparisons in C →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re continuing to enable all developers to build]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65049</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-19-how-were-continuing-to-enable-all-developers-to-build/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T16:48:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about what GitHub is doing to make their products more inclusive, and what’s next.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[forgit –a tool powered by fzf for using git interactively]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/pkWL</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/wfxr/forgit"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T14:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Provides interactive git add, git log (👀 below), git diff, and a bunch more. Powered by fzf

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we build with and for people with disabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/building-with-the-disability-community-2022/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/building-with-the-disability-community-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor’s note: Today is Global Accessibility Awareness Day. We’re also sharing how we’re making education more accessibleand launching a newAndroid accessibility feature.
Over the past nine years, my job has focused on building accessible products and supporting Googlers with disabilities. Along the way, I’ve been constantly reminded of how vast and diverse the disability community is, and how important it is to continue working alongside this community to build technology and solutions that are truly helpful.
Before delving into some of the accessibility features our teams have been building, I want to share how we’re working to be more inclusive of people with disabilities to create more accessible tools overall.
Nothing about us, without us
In the disability community, people often say …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graph machine learning with missing node features]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/graph-machine-learning-with-missing-node-features</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/graph-machine-learning-with-missing-node-features"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T12:18:55.505Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post discusses how feature propagation can be an efficient and scalable approach for handling missing features in graph machine learning applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A hybrid approach to personalize notification volume]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/a-hybrid-approach-to-personalize-notification-volume</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/a-hybrid-approach-to-personalize-notification-volume"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T12:18:55.471Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we’ll share how we use machine learning techniques to ensure people see the right amount of relevant and timely notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing and delivering high-quality code with innersource metrics]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=65060</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-18-securing-and-delivering-high-quality-code-with-innersource-metrics/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T21:50:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With innersource, it’s important to measure both the amount of innersource activity and the quality of the code being created. Here’s how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Koppert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founders Talk 90: From GitHub TV to Rewatch]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/4/1593</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/founderstalk/90"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Connor Sears, founder and CEO of Rewatch, joins Adam to share the journey of creating Rewatch. What began inside of GitHub to help them thrive and connect is now available to every product team on the planet. Rewatch lets teams save, manage, and search all their video content so they can collaborate async and with greater flexibility. We talk about where the tool’s inspiration came from (spoiler alert, inside GitHub it was called GitHub TV which you’ll hear during the show), how teams leverage video to reduce the constraints of communication, how Connor and his co-founder knew they had product-fit and how they grew the team and product, and of course the flip side of that — we talk about some of Connor’s failures along the way, and knowing when it’s the right time to take a big swing.
Disc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Public and Private Bug Bounties and Vulnerability Disclosure Programs]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/understanding-public-and-private-bug-bounties-and-vulnerability-disclosure</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/understanding-public-and-private-bug-bounties-and-vulnerability-disclosure"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How Are Bug Bounty Programs and Vulnerability Disclosure Programs Different?

Let’s start with the similarities. Both bug bounties and VDPs aim to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Matthews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CloudNativePG – a new Kubernetes operator for Postgres]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Lpg4</id>
        <link href="https://www.enterprisedb.com/blog/introducing-cloudnativepg-new-open-source-kubernetes-operator-postgres"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CloudNativePG is distributed under the Apache License 2.0, and is now owned and governed by a newly formed community of contributors to the project, built on solid principles and values inspired by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF).
Among these are openness, fairness, inclusivity, technical excellence, “community over product/company,” built-in quality and built-in security. I’m part of the initial group of maintainers of the project, currently made up by the top six committers of the project within EDB.
If you’ve been following Ship It’s Kaizen episodes, you know we had troubles running Postgres in K8s and recently moved to a managed (sorta) database. I wonder if Gerhard will be tempted to try this operator out anyhow…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything I know and learned about running and maintaining open source projects for three decades]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/bNkZ</id>
        <link href="https://un.curl.dev/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T14:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Curl creator/maintainer Daniel Stenberg is writing a book. It’s (aptly) named: Uncurled
Because of my background and life with Open Source and probably a lot because of the relative success some of my projects have had, I frequently get questions about subjects related to maintaining Open Source. How to run a project and what makes them succeed? For a long time I have been collecting lessons from my life with Open Source into a list of advice for fellow Open Source library hackers. This document is my attempt to convert those thoughts and experiences into words.
I don’t believe it’s finished, but there’s a lot here already! Excited for this and while it’s a free to read GitBook right now, I hope it ends with some kind of physical manifestation.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privileged pod escalations in Kubernetes and GKE]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/05/privileged-pod-escalations-in.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/05/privileged-pod-escalations-in.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T13:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by GKE and Anthos Platform Security Teams 



At the KubeCon EU 2022 conference in Valencia, security researchers from Palo Alto Networks presented research findings on “trampoline pods”—pods with an elevated set of privileges required to do their job, but that could conceivably be used as a jumping off point to gain escalated privileges.
The research mentions GKE, including how developers should look at the privileged pod problem today, what the GKE team is doing to minimize the use of privileged pods, and actions GKE users can take to protect their clusters.
Privileged pods within the context of GKE security

While privileged pods can pose a security issue, it’s important to look at them within the overall context of GKE security. To use a privileged pod as a “trampoline” in GKE, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling data access by moving an exabyte of data to Google Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/scaling-data-access-by-moving-an-exabyte-of-data-to-google-cloud</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/scaling-data-access-by-moving-an-exabyte-of-data-to-google-cloud"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T12:20:06.762Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we approached migrating an exabyte of data to Google Cloud to make it easier for our Tweeps to analyze and visualize data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl annual user survey 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19202</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/17/curl-annual-user-survey-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T21:34:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the eighth consecutive year, we run the curl user survey. We usually kick it off during this time of the year. Tell us how you use curl! This is the best and frankly the only way the curl project has to get real feedback from people as to what features that are used and … Continue reading curl annual user survey 2022 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 178: Active learning & endangered languages]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1658</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/178"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t all AI methods need a bunch of data to work? How could AI help document and revitalize endangered languages with “human-in-the-loop” or “active learning” methods? Sarah Moeller from the University of Florida joins us to discuss those and other related questions. She also shares many of her personal experiences working with languages in low resource settings.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Sarah Moeller – GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Sarah’s academic website
An article about Sarah’s journey into this work
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A clean architecture template for Go services]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Z34k</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/evrone/go-clean-template"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T16:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The purpose of the template is to show:
how to organize a project and prevent it from turning into spaghetti code
where to store business logic so that it remains independent, clean, and extensible
how not to lose control when a microservice grows
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON and virtual columns in SQLite]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/VJ8Q</id>
        <link href="https://antonz.org/json-virtual-columns/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T15:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anton Zhiyanov shows how you can store non-normalized data in SQLite and use virtual columns to query against it without the massive performance penalty that json_extract would otherwise incur.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build terminal style websites in minutes]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ykOo</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/Cveinnt/LiveTerm"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Highly customizable, easy-to-use, and minimal terminal styled website template.
Building a simple website with LiveTerm only takes minutes, and you only need to work with one file: config.json. After you cloned this repository, simply run yarn install && yarn dev and start editing config.json to build your website!
Powered by Next.js.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to measure innersource across your organization]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64997</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-16-how-to-measure-innersource-across-your-organization/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T22:29:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The innersource contribution percentage is the rate of contributions from people outside the team that originally authored the software. Let’s dive into what it can look like for your organization.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Koppert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nu Holdings Ltd. Reports First Quarter 2022 Financial Results]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18373</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/financial-results-q1-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T21:14:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The full earnings release has been made available on the Company’s Investor Relations website
The post Nu Holdings Ltd. Reports First Quarter 2022 Financial Results appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Having to maintain your own cleverness 🎧]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/8O1Z</id>
        <link href="https://maintainable.fm/episodes/jerod-santo-having-to-maintain-your-own-cleverness"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T18:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had the honor of joining Robby Russell (who you may remember from Oh My Zsh) on his Maintainable podcast for a super-fun discussion on well-maintained software. Here’s how Robby describes it:
Robby has a chat with Jerod Santo, the Managing Editor and Partner of Changelog Media. Jerod helps lead and co-host Changelog’s flagship podcast, The Changelog, and builds all the cool stuff that makes Changelog awesome. Jerod shares his journey from being a typical networking engineer (Infosec) to the experienced programmer that he is today and his programming wisdom from the trenches.
Tune in as he highlights the undeniable importance of automated test suites and code readability, describes the arc of an engineer’s career, and talks about the past experiences that make him lean more towards clarity over cleverness when coding. He also shares some of the things engineers should consider in regard to pulling in third-party code or writing from scratch, and so much more. Enjoy!
Thanks for having me, Robby! 💚
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portfolio Review: May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/portfolio-review-may-2022</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/portfolio-review-may-2022"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T16:48:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Balanced and Pure Stocks Portfolios]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The life & death of software]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/N5O2</id>
        <link href="https://www.jamessimone.net/blog/joys-of-apex/the-life-and-death-of-software/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[James Simone ponders the relationship between healthy teams and performance in the software world.
Here’s what it comes down to: teams perform well when successes are shared and failures are owned… We don’t celebrate successes enough, and part of that (I think) is caused by the feeling of pressure that comes from working on a project that seems dooomed to fail without meticulous and ever-present attention.
He goes on to delve in to the source(s) of engineering failures, the dangers of “brightsizing”, known predictors for project success, and a bunch of related topics. Lots to ponder here alongside James, who’s seen a lot of software projects live & die during his eight years in the business.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re using projects to build projects]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64967</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-16-how-were-using-projects-to-build-projects/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T16:02:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At GitHub we use GitHub to build our own products, and the new projects experience is no different. Check out how our team uses projects to build powerful project planning for developers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jed Verity</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Achieves ISO/IEC 27001:2013 Certification!]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64961</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-16-github-achieves-iso-iec-270012013-certification/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T16:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub’s Information Security Management System (ISMS) has been certified against ISO 27001:2013, an internationally recognized standard for security program best practices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brandon Griffeth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Cyberdeck built with the Framework mainboard]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/n7V0</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/brickbots/framedeck"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T15:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WANT!
Framework has created a really slick, fully user serviceable, laptop and have recently started selling the mainboard as a SBC for general use.  To better support folks who may want to integrate it into their projects, they are also releasing technical documentation including  pinouts, cad models and other resources.
When they reached out and explained their plans and offered to let me play with one, I jumped at the chance and this is what I came up with after some experimentation.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A retro-style computer with a modern core]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/YNZ1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/penk/MainboardTerminal"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T14:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WANT!
Mainboard Terminal is not just any cyberdeck, it’s a full-feature PC powered by Framework’s Mainboard. It has a 5” (1080x1080) round LCD, a fully 3D printable case, and is compatible with OLKB Preonic mechanical keyboard.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A practical concurrency guide for Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/o9q9</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/luk4z7/go-concurrency-guide"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T13:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This guide is built on top of some examples from the book Concurrency in Go and Go Programming Language
Covering race conditions, mutexes, deadlocks, channels, patterns, and more.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next generation data insights using natural language queries]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/next-generation-data-insights-using-natural-language-queries</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/next-generation-data-insights-using-natural-language-queries"/>
        <updated>2022-05-15T12:18:06.313Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share details about how we built an in-house product called Qurious, which allows our internal customers to get answers to their analytical queries through natural language questions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Powering real-time data analytics with Druid at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/powering-real-time-data-analytics-with-druid-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/powering-real-time-data-analytics-with-druid-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2022-05-14T12:20:07.724Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share an overview of Twitter’s Druid ecosystem and discuss our work towards a unified ingestion experience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 489: Run your home on a Raspberry Pi]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1585</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/489"/>
        <updated>2022-05-13T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Mike Riley and we’re talking about his book Portable Python Projects (Running your home on a Raspberry Pi). We breakdown the details of the latest Raspberry Pi hardware, various automation ideas from the book, why Mike prefers Python for scripting on a Raspberry Pi, and of course why the Raspberry Pi makes sense for home labs concerned about data security.
Use the code PYPROJECTS to get a 35% discount on the book. That code is valid for approximately 60 days after the episode’s publish date.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 225: A JS framework for startups: Redwood goes 1.0]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1632</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/225"/>
        <updated>2022-05-13T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KBall interviews TPW about the 1.0 release of Redwood - what it provides, why they’ve repositioned as a “JavaScript framework optimized for startups”, and what’s coming next.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelog

    
Vercel – Vercel combines the best developer experience with an obsessive focus on end-user performance.  Our platform enables frontend teams to do t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The saddest "just ship it" story ever]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/GbaA</id>
        <link href="https://kitze.io/posts/saddest-just-ship-it-story-ever"/>
        <updated>2022-05-13T13:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ranty story from Kitze on a time when he didn’t ship the app he was working on and somebody else did!
It’s not their fault. I was just slow. I didn’t ship on time. I’m gonna go ahead and tattoo “JUST SHIP IT” on my forehead. Nah I wouldn’t be able to see it there. On my arm maybe. Nvm, let me go back to scrolling their landing page.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 229: What to do when projects get big and messy]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1643</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/229"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another entry in the maintenance series! Throughout the series we’ve discussed building versus buying, building actually maintainable software, maintaining ourselves, open source maintenance, legacy code, and most recently Go project structure. In this 7th installment of the series, we continue narrowing our focus by talking about what to do when projects get big and messy.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Move fast, even in big codebases. Sourcegraph is universal code search for every developer and team. Easily search across all the code that matters to you and your organization: find example code, explore and read code, debug issues, and more. Head to info.sourcegraph.com/changelog and click the button “Try Sourcegraph now” to get started.

    
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service catalogs, respond to incidents, communicate through status pages, and learn with retrospectives. Small teams up to 10 people can get started for free with all FireHydrant features included. No credit card required to sign up. Learn more at firehydrant.io

    
LaunchDarkly – Fundamentally change how you deliver software. Innovate faster, deploy fearlessly, and make each release a masterpiece.

    
Flatfile – Data import is broken. We fixed it. Flatfile’s powerful out-of-the-box solution takes the data import burden off your shoulders, freeing you to solve bigger business problems and build products that people love.

    
Featuring
sam boyer – Twitter, GitHub
Ian Lopshire – Twitter, GitHub
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Process Isolation in Firefox 100]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47829</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/05/improved-process-isolation-in-firefox-100/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T15:09:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox uses a multi-process model for additional security and stability while browsing: Web Content (such as HTML/CSS and Javascript) is rendered in separate processes that are isolated from the rest of the operating system and managed by a privileged parent process. This way, the amount of control gained by an attacker that exploits a bug in a content process is limited. In this article, we would like to dive a bit further into the latest major milestone we have reached: Win32k Lockdown, which greatly reduces the capabilities of the content process when running on Windows.
The post Improved Process Isolation in Firefox 100 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gian-Carlo Pascutto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta is transferring Jest to the OpenJS Foundation]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/3YNw</id>
        <link href="https://engineering.fb.com/2022/05/11/open-source/jest-openjs-foundation/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good for them (and us)! But what does that mean in practice?
Over the next few months, we’ll be completing the OpenJS Foundation’s incubation program checklist, including transferring the Jest domain, repo, website, and other assets to OpenJS. We’ll also be updating the code of conduct and contributor license agreement.
Additionally, as part of this move, we will be publishing a project charter and creating new governance policies that will document the process for gaining commit access, as well as our leadership selection process.
Next up: React?! A guy can dream…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commands.dev - find commands at the speed of thought]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/73wz</id>
        <link href="https://www.commands.dev/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T13:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A searchable, templated catalog of popular terminal commands curated from across the internet.
Pretty sweet resource from our friends at Warp. Contribute your own commands on GitHub.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A tale of a trailing dot]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18998</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/12/a-tale-of-a-trailing-dot/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T06:40:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trailing dots on host names in URLs is the gift that keeps on giving. Let me take you through a dwindling story of how the dot is handled differently in different places through the stack of an Internet client. The evil trailing dot. DNS When a given host name is to be resolved to an … Continue reading A tale of a trailing dot →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I/O 2022: Android 13 security and privacy (and more!)]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/05/io-2022-android-13-security-and-privacy.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/05/io-2022-android-13-security-and-privacy.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T19:05:00.047Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Eugene Liderman and Sara N-Marandi, Android Security and Privacy Team

Every year at I/O we share the latest on privacy and security features on Android. But we know some users like to go a level deeper in understanding how we’re making the latest release safer, and more private, while continuing to offer a seamless experience. So let’s dig into the tools we’re building to better secure your data, enhance your privacy and increase trust in the apps and experiences on your devices.  
Low latency, frictionless security
Regardless of whether a smartphone is used for consumer or enterprise purposes, attestation is a key underpinning to ensure the integrity of the device and apps running on the device. Fundamentally, key attestation lets a developer bind a secret or designate data to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graduation is here! Celebrate the Class of 2022, and join GitHub on June 11 🎓]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64901</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-11-graduation-is-here-celebrate-the-class-of-2022-and-join-github-on-june-11/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T18:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year, thousands of students from around the world came together and redefined the world we live in, how we learn, and how we move forward. We are honored to be part of the experience and eager to celebrate this milestone. So on June 11 we celebrate the Class of 2022 and welcome them to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lara Croft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking on the Next Generation of Phishing Scams]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/05/taking-on-next-generation-of-phishing.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/05/taking-on-next-generation-of-phishing.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T18:00:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Daniel Margolis, Software Engineer, Google Account Security Team 
Every year, security technologies improve: browsers get better, encryption becomes ubiquitous on the Web, authentication becomes stronger. But phishing persistently remains a threat (as shown by a recent phishing attack on the U.S. Department of Labor) because users retain the ability to log into their online accounts, often with a simple password, from anywhere in the world. It’s why today at I/O we announced new ways we’re reducing the risks of phishing by: scaling phishing protections to Google Docs, Sheets and Slides, continuing to auto enroll people in 2-Step Verification and more. This blog will deep dive into the method of phishing and how it has evolved today. 
As phishing adoption has grown, multi-factor a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving skin tone representation across Google]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/search/monk-skin-tone-scale/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/search/monk-skin-tone-scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T17:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seeing yourself reflected in the world around you — in real life, media or online — is so important. And we know that challenges with image-based technologies and representation on the web have historically left people of color feeling overlooked and misrepresented. Last year, we announced Real Tone for Pixel, which is just one example of our efforts to improve representation of diverse skin tones across Google products.
Today, we're introducing a next step in our commitment to image equity and improving representation across our products. In partnership with Harvard professor and sociologist Dr. Ellis Monk, we’re releasing a new skin tone scale designed to be more inclusive of the spectrum of skin tones we see in our society. Dr. Monk has been studying how skin tone and colorism affect pe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google I/O 2022: Advancing knowledge and computing]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/developers/io-2022-keynote/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/developers/io-2022-keynote/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[TL;DR]
Nearly 24 years ago, Google started with two graduate students, one product, and a big mission: to organize the world’s information and make it universally accessible and useful. In the decades since, we’ve been developing our technology to deliver on that mission.
The progress we've made is because of our years of investment in advanced technologies, from AI to the technical infrastructure that powers it all. And once a year — on my favorite day of the year :) — we share an update on how it’s going at Google I/O.
Today, I talked about how we’re advancing two fundamental aspects of our mission — knowledge and computing — to create products that are built to help. It’s exciting to build these products; it’s even more exciting to see what people do with them.
Thank you to everyone wh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The a11y project checklist]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/X6Le</id>
        <link href="https://www.a11yproject.com/checklist/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T16:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Check your site against this to determine your accessibility compliance with the WCAG.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the world through language]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/understanding-the-world-through-language/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/understanding-the-world-through-language/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Language is at the heart of how people communicate with each other. It’s also proving to be powerful in advancing AI and building helpful experiences for people worldwide.


From the beginning, we set out to connect words in your search to words on a page so we could make the web’s information more accessible and useful. Over 20 years later, as the web changes, and the ways people consume information expand from text to images to videos and more — the one constant is that language remains a surprisingly powerful tool for understanding information.


In recent years, we’ve seen an incredible acceleration in the field of natural language understanding. While our systems still don’t understand language the way people do, they’re increasingly able to spot patterns in information, identify comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 52: Priyanka's Happy Hour (KubeCon EU 2022)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1630</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/52"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we talk to Priyanka Sharma (E.D. at the Cloud Native Computing Foundation) about all things KubeCon Europe 2022. We start with Gerhard’s favourite subject - Priyanka’s Happy Hour - and then we switch focus to the conference.
For many, this will be the first in-person KubeCon since 2019. As for Gerhard, he is not sure that he remember how airports work. If he succeeds, he looks forward to meeting some of you in Valencia. If not, send help.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immersive view coming soon to Maps — plus more updates]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/maps/three-maps-updates-io-2022/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/maps/three-maps-updates-io-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google Maps helps over one billion people navigate and explore. And over the past few years, our investments in AI have supercharged the ability to bring you the most helpful information about the real world, including when a business is open and how crowded your bus is. Today at Google I/O, we announced new ways the latest advancements in AI are transforming Google Maps — helping you explore with an all-new immersive view of the world, find the most fuel-efficient route, and use the magic of Live View in your favorite third-party apps.
A more immersive, intuitive map
Google Maps first launched to help people navigate to their destinations. Since then, it’s evolved to become much more — it’s a handy companion when you need to find the perfect restaurant or get information about a local bus…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Translate learns 24 new languages]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/products/translate/24-new-languages/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/products/translate/24-new-languages/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T15:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years, Google Translate has helped break down language barriers and connect communities all over the world. And we want to make this possible for even more people — especially those whose languages aren’t represented in most technology. So today we’ve added 24 languages to Translate, now supporting a total of 133 used around the globe.
Over 300 million people speak these newly added languages — like Mizo, used by around 800,000 people in the far northeast of India, and Lingala, used by over 45 million people across Central Africa. As part of this update, Indigenous languages of the Americas (Quechua, Guarani and Aymara) and an English dialect (Sierra Leonean Krio) have also been added to Translate for the first time.




Translate's mission translated into some of our newly added langu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Monthly – May 2022 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64908</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-11-open-source-monthly-may-2022-edition/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T15:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction Open Sauced, GitHub’s Explore page, Hacktoberfest, and First Timers Only help folks discover open source projects. This monthly series–Open Source Monthly—will add to these efforts by helping: First-time contributors find the right project to contribute to Corporations and individuals find a new project to sponsor Open source maintainers gain more consistent contributors and sponsors […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rizel Scarlett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I left Google: work-life balance]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/maeP</id>
        <link href="https://www.scottkennedy.us/balance.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T14:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love when software engineers share their career/life choices and the reasoning behind them so others can benefit from their perspective, like this one on bucket filling:
Somebody once described balance to me as three buckets filled with water. One for career, a second for physical health, and a third for social and family life. At any point, one bucket might be running low. But as long as the overall water level is high enough, things should be fine.
Scott’s choice to join a startup seems odd given his reason for leaving Google, but:
So: am I happier? Undoubtedly yes.
I work more hours. I’m more likely to be working in the evening or on the weekend now. But what I do makes a difference that I can see. Progress feels 10x faster.
Most surprising is that I have more energy. It’s easier to find motivation to get back in the gym. I have more energy in social situations.
Working more hours sounds like tipping the work/life balance in the wrong direction, but excitement about your work certainly changes the calculus. He’s happier now, so that’s great!
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A TUI for viewing and editing database files]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/wk8R</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/mathaou/termdbms"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T14:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently supports SQLite and CSV. MySQL and Postgres are on the roadmap. Built with Bubble Tea.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If programming languages were Futurama characters]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/d3ga</id>
        <link href="https://www.netmeister.org/blog/futurama.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news, everyone! Jan Schaumann merged Futurama with your (least) favorite programming languages. Amy Wong is… Ruby?!
Object-oriented, cute, really popular, and a bit naive. Had a bit of Fry grafted onto herself for a while. Also had a thing with Bender. And Zapp. Easy going, but doesn’t do well in difficult situations, falls over easily.
Bender is Shell. Fry is Perl. If you care at all for his reasoning, you’ve already clicked through!
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A closer look at the research to help AI see more skin tones]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/research/ai-monk-scale-skin-tone-story/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/research/ai-monk-scale-skin-tone-story/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T09:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today at I/O we released the Monk Skin Tone (MST) Scale in partnership with Harvard professor and sociologist Dr. Ellis Monk. The MST Scale, developed by Dr. Monk, is a 10-shade scale designed to be more inclusive of the spectrum of skin tones in our society. We’ll be incorporating the MST Scale into various Google products over the coming months, and we are openly releasing the scale so that anyone can use it for research and product development.
The MST Scale is an important next step in a collective effort to improve skin tone inclusivity in technology. For Google, it will help us make progress in our commitment to image equity and improving representation across our products. And in releasing the MST Scale for all to use, we hope to make it easier for others to do the same, so we can l…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl 7.83.1 it burns]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19090</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/11/curl-7-83-1-it-burns/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T06:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to this patch release of curl, shipped only 14 days since the previous version. We decided to cut the release cycle short because of the several security vulnerabilities that were pointed out. See below for details. There are no new features added in this release. It burns. Mostly in our egos. Release video Numbers … Continue reading curl 7.83.1 it burns →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founders Talk 89: Leading GitLab to IPO]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/4/1581</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/founderstalk/89"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Sid Sijbrandij Co-founder and CEO of GitLab is back talking with Adam about all the details of their massive IPO last October 2021. To set the stage, this episode was recorded on Feb 1, 2022. During the show Adam mentioned they IPO’d at a $13B market cap, but they actually ended their opening day at approximately $15B. That’s a massive win for open source, GitLab, Sid, and the rest of the team. For loyal listeners you know we’ve had Sid on this show before, so of course we had to get him back on the show post-IPO to get all the details of this new journey.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not j…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release of Technical Report into the AMD Security Processor]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2022/05/release-of-technical-report-into-amd.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2022/05/release-of-technical-report-into-amd.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ol{margin:0;padding:0}table td,table th{padding:0}.RmvCPDuePa-c3{padding-top:0pt;padding-bottom:0pt;line-height:1.5;orphans:2;widows:2;text-align:left;height:11pt}.RmvCPDuePa-c0{color:#000000;font-weight:400;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;font-size:11pt;font-family:"Arial";font-style:normal}.RmvCPDuePa-c7{padding-top:0pt;padding-bottom:0pt;line-height:1.5;orphans:2;widows:2;text-align:left}.RmvCPDuePa-c2{padding-top:0pt;padding-bottom:0pt;line-height:1.0;text-align:left}.RmvCPDuePa-c6{text-decoration-skip-ink:none;-webkit-text-decoration-skip:none;color:#1155cc;text-decoration:underline}.RmvCPDuePa-c4{background-color:#ffffff;max-width:468pt;padding:72pt 72pt 72pt 72pt}.RmvCPDuePa-c1{color:inherit;text-decoration:inherit}.RmvCPDuePa-c5{border:1px solid black;margin:5px}.title…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced 2FA experience for your npm account]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64931</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-10-enhanced-2fa-experience-for-your-npm-account/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T16:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Late last year, in response to an unprecedented series of account takeovers resulting from the compromise of developer accounts without 2FA enabled, we committed to a variety of enhancements to the npm registry to make two-factor authentication (2FA) adoption easier for developers. Today, we are launching a public beta for a significantly improved 2FA experience […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Borins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Attack Resistance Management?]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/company-news/what-attack-resistance-management</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/company-news/what-attack-resistance-management"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Security Survey on How to Close Your Organization's Attack Resistance Gap]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Matthews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CEO's guide to Emacs]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/pkPL</id>
        <link href="https://www.fugue.co/blog/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T15:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Josh Stella:
For those who haven’t used Emacs, it’s something you’ll likely hate, but may love. It’s sort of a Rube Goldberg machine the size of a house that, at first glance, performs all the functions of a toaster. That hardly sounds like an endorsement, but the key phrase is “at first glance.” Once you grok Emacs, you realize that it’s a thermonuclear toaster that can also serve as the engine for… well, just about anything you want to do with text.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why video calls are bad for brainstorming]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/j57b</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_SK4mcTid10"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T15:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interesting findings by Melanie S. Brucks and Jonathan Levav:
According to new research one important skill is impacted by the restrictions of video calls: creativity. But why is idea generation negatively affected? And could other skills actually benefit from virtual communication?

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hugging Face raised $100 million for open/collaborative machine learning]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Z3jk</id>
        <link href="https://huggingface.co/blog/series-c"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Big news from our friends at Hugging Face:
Hugging Face is now the fastest growing community & most used platform for machine learning! With 100,000 pre-trained models & 10,000 datasets hosted on the platform for NLP, computer vision, speech, time-series, biology, reinforcement learning, chemistry and more, the Hugging Face Hub has become the Home of Machine Learning to create, collaborate, and deploy state-of-the-art models.
What will they spend the money on? Good stuff:
Thanks to the new funding, we’ll be doubling down on research, open-source, products and responsible democratization of AI.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supercharging GitHub Actions with Job Summaries]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64780</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-09-supercharging-github-actions-with-job-summaries/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T16:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now output and group custom Markdown content on the Actions run summary page.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Konrad Pabjan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code's major Markdown tooling upgrade]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/VJWQ</id>
        <link href="https://blog.dendron.so/notes/upyp4ow9fkpwvu50n8wsvnp/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T15:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lots of cool stuff for Markdown authors in April’s VS Code release. Namely:
drag and drop files into the editor to create a Markdown link
find all references to header|links|files|urls inside of Markdown
rename headers|links inside Markdown (and propagate the changes)
rename Markdown files (and propagate to all references)
The Dendron team is excited because their primary vault hosts over 400k lines of Markdown 🤯
VS Code, and IDEs more broadly, help developers manage large code bases by making available tools to leverage and manipulate the syntax of programming languages. By shifting some of this tooling to markdown, can we do the same for large Markdown repositories?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chunky Bacon]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/maR3</id>
        <link href="http://code-anth.xyz/posts/3"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T15:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gui Heurich on one of the legends of the Ruby community, _why the lucky stiff.
Through the things that he built, the way he performed, and the books that he wrote, _why makes us think about code and also about ourselves. It makes us think about ourselves as programmers. In a sense, _why was the meta-programmer, the one that generates other programmers by promoting reflexivity.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare for next semester with GitHub Global Campus and Codespaces]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64752</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-09-prepare-for-next-semester-with-github-global-campus-and-codespaces/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teachers, it is now your turn to join GitHub Global Campus with our student community! Get access to exclusive benefits, programs, and the Power of Codespaces at no cost in GitHub Classroom!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Rosado</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Literate programming Wordle]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ykQo</id>
        <link href="https://jiby.tech/project/literate_wordle/wordle.html"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T14:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve long been fascinated by literate programming (the art of writing code as if it was a novel), but it’s been awhile since I’ve seen a good example of in practice. Here’s a good one:
I wanted to showcase the BDD-inspired low-tech solution I came up with via a toy project, demonstrating a small but significant programming task, broken down as series of design-implementation cycles.
Wordle is a perfect target: it’s a small codebase, with a half dozen features to string together into a useable game.
This story has five chapters and a satisfying conclusion:
This project was my first foray into literate programming at this scale, an attempt to bring together all the good ideas of TDD, modern Python development, Gherkin usage for requirements traceability purposes (without overly zealous extremes of Cucumber automation). All these ideas were until now scattered, implemented each without the others in different places, and this project fuses them into something I hope is more valuable than the sum of its parts.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing a new Swift package for Apache Thrift]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2022/introducing-twitter-apache-thrift</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2022/introducing-twitter-apache-thrift"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T12:24:22.807Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter’s new Thrift library is an open-source, standalone, lightweight, data encoding library. In this blog, we share our library so iOS developers outside Twitter can start using Thrift data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 488: Mob programming deep dive]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1615</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/488"/>
        <updated>2022-05-06T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re talking with Woody Zuill today about all things Mob Programming. Woody leads Mob Programming workshops, he’s a speaker on agile related topics, and coaches and guides orgs interested in creating an environment where people can do their best work. We talk through it all and we even get some amazing advice from Woody’s dad. We define what Mob Programming is and why it’s so effective. Is it a rigid process or can teams flex to make it work for them? How to introduce mob programming to a team. What kind of groundwork is necessary? And of course, are mob programming’s virtues diminished by remote teams in virtual-only settings?
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Square – Develop on the plat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fclones – an efficient duplicate file finder and remover]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/bNwO</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/pkolaczk/fclones"/>
        <updated>2022-05-06T18:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duplicates taking up tons of space on your home NAS? fclones quickly identifies duplicates, even when there’s 10s of thousands that you’re scanning over the network:
fclones treats your data seriously. You can inspect and modify the list of duplicate files before removing them. There is also a –dry-run option that can tell you exactly what changes on the file system would be made.
Also check out the algorithm used to detect duplicates.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 224: Were SPAs a big mistake?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1635</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/224"/>
        <updated>2022-05-06T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let the debate begin (again)! This time we’re arguing whether or not single-page apps were a big mistake. This premise was inspired by Chris Ferdinandi’s SPAs were a mistake post.
Divya & Nick represent Team Yep and KBall goes solo on Team Nope. Jerod, as per our usual arrangement, is on Team Winner.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 6 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make sure you are quickly notified of the errors, crashes, and front-end performance issues that matter most to you and your business. Set thresholds for your alert based on an increase in error count, a spike in load time, or new issues introduced in the latest deployment. Start your free 14-day trial at Raygun.com

    
Vercel – Vercel combines the best developer experience with an obsessive focus on end-user performance.  Our platform enables frontend teams to do their best work. Unlock a better frontend workflow today.

    
Sourcegraph – Move fast, even in big codebases. Sourcegraph is universal code search for every developer and team. Easily search across all the code that matters to you and your organization: find example code, explore and read code, debug issues, and more. Head to info.sourcegraph.com/changelog and click the button “Try Sourcegraph now” to get started.

    
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Divya – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Kevin Ball – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Notes and Links
SPAs were a mistake
Holla! RemixConf May 24-25
Previous YepNope debates:
Should websites work without JS?
Is modern JS tooling too complicated?
Should we rebrand JavaScript?
Are web apps fundamentally different than web sites?
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s most common security vulnerabilities explained]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64815</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-06-todays-most-common-security-vulnerabilities-explained/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-06T15:52:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're taking a look at some of the most common security vulnerabilities and detailing how developers can best protect themselves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Katsioloudes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How i fell in love with low-js]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/q0ae</id>
        <link href="https://edofic.com/posts/2022-01-28-low-js/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-06T14:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andraž Bajt:
Basic premise is: browsers are great at navigating pages, let’s leverage that by serving users directly with HTML. This already gives you half-decent pages but you can go further and sprinkle on some sugar. A bit of JS. Instead of reinventing the world in JS let’s try to really use what modern browsers provide natively and then push just a bit forward.
Is the pendulum starting to swing away from SPAs/client-side rendering and back toward MPAs/server-side rendering? Will we ever find balance somewhere in the middle?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 228: Go and PHP sitting in a tree...]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1602</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/228"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T22:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can Go help you write faster PHP apps? In this episode, we explore the unusual pairing of Go and PHP that led to the RoadRunner project, a high-performance PHP application server, load-balancer, and process manager that is all written in Go.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Move fast, even in big codebases. Sourcegraph is universal code search for every developer and team. Easily search across all the code that matters to you and your organization: find example code, explore and read code, debug issues, and more. Head to info.sourcegraph.com/changelog and click the button “Try Sourcegraph now” to get started.

    
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service catalogs, respond to incidents, communicate through status pages, and learn with retrospectives. Small teams up to 10 people can get started for free with all FireHydrant features included. No credit card required to sign up. Learn more at firehydrant.io

    
LaunchDarkly – Fundamentally change how you deliver software. Innovate faster, deploy fearlessly, and make each release a masterpiece.

    
Flatfile – Data import is broken. We fixed it. Flatfile’s powerful out-of-the-box solution takes the data import burden off your shoulders, freeing you to solve bigger business problems and build products that people love.

    
Featuring
Valery Piashchynski – Twitter, GitHub
Anton Titov – Twitter, GitHub
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
RoadRunner website
RoadRunner on GitHub
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 of our favorite games + source code from Ludum Dare 50]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64485</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-05-ludum-dare-50/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T20:37:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[20 of our favorite games plus source code from the latest Ludum Dare competition.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub will require 2FA by the end of 2023]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ykQe</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-04-software-security-starts-with-the-developer-securing-developer-accounts-with-2fa/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T20:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Hanley on GitHub’s blog:
The software supply chain starts with the developer. Developer accounts are frequent targets for social engineering and account takeover, and protecting developers from these types of attacks is the first and most critical step toward securing the supply chain…
Today, as part of a platform-wide effort to secure the software ecosystem through improving account security, we’re announcing that GitHub will require all users who contribute code on GitHub.com to enable one or more forms of two-factor authentication (2FA) by the end of 2023.
This is a big step in the right direction and their new(ish) 2FA for GitHub Mobile feature helps make the burden not as cumbersome as it might be otherwise.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The ReadME Project Q&A: What you need to know about teaching technical skills]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=63643</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-05-the-readme-project-qa-what-you-need-to-know-about-teaching-technical-skills/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T17:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching is a great way to not only help others but to better learn a topic yourself.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klint Finley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IBM's jerk test]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/zgnn</id>
        <link href="https://johnpublic.mataroa.blog/blog/the-asshole-test/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T16:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some years back I applied to join IBM’s grad scheme, there was a peculiar stage to the process I’ve not seen elsewhere. It was during the onsite day, where a batch of 20 or so applicants were put through various tests in an IBM office. They called it the “group test”; around 8 of us were led to a room and asked to solve a puzzle together.
You can probably see where this story is headed… (see also)
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A tool to quickly "view source" from your mobile phone]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/8Od6</id>
        <link href="https://neatnik.net/view-source/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T15:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you’re on the go and you land on a particularly impressive website. You’d love to peak underneath the covers, but getting at the developer tools on a phone is a pain.
Instead: bookmark this site, copy/paste the URL, and voilá! 💁‍♀️
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founders Talk 88: Making an open source Stripe for time]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/4/1645</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/founderstalk/88"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Peer Richelsen, Co-Founder and Co-CEO of Cal.com, joins the show to talk about building the “Stripe for Time” — with a grand mission to connect a billion people by 2031 through calendar scheduling. Cal has grown from an open-source side project to one of the fastest-growing commercial open source companies. We get into all the details — what it means to be an open source Calendly alternative, how they quantify connecting a Billion people by 2031, where there’s room for innovation in the scheduling space, and why being community first is part of their secret sauce.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 7 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
WorkOS – A platform that gives developers a set of building blocks for quickly addin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting the Cyber Safety Review Board]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18940</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/05/meeting-the-cyber-safety-review-board/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T14:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three Open Source hackers were invited to this meeting with the CSRB and I was one of them. The board with this name is part of CISA, a US government effort that received a presidential order to work on “Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity“. Where “the Nation” here is the US. I’m not in the US … Continue reading Meeting the Cyber Safety Review Board →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: April 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64750</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-04-github-availability-report-april-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T22:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April, we experienced two distinct incidents resulting in significant impact and degraded state of availability for Codespaces and GitHub Packages.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of handy bash one-liners]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/P5Qr</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/onceupon/Bash-Oneliner"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bonnie I-Man Ng:
I was working on bioinformatics a few years ago and was amazed by those single-word bash commands which are much faster than my dull scripts, time saved through learning command-line shortcuts and scripting.
Recent years I am working on cloud computing and I keep recording those useful commands here. Not all of them is oneliner, but I put effort on making them brief and swift. I am mainly using Ubuntu, Amazon Linux, RedHat, Linux Mint, Mac and CentOS, sorry if the commands don’t work on your system.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 51: From Kubernetes to PaaS - now what?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1629</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/51"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we talk to Mark Ericksen about all the things that we could be doing on the new platform - this is a follow-up to episode 50.
Mark specialises in Elixir, he hosts the Thinking Elixir podcast, and he also helps make Fly.io the best place to run Phoenix apps, such as changelog.com. In the interest of holding our new platform right, we thought that it would be a great idea to talk to someone that does this all day, every day, for many years now.
We touch up on how to run database migrations safely, and how to upgrade our application config to the latest Phoenix version. We also talked about some of the more advanced platform features that we may want to start leveraging, like the multi-region PostgreSQL.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode becaus…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software security starts with the developer: Securing developer accounts with 2FA]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64715</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-04-software-security-starts-with-the-developer-securing-developer-accounts-with-2fa/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T15:04:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub will require all users who contribute code on GitHub.com to enable one or more forms of two-factor authentication (2FA) by the end of 2023.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Hanley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Party like it's 1995! Microsoft 3D Movie Maker is open source]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/3Yp6</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/Microsoft-3D-Movie-Maker"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The coolest thing about this story is that the entire endeavor was apparently prompted by a random developer tweet! If you’ve ever wondered what all goes in to opening the source of historic software products like this one:
This code was restored from the Microsoft corporate archives and cleared for release.
Developer names and aliases were removed, with the exception of current employees who worked on the original release who consented to keeping their names in place
The archive consisted of several CDs, some of which were for alternate builds or products, and have been excluded
The code does not build with today’s engineering tools, and is released as-is.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A guide for your daily "professional" interactions]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/7368</id>
        <link href="https://howtoprofessionallysay.akashrajpurohit.com/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T13:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An in-progress list of things you might feel like saying attached to things you should probably say instead. For instance, you’re thinking, “Do your job!” But it’s probably more beneficial to say:
It is my understanding that you are the appropriate person to contact in regards to this. But If there’s is someone better equipped for this let me know.
You can also flip the list to translate what you are being told by someone from what they actually mean.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charts to watch #4]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/charts-to-watch-4</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/charts-to-watch-4"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T13:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A mix of charts on stocks and indices]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advancing Jupyter Notebooks at Twitter - Part 1]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2021/advancing-jupyter-notebooks-at-twitter---part-1--a-first-class-d</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2021/advancing-jupyter-notebooks-at-twitter---part-1--a-first-class-d"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T12:20:59.542Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Notebook is Twitter’s internal notebook solution. It provides a first-class development environment to Data Scientist and Machine Learning practitioners at Twitter. This blog shares features o]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Twitter conversations: A Wordle case study]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/understanding-twitter-conversations--a-wordle-case-study</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/understanding-twitter-conversations--a-wordle-case-study"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T12:20:59.498Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the Data Science team, a piece of our job is understanding how conversations are happening on Twitter. In this blog, we use Wordle as a case study to showcase how we think about similar analyses.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Launching the comma body]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/commabody/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/commabody/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At comma, our mission is:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Ruby has symbols]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/JL2r</id>
        <link href="https://dmitrytsepelev.dev/why-has-ruby-symbols"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T21:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most Ruby engineers know the difference between symbols and strings from a usage perspective. So, in this article I look at them from a different angle.
You’ll learn about a cool compiler optimization called “string interning”, which is used in many languages. Also, you will understand what happens when (almost any) interpreter runs your code, take a look at the AST and take a peak at the symbols interpretation at the low level.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Tsepelev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preventing burnout: a manager's toolkit]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/DzRr</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2022/05/03/preventing-burnout-a-managers-toolkit/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T20:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab’s Sid Sijbrandij shares 12 strategies managers can use to support their team and prevent burnout. One of his standout strategies that I doubt rarely gets put into use is reduce the number of hours worked by agreeing to reduce effort
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why HackerOne Acquired Pull Request and What It Means to Our Customers]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/company-news/why-hackerone-acquired-pull-request-and-what-it-means-our-customers</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/company-news/why-hackerone-acquired-pull-request-and-what-it-means-our-customers"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T18:59:59.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 177: Learning the language of life]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1642</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/177"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI is discovering new drugs. Sound like science fiction? Not at Absci! Sean and Joshua join us to discuss their AI-driven pipeline for drug discovery. We discuss the tech along with how it might change how we think about healthcare at the most fundamental level.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with extended episodes, make the ads disappear, and increment your audio quality with higher bitrate mp3s. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Sean McClain – Twitter, LinkedIn
Joshua Meier – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
View Absci’s AI Lead Scientist Joshua Meier’s presentation at NVIDIA GTC 2022
Learn more about Absci’s machine learning breakthroughs presented at GTC
Learn more about Absci AI Research (AAIR) Lab
View career opportunities at Absci
Absci AI drug discovery technology
Watch the Truist AI Symposium Podcast to get help demystifying the use of AI in drug discovery
Absci website
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An end-to-end machine learning solution for Postgres]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/gdDl</id>
        <link href="https://postgresml.org/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Train and deploy industry-standard or completely custom machine learning models, directly powered by your business data, into your production stack, with an open source Postgres extension.
Is there anything Postgres can’t do?! 😉
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You don't need a UI framework]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/wknG</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2022/05/you-dont-need-ui-framework/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T14:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Josh Comeau writing for Smashing Mag:
Developers often reach for UI frameworks like Bootstrap or Material UI, hoping that they’ll save a bunch of time and quickly build a professional-looking app. Unfortunately, things rarely work out this way. Let’s talk about it.
Stick around for the rebuttals section, too.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[now on HTTP/3]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19074</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/02/now-on-http-3/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T21:41:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first mention of QUIC on this blog was back when I posted about the HTTP workshop of July 2015. Today, this blog is readable over the protocol QUIC subsequently would turn into. (Strictly speaking, it turned into QUIC + HTTP/3 but let’s not be too literal now.) The other day Fastly announced that all … Continue reading now on HTTP/3 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we build a fully regional cloud architecture on AWS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Gb5W</id>
        <link href="https://apptrail.com/blog/2022/03/09/regional-cloud-architecture"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T17:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As it gets easier and easier to deploy to the cloud, and with increased concern about data sovereignty, regional architectures are becoming more common. This article gives you an overview of how we easily maintain our regional services on AWS at Apptrail.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samrose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAI's DALL-E 2 implemented in Pytorch]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/53lr</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/lucidrains/DALLE2-pytorch"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T16:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAI’s new SOTA text-to-image neural network is producing some “insane results”. The linked repo is an open source implementation of the same technique.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being friendly: Strategies for friendly fork management]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64670</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-05-02-friend-zone-strategies-friendly-fork-management/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T16:26:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the second and final post in a series describing friendly forks and alternative strategies for managing them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lessley Dennington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the Results of the 12-month DIB-VDP Pilot]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-disclosure/announcing-results-12-month-dib-vdp-pilot</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-disclosure/announcing-results-12-month-dib-vdp-pilot"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semantic Versioning for TypeScript Types]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/pkAg</id>
        <link href="https://www.semver-ts.org"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T15:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since TypeScript doesn’t follow SemVer itself, TS libraries which do want to follow SemVer need both high-level guidance about how to do that and detailed analysis of the corner cases to watch out for as well as ways to mitigate breaking changes from TS.
This doc is a (beta!) specification of SemVer for managing changes to TypeScript types, including when the TS compiler makes breaking changes in its type-checking and type emit across a “minor” release.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Krycho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data transfer in Manhattan using RocksDB]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-transfer-in-manhattan-using-rocksdb</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-transfer-in-manhattan-using-rocksdb"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T12:23:30.300Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we talk about a performance and stability problem we encountered while migrating Manhattan's storage engine to RocksDB and how we solved it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Considered “18+”]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19048</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/05/02/considered-18/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T09:07:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vodafone UK has taken it on themselves to make the world better by marking this website (daniel.haxx.se) “adult content”. I suppose in order to protect the children. It was first reported to me on May 2, with this screenshot from a Vodafone customer: And later followed up with some more details from another user in … Continue reading Considered “18+” →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncurled]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18936</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/04/30/uncurled/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-30T10:18:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[– Everything I know and learned about running and maintaining Open Source projects for three decades. For several years now, I have had a blog post series in mind to describe something about what people could expect to happen in Open Source projects. I had a few already half-started blog post drafts for some sub … Continue reading Uncurled →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Factors to consider when architecting systems that uses third-party systems]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9OEm</id>
        <link href="https://shekhargulati.com/2022/02/16/factors-to-consider-when-architecting-systems-on-top-of-third-party-systems/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T21:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, I will talk about important factors you should consider when architecting systems that are powered by third-party systems. The factors I detail are:
deployment model
technology coherence
NFRs and SLAs
Infrastructure and hardware needs
API style and documentation
Idempotent APIs
Getting data out of the third party provider
Community
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shekhar Gulati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A cross-platform file explorer powered by a virtual distributed filesystem]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/EQeG</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/spacedriveapp/spacedrive"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T20:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spacedrive helps you organize your files across many devices in one place. Here’s the motivation:
Many of us have multiple cloud accounts, drives that aren’t backed up and data at risk of loss. We depend on cloud services like Google Photos and iCloud, but are locked in with limited capacity and almost zero interoperability between services and operating systems. Photo albums shouldn’t be stuck in a device ecosystem, or harvested for advertising data. They should be OS agnostic, permanent and personally owned. Data we create is our legacy, that will long outlive us—open source technology is the only way to ensure we retain absolute control over the data that defines our lives, at unlimited scale.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wireit upgrades your npm scripts to make them smarter and more efficient]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/W3W1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/google/wireit"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T18:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is alpha software, but it seems pretty low risk to give it a try.
Wireit works with npm run, it doesn’t replace it. To configure an NPM script for Wireit, move the command into a new wireit section of your package.json, and replace the original script with the wireit command.
Now when you run npm run build, Wireit upgrades the script to be smarter and more efficient.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 223: Nick's big rewrite]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1639</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/223"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nick rewrote our JS Danger game board app from Dojo to React for his talk at React Global Online Summit about componentizing application state with React and XState.
On this episode Jerod, KBall, and Feross chat with Nick about the entire process and what he learned along the way. Oh, we also play an epic round of Pro Tip Time!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 8 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn continuously about their applications - from the frontend to the backend. Use the code PARTYTIME and get the team plan free for three months.

    
Vercel – Vercel combines the best developer experience with an obsessive focus on end-user performance.  Our platform enables frontend teams to do their best work. Unlock a better frontend workflow today.

    
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s business needs. Learn more at changelog.com/square to dive into the docs, APIs, SDKs and to create your Square Developer account — tell them Changelog sent you.

    
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Kevin Ball – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Feross Aboukhadijeh – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Nick’s talk at React Global Online Summit
Our Quiz Game repo on GitHub
JS Party #191 on XState
Don’t check in broken code
Conventional Comments
Everything Everywhere All at Once
Elon Musk is buying Twitter. I’m buying JavaScript.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing code navigation to communities]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64639</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-04-29-bringing-code-navigation-to-communities/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to the efforts of the Elixir community, GitHub supports code navigation for Elixir repositories. Read how favorite language can add this support too!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let's talk about blockchains]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/q0Pe</id>
        <link href="https://cmdli.dev/blog/blockchain/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T13:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post by Chris de la Iglesia starts off very down on blockchains, but ends up not so down after all:
We are entering a new world with a new focus on giving users control over their data, their identity, and their systems. We are building distributed filesystems, distributed identity, and yes, blockchains. I think oftentimes we end up seeing only the blockchain technology due to the headlines and the financial investment, but distributed systems as a whole are taking off in a big, big way.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Package Analysis Project: Scalable detection of malicious open source packages]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/04/the-package-analysis-project-scalable.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/04/the-package-analysis-project-scalable.html"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T16:05:00.008Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Caleb Brown, Open Source Security Team 


Despite open source software’s essential role in all software built today, it’s far too easy for bad actors to circulate malicious packages that attack the systems and users running that software. Unlike mobile app stores that can scan for and reject malicious contributions, package repositories have limited resources to review the thousands of daily updates and must maintain an open model where anyone can freely contribute. As a result, malicious packages like ua-parser-js, and node-ipc are regularly uploaded to popular repositories despite their best efforts, with sometimes devastating consequences for users. 
Google, a member of the Open Source Security Foundation (OpenSSF), is proud to support the OpenSSF’s Package Analysis project, w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 227: Analyzing static analysis]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1612</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/227"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matan Peled from Technion University joins Natalie & Mat to discuss his PhD research on meta programming and static analyzers. How does Go’s measure up? What would Matan’s look like if he built one? All that and more!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Move fast, even in big codebases. Sourcegraph is universal code search for every developer and team. Easily search across all the code that matters to you and your organization: find example code, explore and read code, debug issues, and more. Head to info.sourcegraph.com/changelog and click the button “Try Sourcegraph now” to get started.

    
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best practices to keep your projects secure on GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64550</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-04-28-best-practices-to-keep-your-projects-secure-on-github/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T15:55:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These days software is subject to an ever-changing threat landscape. Check out the many ways you can keep your projects secure on GitHub today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin Hutchings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Voice dataset tops 20,000 hours]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47798</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/04/common-voice-dataset-tops-20000-hours/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T15:23:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Common Voice dataset, released today, has achieved a major milestone: More than 20,000 hours of open-source speech data that anyone, anywhere can use. The dataset has nearly doubled in the past year. Mozilla’s Common Voice seeks to change the language technology ecosystem by supporting communities to collect voice data for the creation of voice-enabled applications for their own languages. 
The post Common Voice dataset tops 20,000 hours appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Thermidor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[jq but using Go instead]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Q5Yy</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/hherman1/gq"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T14:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second jq alternative we’ve discovered this week! (first here)
jq is hard to use. There are alternatives like fq and zq, but they still make you learn a new programming language. Im tired of learning new programming languages.
gq is not optimized for speed, flexibility or beauty. gq is optimized for minimal learning/quick usage. gq understands that you don’t use it constantly, you use it once a month and then forget about it. So when you come back to it, gq will be easy to relearn. Just use the builtin library just like you would any other go project and you’re done. No unfamiliar syntax or operations, or surprising limits. Thats it.
I don’t know if Go is a great fit for this use-case, but if you already know it well… makes sense.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pure Stock Portfolio: a stock to sell]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/pure-stock-portfolio-a-stock-to-sell</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/pure-stock-portfolio-a-stock-to-sell"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T13:45:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A very bad earning report made me change the idea on the company]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Felix Krause put his "whole life" into a single database]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/zgyn</id>
        <link href="https://howisfelix.today/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T13:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I used scare quotes around “whole life” because those are his words and surely there’s a lot more to life than things you can quantify, but still: this is interesting
Back in 2019, I started collecting all kinds of metrics about my life. Every single day for the last 2.5 years I tracked over 100 different data types - ranging from fitness & nutrition to social life, computer usage and weather.
This data produces 44 graphs that are all shared publicly on the website.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MDN Plus now available in more markets]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47805</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/04/mdn-plus-now-available-in-more-markets/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T10:05:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost a month ago, we announced MDN Plus, a new premium service on MDN that allows users to customize their experience on the website.
We are very glad to announce today that it is now possible for MDN users around the globe to create an MDN Plus free account, no matter where they are.
The post MDN Plus now available in more markets appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hermina</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 50: Kaizen! We are flying ✈️]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1628</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/50"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is our 5th Kaizen where we talk about the next improvement to changelog.com: we are now running on fly.io and our PostgreSQL is managed. This is a migration that many were curious about, including Simey de Klerk, the person that requested this episode.
After migrating all our media files to AWS S3 (check episode 40), we thought that this part was going to be easy. Plan met reality. Pull request 407 has all the details.
We want to emphasise the type of partner relationships that we seek at Changelog & why they are important to us, as well as to our listeners. Honeycomb & Fly embody the principles that we care about, and Gerhard thinks that we are currently missing a Kubernetes partner.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ad…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we fought bad apps and developers in 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/04/how-we-fought-bad-apps-and-developers.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/04/how-we-fought-bad-apps-and-developers.html"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T16:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Steve Kafka and Khawaja Shams, Android Security and Privacy Team 
Providing a safe experience to billions of users continues to be one of the highest priorities for Google Play. Last year we introduced multiple privacy focused features, enhanced our protections against bad apps and developers, and improved SDK data safety. In addition, Google Play Protect continues to scan billions of installed apps each day across billions of devices to keep people safe from malware and unwanted software.  
  
We continue to enhance our machine learning systems and review processes, and in 2021 we blocked 1.2 million policy violating apps from being published on Google Play, preventing billions of harmful installations. We also continued in our efforts to combat malicious and spammy developers, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing zq: an easier (and faster) alternative to jq]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/YNYP</id>
        <link href="https://www.brimdata.io/blog/introducing-zq/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve found the (excellent) jq tool for working with JSON a bit unwieldy… check out zq and see if you like its API any better. I wouldn’t put too much weight on the faster aspect, though:
We will cover zq’s performance in a future article, but to cut to the chase here, zq is almost always at least a bit faster than jq when processing JSON inputs
Almost always at least a bit faster is not something you’re likely to notice in practice.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I can’t do on macOS which I can do on Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/o9Y8</id>
        <link href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/04/things-i-cant-do-on-macos-which-i-can-do-on-ubuntu/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T14:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A solid rant by Terence Eden, who has to use macOS for work but would rather not:
I know you’re going to be tempted to reply with “you’re using it wrong” - but I’m not. This is how I like to use my computer. And it is clear that the MacBook isn’t my computer - it is Apple’s. (OK, OK! It belongs to my employer!)
Some of his grievances like window snapping and moving/removing UI elements can be alleviated with 3rd-party solutions, but he’s not wrong that the operating system doesn’t provide these features.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Infinite Mac: an instant-booting Quadra in your browser]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/MdM6</id>
        <link href="https://blog.persistent.info/2022/03/blog-post.html"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T13:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mihai Parparita:
It’s a golden age of emulation. Between increasing CPU power, WebAssembly, and retrocomputing being so popular The New York Times is covering it, it’s never been easier to relive your 80s / 90s / 2000s nostalgia. Projects like v86 make it easy to run your chosen old operating system in the browser. My heritage being of the classic Mac line, I was curious what the easiest to use emulation option was in the modern era…
Here’s a video demo of what resulted: a full-featured classic 68K Mac in your browser.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl 7.83.0 headers bonanza]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18986</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/04/27/curl-7-83-0-headers-bonanza/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T06:28:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the third curl release of the year. Release presentation Numbers the 207th release6 changes53 days (total: 8,804)125 bug-fixes (total: 7,816)185 commits (total: 28,507)2 new public libcurl function (total: 88)0 new curl_easy_setopt() option (total: 295)2 new curl command line option (total: 247)60 contributors, 29 new (total: 2,626)35 authors, 13 new (total: 1,027)4 security fixes … Continue reading curl 7.83.0 headers bonanza →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Scientist x Machine Learning Engineer Roles: How are they different? How are they alike?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18264</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/data-scientist-machine-learning-engineer-roles-how-are-they-different-how-are-they-alike/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T22:05:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nubank's take on how these two roles interact and how each plays a key part in a successful team.
The post Data Scientist x Machine Learning Engineer Roles: How are they different? How are they alike? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felipe Almeida - Machine Learning Engineer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Scientist x Machine Learning Engineer Roles: How are they different? How are they alike?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18264</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/data-scientist-x-machine-learning-engineer-roles-how-are-they-different-how-are-they-alike/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T22:05:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nubank's take on how these two roles interact and how each plays a key part in a successful team.
The post Data Scientist x Machine Learning Engineer Roles: How are they different? How are they alike? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felipe Almeida - Machine Learning Engineer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution of ML Fact Store]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/5941d3231762</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/evolution-of-ml-fact-store-5941d3231762?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T20:44:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[by Vivek Kaushal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 487: Warp wants to be the terminal of the future]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1627</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/487"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we’re talking with Zach Lloyd, founder of Warp — the terminal being re-imagined for the 21st century and beyond. Warp is a blazingly fast, rust-based terminal that’s being designed from the ground up to work like a modern app. We get into all the details — why now is the right time to re-invent the terminal, where they got started, the business they aim to build around Warp, what it’s going to take to gain adoption and grow, but more importantly — what’s Warp like today to get developers excited and give it a try.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Desktop 3.0 brings better integration for your pull requests]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=64509</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-04-26-github-desktop-3-0-brings-better-integration-for-your-pull-requests/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T16:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Desktop 3.0 brings better integration with your GitHub Pull Requests. You can now receive real time notifications and review the status of your check runs for your pull request.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sergio Padrino</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 176: MLOps is NOT Real]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1640</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/176"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all hear a lot about MLOps these days, but where does MLOps end and DevOps begin? Our friend Luis from OctoML joins us in this episode to discuss treating AI/ML models as regular software components (once they are trained and ready for deployment). We get into topics including optimization on various kinds of hardware and deployment of models at the edge.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 0 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with extended episodes, make the ads disappear, and increment your audio quality with higher bitrate mp3s. Let’s do this!

    
Ship It! – A podcast about getting your best ideas into the world and seeing what happens. Listen to an episode that interests you and subscribe today.

    
Featuring
Luis Ceze – Twitter, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
OctoML
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The machine learning job market in 2022]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/RRYM</id>
        <link href="https://evjang.com/2022/04/25/rome.html"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T13:20:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Jang was recently on the job market (finally landing at [Halodi Robotics])(https://halodi.com/) and in this post he shares his process and view of the job market today. He also has some insights on where it’s headed. In brief:
In the future, every successful tech company will use their data moats to build some variant of an Artificial General Intelligence.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of free Tailwind CSS components]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/3Yj6</id>
        <link href="https://www.hyperui.dev/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T12:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And if you like Alpine, there’s a companion collection of snippets that you can copy/paste into your project.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>