<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-10-23T12:23:37.525Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring the impact of Twitter network latency with CausalImpact]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac"/>
        <updated>2022-10-22T12:22:27.968Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share how we adopted the CausalImpact package from Google on a Twitter edge network experiment to measure the impact of improving Twitter's latency on customer engagement and revenue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graph machine learning with missing node features]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/graph-machine-learning-with-missing-node-features</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/graph-machine-learning-with-missing-node-features"/>
        <updated>2022-10-22T12:22:27.840Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post discusses how feature propagation can be an efficient and scalable approach for handling missing features in graph machine learning applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 511: The terminal as a platform]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1854</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/511"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking with Will McGugan about using the terminal to not just build software, but also to deliver software. Will is a few months into his journey of building Textualize, a company he started around his open source projects Textual and Rich. When combined Textual and Rich give you a Python framework to build beautiful full-featured TUIs for the Terminal. We talk with Will about his big idea of the terminal as a platform, how he got here from first principles, what it takes to build Textual apps and whether or not they can replace not so good web admins, building, launching, and distributing Textual apps, why Python was his choiice of language, the big picture and business model behind Textualize, and why he’s building this as open source and in public.
Discuss on Changelog …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[8 tips to solve software engineering technical exercise for Nubank’s hiring process]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19592</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/tips-software-engineering-technical-exercise/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T20:11:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the steps in Nubank's software engineering recruiting process are the algorithm exercises. Check out how they work and get a few tips on how to do well on these tests.
The post 8 tips to solve software engineering technical exercise for Nubank’s hiring process appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaqueline Duque - Senior Software Engineer at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 248: Fake legs till you make legs]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1875</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/248"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What do Story of the Week, HeadLIES & Pro Tip Time have in common? They’re all games we play on this seriously ridiculous episode of JS Party!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 8 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn continuously about their applications - from the frontend to the backend. Use the code CHANGELOG and get the team plan free for three months.

    
Vercel – Vercel combines the best developer experience with an obsessive focus on end-user performance.  Our platform enables frontend teams to do their best work. Unlock a better frontend workflow today.

    
Fly.io – Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

    
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Amelia Wattenberger – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Story of the Week
The Future of the Web is on the Edge
Brave blocking annoying and privacy-harming cookie consent banners
Linear’s website temporarily replaced with a Figma file
HeadLIES
Apple’s Mixed Reality Headset to Offer Iris Scanning for Payments, Logging In
The US department of Veteran Affairs postpones rollout of electronic health record systems, developed by Oracle under a $50B contact, until 2030
Heroku reverses course, plans to reintroduce free plans after facing community backlash
Decentraland’s reported to have only has 38 Daily Active Users in their $1.3B Ecosystem
Meta Avatar Legs Demo ‘Created By Motion Capture’, Not Live VR
Pro Tip Time
Nick: How I use git worktrees
Jerod: Get a Pi-hole!
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How AI can help in the fight against breast cancer]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/health/how-ai-can-help-in-the-fight-against-breast-cancer/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/health/how-ai-can-help-in-the-fight-against-breast-cancer/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, there were 2.3 million people diagnosed with breast cancer and 685,000 deaths globally. Early cancer detection is key to better health outcomes. But screenings are work intensive, and patients often find getting mammograms and waiting for results stressful.
In response to these challenges, Google Health and Northwestern Medicine partnered in 2021 on a clinical research study to explore whether artificial intelligence (AI) models can reduce the time to diagnosis during the screening process, narrowing the assessment gap and improving the patient experience. This work is among the first prospective randomized controlled studies for AI in breast cancer screening, and the results will be published in early 2023.
Behind this work, are scientists and researchers united in the fight agai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Merge 2022 – that’s a wrap! 🎬]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67825</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-21-git-merge-2022-mission-report/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T16:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git Merge 2022 just wrapped up bringing the community together for 16 talks, three workshops, one Git Contributor Summit, and lots of great conversations over two days. Read on for more info, photos from the event, and all of the session recordings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why 37signals is leaving the cloud]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/2lRD</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/why-we-re-leaving-the-cloud-654b47e0"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T15:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TLDR: AWS is super-expensive at scale.
Of course it’s expensive to rent your computers from someone else. But it’s never presented in those terms. The cloud is sold as computing on demand, which sounds futuristic and cool, and very much not like something as mundane as “renting computers”, even though that’s mostly what it is.
But also:
It’s also about what kind of internet we want to operate in the future. It strikes me as downright tragic that this decentralized wonder of the world is now largely operating on computers owned by a handful of mega corporations. If one of the primary AWS regions go down, seemingly half the internet is offline along with it.
Methinks this will become even more of a trend in the coming months and years.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Focus is saying no to good ideas]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/O5Z7</id>
        <link href="https://commoncog.com/focus-saying-no-to-good-ideas/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is one of those pieces of advice that is easy to say, but hard to do. Cedric Chin:
The only problem with this advice is that it’s trite — it sounds obvious; people don’t take it seriously; it’s a cliché. But it really isn’t any of those things, not if you’re actually trying to put it to practice. One of the more interesting things about focus is that you can see it in good operators, if you know how to look. But it happens to also be really difficult to do.
Instead of articulating a fully-fleshed out theory of focus, I want to do something different here. I’m going to tell you a handful of stories. This should do more to illustrate the nature of focus in business than anything else that I can say. Let’s get started.
Some good stories follow. I’ll just add that good ideas is just one category of things that focus means saying “no” to. Another major category is good opportunities.
When you’re first getting started in your career, you are short on opportunities and long on time. But success breeds success. At a certain point, that relationship flips and you have more opportunities (actual, good ones) than you have time. Saying “no” to the wrong ones and “yes” to the right ones is another lesson in and of itself, but the same thing is in danger: your focus.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Things Right]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/making-things-right</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/making-things-right"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T13:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Did you know HackerOne has had a Make It Right fund for years?
Often, programs and hackers come to agreeable solutions on reports according to in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling data access by moving an exabyte of data to Google Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/scaling-data-access-by-moving-an-exabyte-of-data-to-google-cloud</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/scaling-data-access-by-moving-an-exabyte-of-data-to-google-cloud"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T12:26:58.375Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we approached migrating an exabyte of data to Google Cloud to make it easier for our Tweeps to analyze and visualize data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build a game this November with Game Off 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67943</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-21-build-a-game-this-november-with-game-off-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T07:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Save the date! Game Off returns on November 1 for it’s 10th year! 🎉]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unboxing fork improvements and unwrapping fork docs]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67990</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-20-unboxing-fork-improvements-and-unwrapping-fork-docs/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T18:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re always trying to improve the GitHub developer experience in meaningful ways, and we love learning from our customers. In the last several months we released several new fork capabilities, and we’re publishing revised fork documentation that gives more details with clearer explanations to make fork concepts easier to understand.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>allthedoll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 252: Who owns our code?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1809</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/252"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re joined by tech Lawyer Luis Villa to explore the question, who owns code? The company, the engineer, the team? What about when you’re using AI, Machine learning, GitHub Copilot… is that still your code?
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s business needs. Learn more at changelog.com/square to dive into the docs, APIs, SDKs and to create your Square Developer account — tell them Changelog sent you.

    
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service catalogs, respond to incidents, communicate through status pages, and learn with retrospectives. Small teams up to 10 people can get started for free with all FireHydrant features included. No credit card required to sign up. Learn more at firehydrant.com/

    
Honeycomb – Guess less, know more. When production is running slow, it’s hard to know where problems originate: is it your application code, users, or the underlying systems? With Honeycomb you get a fast, unified, and clear understanding of the one thing driving your business: production. Join the swarm and try Honeycomb free today at honeycomb.io/changelog

    
Featuring
Luis Villa – Twitter, LinkedIn, Website
Angelica Hill – Twitter, GitHub
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Tidelift
Luis’s new newsletter!
NYTimes review of Dennis Duncan’s “Index, A History of the”
The Berne Convention for the Protection of Literary and Artistic Works
Google LLC v. Oracle America, Inc.
Why Andy Warhol’s ‘Prince Series,’ the Subject of a Long-Term Copyright Dispute, Should Be Considered Fair Use After All
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving navigation for GitHub Actions]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67971</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-20-improving-navigation-for-github-actions/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Actions changed how developers automate workflows with GitHub. Today, we’re introducing a new navigation to manage your GitHub Actions experience, improving discoverability and accessibility as well as opening up future feature opportunities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amarilis Dias</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How trying new programming languages helped me grow as a software engineer]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/gwj6</id>
        <link href="https://cichocinski.dev/blog/trying-new-programming-languages-helped-grow-software-engineer"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T13:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tomasz Cichociński:
It’s completely fine to deepen one technology or one programming language knowledge. It’s totally fine to just have a 9-5 job that pays the bills. But if you aim to level up, I’m highly recommending trying something new to broaden your perspective.
If you’re writing JavaScript, try some functional language like Elixir or ReScript. If you’re already familiar with high level, garbage collected languages, try something low level like Rust or even C/C++. Play with different concurrency model like coroutines or actor model.
You don’t need to change your job, you don’t need to ship products with it. Try to create something fun. You’ll thank yourself later.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Investigation]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/6raZ</id>
        <link href="https://githubcopilotinvestigation.com/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T18:25:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is GitHub Copilot an AI parasite trained in the realms of fair use on pub­lic code any­where on the inter­net? Or, is it a much needed automation layer to all the reasons we open source in the first place?
When I first wrote about Copi­lot, I said “I’m not wor­ried about its effects on open source.” In the short term, I’m still not wor­ried. But as I reflected on my own jour­ney through open source—nearly 25 years—I real­ized that I was miss­ing the big­ger pic­ture. After all, open source isn’t a fixed group of peo­ple. It’s an ever-grow­ing, ever-chang­ing col­lec­tive intel­li­gence, con­tin­u­ally being renewed by fresh minds. We set new stan­dards and chal­lenges for each other, and thereby raise our expec­ta­tions for what we can accom­plish.
Amidst this grand alchemy, Copi­lot inter­lopes. Its goal is to arro­gate the energy of open-source to itself. We needn’t delve into Microsoft’s very check­ered his­tory with open source to see Copi­lot for what it is: a par­a­site.
The legal­ity of Copi­lot must be tested before the dam­age to open source becomes irrepara­ble. That’s why I’m suit­ing up.
What are your thoughts on this investigation and “poten­tial law­suit” against GitHub Copi­lot?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 75: How vex.dev runs on AWS, Fly.io & GCP]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1703</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/75"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Few genuinely need a multi-cloud setup. There is plenty of advice out there which mostly boils down to don’t do it, you will be worse off. Vex.dev is a startup that provides APIs for video and audio streaming. The hard part is real-time combined with massive scale - think hundreds of thousands of concurrent connections. They achieve this by using a combination of Fly.io, AWS and GCP. Jason Carter, founder of Vex Communications, is joining us today to talk about the multi-cloud setup that vex.dev runs.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service ca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arbitrary deadlines are actually awesome]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/posts/2550</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/posts/arbitrary-deadlines-are-actually-awesome"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T18:05:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After reading Lucas da Costa’s Why deadlines are pointless and what to do instead, I agree with almost every point he makes, especially this one:
It’s about time we start calling deadlines by their real name: pressure
Lucas goes on to describe how deadlines can cause harm, can’t actually make people code faster, and so on. I agree with that too. But does that make them pointless? Not necessarily!
Sometimes a little pressure is just what the doctor ordered. Here’s what I mean by that.
Note: Lucas’s article is written to software teams that are dedicated to a single product. This post is to a slightly different audience: those of us with many disparate things we could be working on at any given time. For that reason, I don’t believe his take on Parkinson’s Law  applies in this context. If yo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why three Availability Zones are better than two]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/zDG3</id>
        <link href="https://shekhargulati.com/2022/10/06/why-an-architecture-with-three-availability-zones-is-better-than-the-one-with-two-availability-zones/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T16:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is just not about redundancy. In this post I cover how having more AZs mean you need fewer nodes to achieve higher availability.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shekhar Gulati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When life gives you lemons, write better error messages]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/5j98</id>
        <link href="https://scribe.rip/when-life-gives-you-lemons-write-better-error-messages-46c5223e1a2f"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T15:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an excellent deep-dive on error message best practices by Jenni Nadler from Wix:
Error messages are part of our daily lives online. Every time a server is down or we don’t have internet, or we forget to add some info in a form, we get an error message. “Something went wrong” is the classic. But what went wrong? What happened? And, most importantly, how can I fix it?

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funded curl improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20153</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/10/19/funded-curl-improvements/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T06:59:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am happy to announce that curl receives funding from The Sovereign Tech Fund. This funding is directed towards three specific projects that we have identified as interesting and worthwhile to push forward as ways to improve curl and the life of curl users. This “investment” will fund two developers to work on curl over … Continue reading Funded curl improvements →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Rust?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/LWJa</id>
        <link href="https://www.rerun.io/blog/why-rust"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T21:17:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rust is quite popular, but why? Emil Ernerfeldt, CTO of rerun.io, shares his thoughts in the subject.
I believe Rust is the most important development in system programming languages since C. What is novel is not any individual feature (“Rust is not a particularly original language”), but the fact that so many amazing features have come together in one mainstream language.
Rust is not a perfect language (scroll down for my complaints!), but it’s so much nicer than anything else I’ve used.
I’m not alone in loving Rust - Rust has been the most loved language in the Stack Overflow Developer Survey for seven years straight. So what are the features that make me love Rust so much?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchestrating Data/ML Workflows at Scale With Netflix Maestro]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/aaa2b41b800c</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/orchestrating-data-ml-workflows-at-scale-with-netflix-maestro-aaa2b41b800c?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T20:43:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[by Jun He, Akash Dwivedi, Natallia Dzenisenka, Snehal Chennuru, Praneeth Yenugutala, Pawan Dixit]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git security vulnerabilities announced]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67904</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-18-git-security-vulnerabilities-announced/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T17:11:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade your local installation of Git, especially when cloning with --recurse-submodules from untrusted repositories, or if you use git shell interactive mode.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taylor Blau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backstage 25: Should we get down with OP3?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/12/1880</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/backstage/25"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T17:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Open Podcast Prefix Project is a free and open source podcast prefix analytics service committed to open data and listener privacy. This hits close to home for us in a couple ways, so we invited the project’s creator, John Spurlock, Backstage to learn more about it.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
John Spurlock – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Adam Stacoviak – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
op3.dev
Livewire.io
The Podcast Index
podcastindex.social
The new podcast namespace
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go performance case studies]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/7Ya2</id>
        <link href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2022-10-14-golang-performance-case-studies/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T15:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zach Musgrave from Dolt reviews several case studies of performance problems they ran into while benchmarking Dolt DB to get row access to be as fast as MySQL.
Oh, and he also shares how to fix each problem, which is nice. 😉
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing fine-grained personal access tokens for GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67900</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-18-introducing-fine-grained-personal-access-tokens-for-github/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T15:35:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fine-grained personal access tokens offer enhanced security to developers and organization owners, to reduce the risk to your data of compromised tokens.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hirsch Singhal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting the Mediation Team at H1-702]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/meeting-mediation-team-h1-702</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/meeting-mediation-team-h1-702"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T15:28:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello world, we are the Mediation Team.
For those who don’t know what we do - we are here to help the ethical hacking community and custome]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python CLI tricks that don't require any code whatsoever]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Mby0</id>
        <link href="https://martinheinz.dev/blog/83"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T14:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out-of-the-box, the Python standard library ships with many great libraries, some of which provide CLIs, allowing us to do many cool things directly from terminal without needing to even open a .py file.
This includes things like starting a webserver, opening a browser, parsing JSON files, benchmarking programs and many more, all of which we will explore in this article.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Heinz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 197: Data for All]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1878</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/197"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T14:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People are starting to wake up to the fact that they have control and ownership over their data, and governments are moving quickly to legislate these rights. John K. Thomson has written a new book on the topic that is a must read! We talk about the new book in this episode along with how practitioners should be thinking about data exchanges, privacy, trust, and synthetic data.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
John K. Thompson – Twitter, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Use the code podpracticalAI19 for 40% off of Data for All, along with all Manning products in all formats!!!
Data for All
John’s other books:

Analytics Teams: Harnessing analytics and artificial intelligence for business improvement
Analytics: How to win with Intelligence
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deviating from specs]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20422</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/10/18/deviating-from-specs/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T12:19:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[tldr: we do not particular keep track nor document curl’s exact spec compliance. I cannot fathom how we could. Today, in October 2022, curl and libcurl combined consist of nearly 150,000 lines of source code (not counting blank lines). 19% of those are comments. This source code pile was carefully crafted with the sole purpose … Continue reading Deviating from specs →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News: Harmonai revisited, lessons learned from public salary, Open Core Ventures, Stripe is Paypal in 2010 & Helix]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1879</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/news-2022-10-17"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We revisit our Harmonai story from last week, Jamie Tanna reviews posting his salary history publicly, Sid Sijbrandij’s new (open core) venture fund, Zed Shaw thinks Stripe is like Paypal in 2010 & Helix is a new Rust-based terminal.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Zach Evans on Twitter
Lessons learned since posting my salary history publicly
Open Core Ventures
Stripe is Paypal circa 2010
Helix Editor (pic)
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to build software like an SRE]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Y1lV</id>
        <link href="https://www.willett.io/posts/precepts/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T19:02:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is awesome — Brandon, please write down more lessons as learned, even if they’re just something for you to reference later on.
I’ve been doing this “reliability” stuff for a little while now (~5 years), at companies ranging from about 20 developers to over 2,000. I’ve always cared primarily about the software elements I describe as living “outside” the application – like, how does it get its configuration? What kinds of instances does it run on, and are those the best kinds to use? What steps does it take on its path from “code in a repository” to “running in production”? And I’ve always kept track of what I liked – which mechanisms allowed fast iteration and which caused frustration, which led to outages and which prevented them.
… So! With that out of the way – this is how I’d rebuild it all from scratch if I could.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clojure 15th Anniversary: A Retrospective]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19498</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/clojure-15th-anniversary-a-retrospective/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T18:25:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clojure’s history is beautiful and simple in code. Nubank has a lot of reasons to say: happy birthday, Clojure!
The post Clojure 15th Anniversary: A Retrospective appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Georgia Anunciação - Technical Writer at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub at the 77th United Nations General Assembly]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67882</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-17-github-at-the-77th-united-nations-general-assembly/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T17:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read about how the GitHub Social Impact, Tech for Social Good and Policy teams participated in the 77th session of the United Nations General Assembly, including events we hosted with the World Health Organization and the UN Development Programme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mala Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The UNIX Pipe Card Game]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/rX3n</id>
        <link href="https://punkx.org/unix-pipe-game/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T16:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An actual card game to teach actual kids how to actually combine unix commands with pipes.
task: print the most common line from a file, we need to first cat the file (in our case the file is card 03.txt), then sort it, uniq count it, then do numeric sort, then tail -1:
answer: cat 03.txt | sort | uniq -c | sort -n | tail -1
Print it yourself or… actually it’s sold out for now so you’ll have to print it yourself.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CRUD framework for full stack TypeScript]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/AXnQ</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/remult/remult"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Full-stack web development is (still) too complicated. Simple CRUD, a common requirement of any business application, should be simple to build, maintain, and extend when the need arises.
Remult is a full-stack CRUD framework that uses your TypeScript entities as a single source of truth for your API, frontend type-safe API client and backend ORM.
This isn’t just production-ready, it’s been used in production since 2018.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 tips for embedding security into your workflows]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67859</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-17-5-tips-for-embedding-security-into-your-workflows/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T15:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having a robust security plan is key to innovation. These tips will empower you to gain the upper hand on cyberattacks, so you can ship quickly and innovate with ease.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Paine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connect VisiData to SQL Databases with vdsql]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/RdWw</id>
        <link href="https://www.visidata.org/blog/2022/connect-visidata-to-sql-databases-with-vdsql/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T14:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[vdsql is a new plugin that allows VisiData to connect to databases and query them directly, using the database’s own query engine.  It uses Ibis to generate SQL for many popular backends, including Postgres, DuckDB, Clickhouse, and more.
vdsql v0.2, released this past week, is already quite useful, and development continues to improve both vdsql and VisiData for bigger data!
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saul Pwanson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Powering real-time data analytics with Druid at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/powering-real-time-data-analytics-with-druid-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/powering-real-time-data-analytics-with-druid-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2022-10-16T12:22:09.700Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share an overview of Twitter’s Druid ecosystem and discuss our work towards a unified ingestion experience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Quality Automation at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2022-10-16T12:22:09.681Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we share how Twitter implemented a Data Quality Platform that gave customers the ability to have automated data quality checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and scalability for search]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search"/>
        <updated>2022-10-15T12:22:17.516Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we power real-time search for Tweets, Users, Direct Messages and more using Elasticsearch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 247: Docusaurus 2 is a pretty big deal]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1825</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/247"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Docusaurus maintainer Sébastien Lorber joins Jerod & Amal for a deep-dive on everybody’s favorite documentation generator. It’s back with a big 2.0 release, boasts some big users, and has a big set of new features such as document versioning, a plugin architecture, and more.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 6 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make sure you are quickly notified of the errors, crashes, and front-end performance issues that matter most to you and your business. Set thresholds for your alert based on an increase in error count, a spike in load time, or new issues introduced in the latest deployment. Start your free 14-day trial at Raygun.com

    
Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelog

    
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
Featuring
Sébastien Lorber – Twitter, GitHub
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Docusaurus
The showcase
docusaurus.new
This Week in React
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is it like to be an UX Researcher at Nubank?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19483</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/ux-researcher-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T16:52:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UX Researcher helps the design and business teams to learn from our clients, and uses this data and knowledge to design the best products.
The post What is it like to be an UX Researcher at Nubank? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tutz Dias - Senior UX Research at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 510: Taking Postgres serverless]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1851</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/510"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking about serverless Postgres! We’re joined by Nikita Shamgunov, co-founder and CEO of Neon. With Neon, truly serverless PostgreSQL is finally here. Neon isn’t Postgres compatible…it actually is Postgres! Neon is also open source under the Apache License 2.0.
We talk about what a cloud native serverless Postgres looks like, why developers want Postgres and why of the top 5 databases only Postgres is growing (according to DB-Engines Ranking), we talk about how they separated storage and compute to offer autoscaling, branching, and bottomless storage, we also talk about their focus on DX — where they’re getting it right and where they need to improve. Neon is invite only as of the recording and release of this episode, but near the end of the show Nikita shares a few ways…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSI’s Deep Dive is an essential discussion on the future of AI and open source]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67815</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-14-osis-deep-dive-is-an-essential-discussion-on-the-future-of-ai-and-open-source/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T16:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub is sponsoring Open Source Initiative’s Deep Dive: AI because we think it’s important for the community to unpack how open source software, process, and principles can help best deliver on the promise of AI.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Linksvayer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewriting curl in three days]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20379</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/10/14/rewriting-curl-in-three-days/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T11:52:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To celebrate the hubris-infested comment from a few years ago, I created this book cover mock up. Turned out very popular on Twitter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There is a tab in my cookie]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20387</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/10/14/there-is-a-tab-in-my-cookie/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T08:06:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An HTTP cookie, is just a name + value pair sent from the server to the client. That pair is stored and is sent back to the server in subsequent requests when conditions match. Cookies were first invented and used in the 1990s. Sources seem to agree that the first browser to support them, was … Continue reading There is a tab in my cookie →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking authentication UX]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/kwyY</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/authentication-ux-design-guidelines/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T20:57:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Mag’s Vitaly Friedman puts down some of his recent thoughts on authentication flows:
nobody wakes up in the morning hoping to finally identify crosswalks and fire hydrants that day. Yet every day, we prompt users through hoops and loops to sign up and log in, to set a complex enough password or recover one, to find a way to restore access to locked accounts and logged-out sessions.
Of course security matters, yet too often, it gets in the way of usability. As Jared Spool said once, “If a product isn’t usable, it’s also not secure.” That’s when people start using private email accounts and put passwords on stick-it-notes because they forget them. As usual, Jared hits the nail on the head here. So what can we do to improve the authentication UX?
Vitaly lists seven recommendations. Nothing radical here, but solid advice worth thinking through.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing GitHub Advanced Security SIEM integrations for security professionals]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67795</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-13-introducing-github-advanced-security-siem-integrations-for-security-professionals/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T19:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about using GitHub Advanced Security (GHAS) alerts with Security Information and Events Management (SIEM) tools. Check out the integrations, and read more about getting started.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Shanahan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 251: Hacking with Go: Part 2]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1832</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/251"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re once again exploring hacking in Go from the eyes of security researchers. This time, Natalie & Ian are joined by Ivan Kwiatkowski (a.k.a. Justice Rage)!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service catalogs, respond to incidents, communicate through status pages, and learn with retrospectives. Small teams up to 10 people can get started for free with all FireHydrant features included. No credit card required to sign up. Learn more at firehydrant.com/

    
Honeycomb – Guess less, know more. When production is running slow, it’s hard to know where problems originate: is it your application code, users, or the underlying systems? With Honeycomb you get a fast, unified, and clear understanding of the one thing driving your business: production. Join the swarm and try Honeycomb free today at honeycomb.io/changelog

    
Featuring
Ivan Kwiatkowski – Twitter, GitHub
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Ian Lopshire – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
🎧 Hacking with Go: Part 1
Reversing in action: Golang malware used in the SolarWinds attack
Stowaway
Brute Ratel
Reverse Engineering for Beginners
Practical Malware Analysis
Turing Complete on Steam
The Zachtronics Puzzle Pack on Steam
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing HackerOne Assets]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/introducing-hackerone-assets</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-management/introducing-hackerone-assets"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding where the critical flaws lie within your organization's attack surface is critical—but complicated. After all, your attack surface includes your infrastructure, network, software, applications, devices, and the extended supply chain. But it doesn’t stop there. Digital transformation, cloud adoption, the shift to remote work, mergers and acquisitions (M&A), and shadow IT further muddy the waters for today’s security leaders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Naz Bozdemir</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corb3nik Introduces His Tool: Caido]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/corb3nik-introduces-his-tool-caido</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/corb3nik-introduces-his-tool-caido"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T15:38:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, who is Corb3nik?
My name is Ian, also known as Corb3nik on social media. I’m a long time CTF enthusiast and bug bounty hunter. Currentl]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jesse@hackerone.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story of Scalar]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67767</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-13-the-story-of-scalar/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T15:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New to Git v2.38, Scalar is a built-in repository manager for large repos. Here, we’ll tell the story of how Scalar went from a rough VFS for Git successor to a fully-integrated Git tool, with all of the engineering lessons learned in the process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Derrick Stolee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The myth of mass collaboration]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/X1Rd</id>
        <link href="https://staltz.com/the-myth-of-mass-collaboration.html"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[André Staltz:
I used to believe there was mass collaboration on the internet. But I’ve realized that collaboration is extremely hard. It does not scale, especially not at internet scale. The examples we look up to are either not collaborative on the microscopic level, or are rare exceptions to the rule.
The examples he’s referring to are “Wikipedia, open source projects such as Linux, hacktivism, and crowdsourced science experiments such as Rosetta@home.”
This post is sobering, but André speaks from a lot of experience.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 74: Vorsprung durch Technik]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1838</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/74"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t think that you can imagine just how excited Gerhard was to find out that Audi, his favourite car company, has a Kubernetes competence centre. We have Sebastian Kister joining us today to tell us why people, followed by tech make the process.
The right thing to focus on is the genuine smiles that people give in response to something we do or say. That is an important SLI & SLO for reducing friction between silos.
How does this impact the flow of artefacts into production systems that design & build cars?
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make su…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Product Teams Can Build Empathy Through Experimentation]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/6253603880a6</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/how-product-teams-can-build-empathy-through-experimentation-6253603880a6?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T20:56:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A conversation between Travis Brooks, Netflix Product Manager for Experimentation Platform, and George Khachatryan, OfferFit CEO]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How  AI is helping African communities and businesses]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/how-ai-is-helping-african-communities-and-businesses/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/how-ai-is-helping-african-communities-and-businesses/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor’s note: Last week Google hosted the annual Google For Africa eventas part of our commitment to make the internet more useful in Africa, and to support the communities and businesses that will power Africa’s economic growth. This commitment includes our investment in research. Since announcing the Google AI Research Center in Accra, Ghanain 2018, we have made great strides in our mission to use AI for societal impact. In May we made several exciting announcements aimed at expanding these commitments.
Yossi Matias, VP of Engineering and Research, who oversees research in Africa, spoke with Jeff Dean, SVP of Google Research, who championed the opening of the AI Research Center, about the potential of AI in Africa.
Jeff: It's remarkable how far we've come since we opened the center in A…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In praise of ffmpeg]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/lOVn</id>
        <link href="https://drewdevault.com/2022/10/12/In-praise-of-ffmpeg.html"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T15:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ffmpeg is one of the foremost pillars of achievement in free software. It has touched the lives of every reader, whether they know it or not. If you’ve ever watched TV, or gone to a movie, or watched videos online, or listened to a podcast, odds are that ffmpeg was involved in making it possible. It is one of the most well-executed and important software projects of all time.
Yep. It also has one of the most epic man pages in the ’Verse.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 196: What's up, DocQuery?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1872</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/196"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chris sits down with Ankur Goyal to talk about DocQuery, Impira’s new open source ML model.  DocQuery lets you ask questions about semi-structured data (like invoices) and unstructured documents (like contracts) using Large Language Models (LLMs).  Ankur illustrates many of the ways DocQuery can help people tame documents, and references Chris’s real life tasks as a non-profit director to demonstrate that DocQuery is indeed practical AI.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Ankur Goyal – Twitter, LinkedIn
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Notes and Links
DocQuery
DocQuery Announcement
DocQuery Blog Announcement
DocQuery | GitHub
Impira
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave plans to start blocking cookie consent banners]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/04ro</id>
        <link href="https://brave.com/privacy-updates/21-blocking-cookie-notices/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T14:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New versions of Brave will hide—and, where possible, completely block—cookie consent notifications. Brave’s approach is distinct and more privacy-preserving than similar systems used in other browsers (such as the “auto-consent” systems used in other browsers), and helps keep the Web user-first.
Unlike other approaches, this won’t simply automate the process of clicking “no” in cookie-banners, Brave will block the cookie-banners themselves.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reconsidering Tweets]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/reconsidering-tweets</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/reconsidering-tweets"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T12:25:35.704Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share findings from a follow-up analysis in which we seek to understand how prompts cause people to reconsider potentially harmful or offensive content before they hit send.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Security of Passkeys in the Google Password Manager]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/10/SecurityofPasskeysintheGooglePasswordManager.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/10/SecurityofPasskeysintheGooglePasswordManager.html"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Arnar Birgisson, Software Engineer


We are excited to announce passkey support on Android and Chrome for developers to test today, with general availability following later this year. In this post we cover details on how passkeys stored in the Google Password Manager are kept secure. See our post on the Android Developers Blog for a more general overview.
Passkeys are a safer and more secure alternative to passwords. They also replace the need for traditional 2nd factor authentication methods such as text message, app based one-time codes or push-based approvals. Passkeys use public-key cryptography so that data breaches of service providers don't result in a compromise of passkey-protected accounts, and are based on industry standard APIs and protocols to ensure they are not su…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Universe 2022 agenda is live]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67730</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-11-the-github-universe-2022-agenda-is-live/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T19:39:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore 80+ content sessions delivered by over 120 different speakers, across two days and four content tracks, all designed to level up your skills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Lindeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lessons learned since posting my salary history publicly]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ZoZj</id>
        <link href="https://www.jvt.me/posts/2022/09/21/year-later-salary-history/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T19:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just over a year ago, I did something quite “out there”, even for me, and I posted my salary history publicly. This was accompanied by a blog post to explain why I was doing it, and it’s certainly been popular.
When I first posted it, I made a note to myself to come back in a year, and see whether anything had changed, as well as to look back on some of the events that happened immediately after my posting, as it certainly made life interesting in the month or so following the post.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Tanna</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[View GitHub code scanning findings directly in VS Code and GitHub Codespaces]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67648</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-11-view-github-code-scanning-findings-directly-in-vs-code-and-github-codespaces/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T19:10:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers can now view GitHub code scanning findings directly in VS Code and GitHub Codespaces. The new Microsoft SARIF Viewer extension gives developers direct access to their code scanning results, making remediating vulnerabilities easier than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brittany O'Shea</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Python package to make publication-ready but customizable forest plots]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/04dD</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/lsys/forestplot"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T18:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[R has many such packages. In Python, not so much. This one is designed to be easy to use while being customizable (some examples in the README).

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucas Shen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re using machine learning to understand proteins]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/health/machine-learning-to-understand-proteins/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/health/machine-learning-to-understand-proteins/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When most people think of proteins, their mind typically goes to protein-rich foods such as steak or tofu. But proteins are so much more. They’re essential to how living things operate and thrive, and studying them can help improve lives. For example, insulin treatments are life-changing for people with diabetes that are based on years of studying proteins.
There is a world of information yet to discover when it comes to proteins — from helping people get the healthcare they need to finding ways to protect plant species. Teams at Google are focused on studying proteins so we can realize Google Health’s mission to help billions of people live healthier lives.
Back in March, we published apost about a model we developed at Google that predicts protein function and a tool that allows scientis…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A React library for building dashboards fast]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/LWVa</id>
        <link href="https://www.tremor.so/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T18:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This looks like top notch work:
Get more than 20 components with beautiful defaults and simple props. From charts to input and layout elements, we covered all the essential components to lift the tedious front-end work from your shoulders. Get ahead with our simple API approach in no time.
Check out their demo dashboard right here.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 7 and Pixel 7 Pro: The next evolution in mobile security]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/10/google-pixel-7-and-pixel-7-pro-next.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/10/google-pixel-7-and-pixel-7-pro-next.html"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T17:01:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dave Kleidermacher, Jesse Seed, Brandon Barbello, Sherif Hanna, Eugene Liderman, Android, Pixel, and Silicon Security Teams 
Every day, billions of people around the world trust Google products to enrich their lives and provide helpful features –  across mobile devices, smart home devices, health and fitness devices, and more. We keep more people safe online than anyone else in the world, with products that are secure by default, private by design and that put you in control. As our advancements in knowledge and computing grow to deliver more help across contexts, locations and languages, our unwavering commitment to protecting your information remains. 
That’s why Pixel phones are designed from the ground up to help protect you and your sensitive data while keeping you in control. We’re t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the go with GitHub Projects on GitHub Mobile (public beta)]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67715</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-11-on-the-go-with-github-projects-on-github-mobile-public-beta/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T16:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stay connected and up to date on your work with GitHub Projects on GitHub Mobile, now in public beta.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Candy Ho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thank You to the Hacker Community, From HackerOne]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/ethical-hacker/thank-you-hacker-community-hackerone</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/ethical-hacker/thank-you-hacker-community-hackerone"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I joined HackerOne last year, the vitality of the hacker community drew me to this organization. And as Chief Hacking Officer, I see the impact t]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok Celebrates Two Years of Bug Bounty]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/bounty/tiktok-celebrates-two-years-bug-bounty</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/bounty/tiktok-celebrates-two-years-bug-bounty"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok, a social media giant with more than 1 billion active monthly users, understands the importance of a global community, be that community TikTokers or ethical hackers!  In 2020, TikTok launched its public bug bounty program on HackerOne. In the two years since, they’ve taken many steps to maintain a partnership with the global hacker community that’s rewarding and inviting.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How mapping the world’s buildings makes a difference]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/how-mapping-the-worlds-buildings-makes-a-difference/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/how-mapping-the-worlds-buildings-makes-a-difference/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Lamwo district, in northern Uganda, providing access to electricity is a challenge. In a country where only about 24% of the population has a power supply to their home from the national grid, the rate in Lamwo is even lower. This is partly due to lack of information: The government doesn’t have precise data about where settlements are located, what types of buildings there are, and what the buildings’ electricity needs might be. And canvassing the area isn’t practical, because the roads require four-wheel-drive vehicles and are impassable in the rain.
Ernest Mwebaze leads Sunbird AI, a Ugandan nonprofit that uses data technology for social good. They’re assessing areas in Lamwo district to support planning at the Ministry of Energy in Uganda. “There are large areas to plan for,” explai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development speed over everything]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/dev-speed/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/dev-speed/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lest we stagnate]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News: Forking SQLite, generative AI for music, saying no to sprints, awesome diagramming tools & state machine facts]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1871</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/news-2022-10-10"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The libSQL community is forking SQLite, StabilityAI announces Haromai and Dance Diffusion, Robin Rendle doesn’t believe in sprints, Shubham Garg curates some awesome diagramming tools & Chris Pressey writes up some must-read facts about state machines.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Unpopular Opinion Twitter Thread
libSQL is a fork of SQLite
StabilityAI announced AI Music Generator Harmonai
I Don’t Believe in Sprints
Awesome Diagramming
Facts About State Machines
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting global mental health needs, with technology's help]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/world-mental-health-day-2022/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/world-mental-health-day-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates that nearly 1 billion people are living with a mental disorder, worldwide. During the global pandemic, the world saw a 25% increase in the prevalence of anxiety and depression. There was even a corresponding spike in searches on Google for mental health resources — which is a trend that continues to climb each year. To help people connect with timely, life-saving information and resources and to empower them to take action on their mental health needs, teams of Googlers are working — inside and outside of the company — to make sure everyone has access to mental health support.


Connecting people to resources on Search and YouTube
Before we can connect people to timely information and resources, we need to understand their intent when they turn…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use SQL to instantly query your cloud services]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/V10P</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/turbot/steampipe"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T15:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This lets you do so many cool things, even joining across disparate services:
select
  aws.name aws_user_name,
  slack.id as slack_user_id,
  slack.display_name as slack_name
from
  aws_iam_user as aws,
  slack_user as slack
where
  aws.name = slack.email;

+--------------------------+---------------+------------+
|     aws_user_name        | slack_user_id | slack_name |
+--------------------------+---------------+------------+
| dwight@dundermifflin.com | U2EMB8HLP     | dwight     |
| jim@dundermifflin.com    | U02HE4Z7E     | jim        |
+--------------------------+---------------+------------+

Useful for compliance, security, ops, and cost management.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving Firefox responsiveness on macOS]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47924</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/10/improving-firefox-responsiveness-on-macos/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T15:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're running Firefox on macOS you might have noticed that its responsiveness has improved significantly in version 103, especially if you've got a lot of tabs, or when your machine is busy running other applications at the same time. This improvement was achieved via a small change in how locking is implemented within Firefox's memory allocator.
The post Improving Firefox responsiveness on macOS appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriele Svelto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stripe is Paypal circa 2010]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/y7GA</id>
        <link href="https://learnjsthehardway.com/blog/18-stripe-is-paypal-circa-2010/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T14:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A journey from Stripe to Paypal and back to Stripe led Zed Shaw to the conclusion in the headline. And, no, that is not a compliment (in case you weren’t sure).
Zed goes deep on why he feels this way, listing seven serious downsides to using Stripe today. What’s a dev to do? His advice at the end alone is worth the cost of admission:
This is why I advocate to people to be ready to switch payment processing at a moment’s notice. Right now I could flip two options and I’d be back on Paypal. If I was pressed I could probably implement any other payment processor in about a week or a day. The ability to quickly switch payments is your only defense against frozen accounts, fraud, and rogue employees.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is it like being a Business Analyst at Nubank?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19326</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/business-analyst-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T21:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Business Analysts are people passionate about immersing themselves into numbers and helping define the company's next steps. Find out about the daily routine of this career in this article.
The post What is it like being a Business Analyst at Nubank? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel Assis - Business Analytics Manager at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 509: A new batch of web frameworks emerge!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1870</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/509"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re talking fresh, faster, and new web frameworks by way of JS Party. Yes, today’s show is a web framework sampler because a new batch of web frameworks have emerged. There’s always something new happening in the front-end world and JS Party does an amazing job of keeping us up to date. So…what’s fresh, faster, and new?
The first segment of the show focuses on Deno’s Fresh new web framework. Luca Casonato joins Jerod & Feross to talk about Fresh – a next generation web framework, built for speed, reliability, and simplicity.
In segment two, AngularJS creator Miško Hevery joins Jerod and KBall to talk about Qwik. He says Qwik is a fundamental rethinking of how a web application should work. And he’s attempting to convince Jerod & KBall that the implications of that are BIG.
In t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 246: 7 pounds of news in a 5 pound bag]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1862</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/246"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hang with Jerod, Nick & KBall while we discuss what’s new & noteworthy in the web world. Cloudflare Turnstile, Linkify 4.0, TC39 updates, the Figma acquisition, Penpot, pay transparency, and more! We might even discuss TypeScript if Nick gets his way…
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 16 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make sure you are quickly notified of the errors, crashes, and front-end performance issues that matter most to you and your business. Set thresholds for your alert based on an increase in error count, a spike in load time, or new issues introduced in the latest deployment. S…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mastodon.technology is shutting down]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/qMbp</id>
        <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-technology-shutdown/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T16:22:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After more than half a decade (6+ years), Mastodon.technology is shutting down. The reason? One person is responsible (Ash Furrow) and they’ve hit their limit personally and technically.
A member of my family was very recently diagnosed with a terminal illness. I am doing everything I can to support them.
Last week, with yet more Elon Musk and Twitter news, the fediverse generally experienced extra traffic with an influx of new users. I woke up to mastodon.technology downtime alerts. In the midst of supporting my family, I had to ssh into a server and fiddle with settings.
I am exhausted.
The server has also gotten too large and too complex for me to administer. I’ve always been keen to learn the next new skill I need to be an effective admin. But I just don’t have it in me anymore. The monitoring that I have in place is insufficient to solve the current problems and I have zero bandwidth to invest in learning the skills to diagnose and fix the issue.
Ages ago (4 years) we talked with Eugen Rochko on The Changelog (the creator of Mastodon) about the “absolute freedom in how people can run their servers,”  and how the “incentives are usually ideological” when running a Mastodon server.
Yes, we talked about the costs of running a server, but from my recollection that seemed to be purely from a monetary perspective. The costs of running a server are also quite time intensive and those costs needs to be factored in as well.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take advantage of git rebase]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ZodW</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2022/10/06/take-advantage-of-git-rebase/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T15:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a solid primer on git rebase and the many ways it’s useful.
In Git, a rebase is a very versatile and useful tool to rework commits. Use it to achieve a workflow with high-quality changes proposed in high-quality commits and merge requests. It makes your developers and reviewers more efficient. Code reviews and debugging also become easier and more effective.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 250: Mat's GopherCon EU diary]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1863</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/250"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join Mat Ryer on his journey to Berlin for GopherCon EU 2022. Along the way he chats with Egon Elbre, Ale Kennedy, Ole Bulbuk, Christian Haas, Bill Kennedy & Ron Evans. Danke!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s business needs. Learn more at changelog.com/square to dive into the docs, APIs, SDKs and to create your Square Developer account — tell them Changelog sent you.

    
Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelog

    
Featuring
Egon Elbre – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Ale Kennedy – Twitter
Ole Bulbuk – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Christian Haas – Twitter, GitHub
Bill Kennedy – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Ron Evans – Twitter, GitHub
Mat Ryer – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Notes and Links
GopherCon EU
Gophers Say! GopherCon EU Edition
TinyGo
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developers are now included in the WIPO Global Innovation Index]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67632</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-06-developers-are-now-included-in-the-wipo-global-innovation-index/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T21:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited that the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO) has launched the 2022 edition of its Global Innovation Index (GII) with an indicator of developer creative outputs based on GitHub commits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Cihon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub’s supply chain security features now support Dart]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67596</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-06-githubs-supply-chain-security-features-now-support-dart/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T18:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-platform apps built with the popular Flutter toolkit can now benefit from Dependabot alerts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Tooley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dreamfusion! Text-to-3D model powered by Stable Diffusion]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Qpbd</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/ashawkey/stable-dreamfusion"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T17:10:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This working implementation of text-to-3D (powered by Stable Diffusion) didn’t take six months, like Simon predicted it would. Although I will concede that it’s not a 3D environment that can then go into in a game engine, but I’m sure that’s just a few more weeks away this point.
From the readme:
This project is a work-in-progress, and contains lots of differences from the paper. Also, many features are still not implemented now. The current generation quality cannot match the results from the original paper, and many prompts still fail badly!
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 73: A modern bank infrastructure]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1795</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/73"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matias Pan is a Staff Software Engineer at Lemon Cash, a crypto startup based in Argentina. Lemon infrastructure runs digital wallets & physical cards, which technically makes them a bank. How does Matias & his team think about enabling developers get code from their workstations into production? Remember, we are talking about a bank - a bad deploy is a big deal. And when a bad database migration goes out, what happens then?
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CLI to share files directly with iOS and Android devices]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/8lrO</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/parvardegr/sharing"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T13:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[run npm install -g easy-sharing
run sharing /directory-or-file-to-share
scan the QR code with your phone

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Twitter conversations: A Wordle case study]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/understanding-twitter-conversations--a-wordle-case-study</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/understanding-twitter-conversations--a-wordle-case-study"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T12:25:35.675Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the Data Science team, a piece of our job is understanding how conversations are happening on Twitter. In this blog, we use Wordle as a case study to showcase how we think about similar analyses.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[js13kGames 2022 winners 🏆]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67439</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-06-js13k-2022-winners/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T07:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The eleventh annual js13kGames coding competition, challenging participants to create games in 13kB or less of JavaScript in a month, just wrapped up. This post highlights the top thirteen entries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Come see us at All Things Open!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/njqo</id>
        <link href="https://youtu.be/Z8DEo4DSoHY"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T20:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’re cordially invited to the “Best Booth in the Building”! We’ll be giving away stickers & t-shirts, recording shows, playing video games & awarding one lucky/skilled listener with a FREE Nintendo Switch 🕹

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building Open Finance at Nubank: a view behind the scenes]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19288</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/building-open-finance-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T19:08:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nubank has joined Open Finance, a Central Bank system that allows customers to share their data from one institution to another in a secure and efficient way, among other applications.
The post Building Open Finance at Nubank: a view behind the scenes  appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sócrates Lopes - Engineering Manager at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detect secrets in your code more accurately with dry runs for custom patterns now available in GitHub Advanced Security]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67546</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-05-detect-secrets-in-your-code-more-accurately-with-dry-runs-for-custom-patterns/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T18:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how you can seamlessly define trusted custom secret patterns to detect secrets unique to your organization with GitHub Advanced Security.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brittany O'Shea</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cool HTML elements nobody uses]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/oj4l</id>
        <link href="https://scribe.rip/7-cool-html-elements-nobody-uses-436598d85668"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T17:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tapajyoti Bose draws our attention to some obscure-but-useful elements: meter & progress, sup & sub, datalist, map & area, details & summary, object, and abbr
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A gentle introduction to how Stable Diffusion works]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/MbGD</id>
        <link href="https://jalammar.github.io/illustrated-stable-diffusion/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T16:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If Stable Diffusion has you using metaphors like wizardry, spell casting, and the like, maybe this excellent, illustrated explainer by Jay Alammar will help you distinguish it from magic. 🪄
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: September 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67485</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-05-github-availability-report-september-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T16:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In September, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services. We also experienced one incident resulting in significant impact to Codespaces. We are still investigating that incident and will include it in next month’s report. This report also sheds light into an incident that impacted Codespaces in August and an incident that impacted Actions in August.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podinfo – A Go microservice template for Kubernetes]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/rXD9</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/stefanprodan/podinfo"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T15:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podinfo is a tiny web application made with Go that showcases best practices of running microservices in Kubernetes.
This is used by CNCF projects like Flux and Flagger for end-to-end testing as well as workshops.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working on a creative project? Unleash your originality and start to tinker with the Aspiring Creatives Experience]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67540</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-05-working-on-a-creative-project-unleash-your-originality-and-start-to-tinker-with-the-aspiring-creatives-experience/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T15:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Develop your design and collaboration skills to get your clever intentions off the ground.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bass</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of diagramming tools used by software engineering teams]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9lew</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/shubhamgrg04/awesome-diagramming"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T14:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diagrams are faster and compact way for knowledge transfer. It’s much easier to convey system architecture with a diagram compared to writing an essay on it.
Diagrams are especially useful in providing high level overview of software design. Following are the most-widely used diagrams by engineering teams…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two ways you can experience GitHub Universe]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67515</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-05-two-ways-you-can-experience-github-universe/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T13:01:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Universe is back and more robust than ever, with two great ways to engage with everything this global developer event has to offer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Lindeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data transfer in Manhattan using RocksDB]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-transfer-in-manhattan-using-rocksdb</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-transfer-in-manhattan-using-rocksdb"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T12:23:35.422Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we talk about a performance and stability problem we encountered while migrating Manhattan's storage engine to RocksDB and how we solved it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can't buy a Raspberry Pi right now. Why?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/3LeJ</id>
        <link href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2022/you-cant-buy-raspberry-pi-right-now"/>
        <updated>2022-10-04T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we had Mike Riley on the show back in May, one major deterrent to his pitch that we can/should “run our homes on a Raspberry Pi” is that, well, you couldn’t buy one anywhere.
It’s six months later and you still can’t buy one! In this post, Jeff Geerling dives into the why behind that unfortunate fact, gets an official response from RPi, and lays out a few alternatives. One alternative even pleasantly surprised him…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Structure Sketches]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/y7DR</id>
        <link href="https://okso.app/showcase/data-structures"/>
        <updated>2022-10-04T15:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minimalistic data structure sketches with links to the code examples on JavaScript

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oleksii Trekhleb</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take your next video conference from within the Matrix]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/2leV</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/joschuck/matrix-webcam"/>
        <updated>2022-10-04T14:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No, not that Matrix, although I’m sure you could pull this off there as well…

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s Celebrate the Hacker Community]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/lets-celebrate-hacker-community</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/lets-celebrate-hacker-community"/>
        <updated>2022-10-04T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October is Cybersecurity Awareness Month, but at HackerOne, we’ve decided it should be Hacker Awareness Month. We want to spend October celebratin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expand your open source contributions during Hacktoberfest 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67479</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-04-expand-your-open-source-contributions-during-hacktoberfest-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-04T12:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Give back to open source projects during the month of October! This year, we’re encouraging more than code contributions: writing, design, advocacy, and financial donations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abby Cabunoc Mayes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seer – a GUI frontend to gdb]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/mlDy</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/epasveer/seer"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T18:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GNU Debugger is powerful, but it can also be inscrutable at times. Maybe this GUI will help?

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highlights from Git 2.38]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67386</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-10-03-highlights-from-git-2-38/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T18:01:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another new release of Git is here! Take a look at some of our highlights on what's new in Git 2.38.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taylor Blau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News: Hacktoberfest is ON, DiffusionBee is 1.0, Dracula UI is out, GitX is undead, Prerender is off AWS & we'll be at ATO!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1864</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/news-2022-10-03"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Ocean kicks off Hacktoberfest 2022, Divam Gupta releases DiffusionBee 1.0 with “Image To Image” support, Zeno Rocha open sources Dracula UI for React, GitX gets brought back from the brink & Prerender.io engineers save a bundle by moving off AWS.
Oh, and join us at All Things Open in early November!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Hacktoberfest 2022

github.com/thechangelog/transcripts
github.com/thechangelog/show-notes
DiffusionBee

🎧 Mentioned on The Changelog #506
Source on GitHub
Dracula UI

🎧 Zeno on The Changelog #405
🎧 Zeno on The Changelog #4248
github.com/gitx/gitx
Prerender moving away from AWS
💚 Join us at All Things Open 2022!
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facts about state machines]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/dq5E</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/cpressey/Facts-about-State-Machines"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T13:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Johannes Schuck holds the opinion that state machines are underrated. So he wrote this:
The goal of this list of facts is not to teach you what state machines are or how to use them; there are plenty of other resources for that. Rather, the goal here is to motivate their usage and to highlight things about them that are frequently overlooked, but nonetheless relevant.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over-squashing, Bottlenecks, and Graph Ricci curvature]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/over-squashing--bottlenecks--and-graph-ricci-curvature</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/over-squashing--bottlenecks--and-graph-ricci-curvature"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T12:27:22.391Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over-squashing is a common plight of Graph Neural Networks. In this post, we discuss how this phenomenon can be understood and remedied through the concept of Ricci curvature.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Sparrow tackles data storage challenges of scale]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/twitter-sparrow-tackles-data-storage-challenges-of-scale</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/twitter-sparrow-tackles-data-storage-challenges-of-scale"/>
        <updated>2022-10-01T12:22:12.675Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we discuss the scale at which Twitter operates through Project Sparrow, an initiative that shifted the architecture of our data pipelines from a batch event approach to streaming.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[node_modules: How one character saved 50 GB of disk space]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/qMDp</id>
        <link href="https://mainmatter.com/blog/2022/09/29/pnpm"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T20:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tobias Bieniek:
Have you ever worked with JavaScript? Have you been annoyed by the three hundred copies of left-pad in all of the node_modules folders on your disk? Would you prefer if all of your projects shared their node_modules folders instead of each getting their own copy?
The single character that saved him all that space? The p in pnpm…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 508: A guided tour through ID3 esoterica]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1833</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/508"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we turn the mics on ourselves, kind of. Lars Wikman joins the show to give us a guided tour through ID3 esoterica and the shiny new open source Elixir library he developed for us. We talk about what ID3 is, its many versions, what it aims to be and what it could have been, how our library project got started, all the unique features and failed dreams of the ID3v2 spec, how ID3v2 and Podcast 2.0 are solving the problem differently, and how all of this maps back to us giving you (our listeners) a better experience while listening to our shows.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 15 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
InfluxData – The time series platform for building and operating time series applications — InfluxDB empowers d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why aren't there more programming languages startups?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/jqDl</id>
        <link href="https://www.akitasoftware.com/blog-posts/why-arent-there-more-programming-languages-startups"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T19:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jean Yang:
There’s clearly a lot of programmer pain. But why we don’t see more tech transfer of these “deep” technologies from research into industry is something I have been thinking about since I was in college, when I decided I wanted to spend my life making programmers’ lives better. Many other fields, from robotics to databases, have clearer paths to commercialization. But when it comes to new programming languages or software analyses, the path of tech transfer is often decades-long, if it exists at all.
She goes on to describe a few factors that are in the way of “deep tech” dev tools investing, how some of those things are changing, and how others still need to change.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 245: Launching Platformatic DB 🚀]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1853</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/245"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patformatic co-founders Matteo Collina & Luca Maraschi join Amal & Chris to discuss their just-announced (and we mean just announced) open source database tool: Platformatic DB!
It’s a daemon that can turn any PostgreSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, or SQLite database into a REST and GraphQL endpoint. What makes it special is that it allows massive customization thanks to the flexibility of Fastify plugins.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s business needs. Learn more at changelog.com/square to dive into the docs, APIs, SDKs and to create your Square Developer account — tell them Changelog sent you.

    
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn continuously about their applications - from the frontend to the backend. Use the code CHANGELOG and get the team plan free for three months.

    
Fly.io – Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

    
Featuring
Matteo Collina – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Luca Maraschi – Twitter, GitHub
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Christopher Hiller – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
🎧 JS Party #197: Fastify served with a refreshing Pino 🍷
Our first Open Source tool: Platformatic DB
Platformatic on GitHub
@databases
Adventures in Nodeland
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 249: Functional programming with generics?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1808</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/249"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We did an episode on functional programming in Go with Aaron Schlesinger back in 2019… But that was before generics were a thing. Let’s revisit the topic and discuss the pros and cons now that we have generics. What’s changed? What hasn’t?
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
Honeycomb – Guess less, know more. When production is running slow, it’s hard to know where problems originate: is it your application code, users, or the underlying systems? With Honeycomb you get a fast, unified, and clear understanding of the one thing driving your business: production. Join the swarm and try Honeycomb free today at honeycomb.io/changelog

    
Ship It! – A podcast about getting your best ideas into the world and seeing what happens. Listen to an episode that interests you and subscribe today.

    
Featuring
Aaron Schlesinger – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Go Time #87: Functional programming?
Dylan Meeus’s GopherCon 2020
Aaron’s GopherCon 2017
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dracula UI is now free and open source]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/W1mJ</id>
        <link href="https://twitter.com/zenorocha/status/1575476765228560384"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T16:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dracula UI is a dark-first collection of UI patterns and components. Key features:
Built for Dark Mode:  Most templates are built using light colors and later on adapted to dark colors. Dark themes shouldn’t be an afterthought, they should be a top priority.
Designer Friendly: Speed up the prototyping phase by using a highly configurable Design System. Collaborate easily by taking advantage of a carefully crafted Figma file.
Great Developer Experience: Don’t worry about class names, just use the Visual Studio Code snippets. You can take advantage of autocomplete and also access the entire documentation right from your code editor.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JC converts the output of popular commands to JSON for easier parsing]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/eE71</id>
        <link href="https://blog.kellybrazil.com/2022/09/27/jc-version-1-22-0-released/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T19:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a neat little CLI utility from Kelly Brazil that parses the output of common Unix system commands into JSON/YAML. We’re linking to the latest version (1.22.0) which adds new magic parsers for /proc files. This handy glue-type tool gets one click neater every release!

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AJ Kerrigan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub supports internet freedom and global availability in Iran]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67361</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-09-29-github-supports-internet-freedom-and-global-availability-in-iran/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T19:11:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Access to the open internet is essential to defending human rights, and developers have an important role in promoting freedom of expression and transparency. GitHub is committed to keeping Iranians connected to the global developer community.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shelley McKinley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A tool for refurbishing and modernizing Python codebases]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Jgpn</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/dosisod/refurb"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T18:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Point Refurb at your Python code to see how bad good it is. Here’s the author’s motivation:
I love doing code reviews: I like taking something and making it better, faster, more elegant, and so on. Lots of static analysis tools already exist, but none of them seem to be focused on making code more elegant, more readable, or more modern. That is where Refurb comes in.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After the offer: staying in tech long-term]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67322</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-09-29-after-the-offer-staying-in-tech-long-term/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T16:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tech can be a tricky industry (to say the least). We talked with three tech professionals who share why they stay, what has helped them the most, and the power of switching things up.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klint Finley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Id3vx – a library for parsing and encoding ID3 tags]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/posts/2549</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/posts/id3vx-a-library-for-parsing-and-encoding-id3-tags"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T14:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The podcast moguls of Changelog Media have been keen to introduce chapters into their podcast episodes and they reached out to me for a hand. And would you know, now they have chapters and the Elixir community has a shiny new ID3 tag library.
Chapters are neat, they let you see a Table of Contents, jump to specific parts and similar. The changelog.com site is an open source project built in Elixir. I love working with Elixir. It is a steadily growing but still somewhat niche language and it doesn’t have every library under the sun, only most of them. It hasn’t had a fully fledged ID3v2 library so far. There are a few libraries that let you parse a tag in one specific way, targeting a subset. I haven’t found any that allow writing a tag. To create podcast chapters you need to update the ID3…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lars Wikman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 72: Klustered & Rawkode Academy]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1790</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/72"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of our listeners, Andrew Welker, suggested that we talk about Klustered, so a few hours before David Flanagan was about to do his workshop at Container Days, we recorded this episode. We talked about all the weird and wonderful Kubernetes debugging sessions on Klustered, a YouTube playlist with 43 videos and counting.
We then talked about Rawkode Academy, and we finished with conferences. Good thing we did, because David almost forgot about KubeHuddle, the conference that he is co-organising next week. Gerhard is looking forward to talking at it! No, seriously, check it out at kubehuddle.com.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the Results of Hack U.S.]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/bounty/announcing-results-hack-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/bounty/announcing-results-hack-us"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MNT's Reform is an open source PC that fits in your pocket]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/rXZ9</id>
        <link href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/meet-an-open-source-pc-that-can-fit-in-your-pocket"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T18:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MNT Research… is going small for its next project. The MNT Pocket Reform has a seven-inch screen with a clamshell design that, when closed, will be less than five centimeters thick. If its perky purple facade looks a bit retro, that’s no surprise; the Pocket’s inspirations read like a ‘greatest hits’ list of pocketable computers.
They’re taking open source seriously:
MNT’s open-source promise is not limited to an open source operating system or select internal components The Pocket Reform, as with MNT’s full-size Reform laptop, will provide mainboard schematics, 3D models for physical components, and open source drivers, among other things.
Coming soon to a crowd fund near you.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We reduced our server costs 80% by moving away from AWS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9lVw</id>
        <link href="https://scribe.rip/how-we-reduced-our-annual-server-costs-by-80-from-1m-to-200k-by-moving-away-from-aws-2b98cbd21b46"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T17:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zsot Varga explains how Prerender saved $800k annually by removing their reliance on AWS and building in-house infrastructure to handle traffic and cached data. This was no minor migration, and it took months to pull off, but it’s a solid lesson in testing your assumptions.
The cloud (which is AWS in most cases) is the default for most businesses today. That’s a good starting place for many reasons, but once you get up and going you may find it’s not the best choice for your business, like the folks at Prerender learned.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We reduced our server costs 80% by moving away from AWS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9lVw</id>
        <link href="https://levelup.gitconnected.com/how-we-reduced-our-annual-server-costs-by-80-from-1m-to-200k-by-moving-away-from-aws-2b98cbd21b46"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T17:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zsot Varga explains how Prerender saved $800k annually by removing their reliance on AWS and building in-house infrastructure to handle traffic and cached data. This was no minor migration, and it took months to pull off, but it’s a solid lesson in testing your assumptions.
The cloud (which is AWS in most cases) is the default for most businesses today. That’s a good starting place for many reasons, but once you get up and going you may find it’s not the best choice for your business, like the folks at Prerender learned.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacktoberfest-hunt CLI]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/kwoR</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/stefanbuck/hacktoberfest-hunt"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T16:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s Hacktoberfest again, but you don’t know where to find interesting projects? This CLI will help you find participating projects based on your starred repositories. Simply run:
npx hacktoberfest-hunt

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best practices on rolling out code scanning at enterprise scale]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=67292</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-09-28-best-practices-on-rolling-out-code-scanning-at-enterprise-scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T16:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn best practices on how to roll out centrally managed, developer-centric application security with a third party CI/CD system like Jenkins or ADO.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Alwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Timestone: Netflix’s High-Throughput, Low-Latency Priority Queueing System with Built-in Support…]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/1abf249ba95f</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/timestone-netflixs-high-throughput-low-latency-priority-queueing-system-with-built-in-support-1abf249ba95f?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T15:40:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[by Kostas Christidis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The first 300 setopts]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19536</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/09/28/the-first-300-setopts/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T11:55:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Already when the first version of curl shipped in 1998, I had plans and ideas in the back of my head to turn it to a library at some point. I had already before worked on providing libraries with APIs for applications and I appreciated their powers. During the summer of 2000 I refactored the … Continue reading The first 300 setopts →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Hackerone’s Enhanced Pentest as a Service to Streamline Security Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/pentests/use-hackerones-enhanced-pentest-service-streamline-security-testing</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/pentests/use-hackerones-enhanced-pentest-service-streamline-security-testing"/>
        <updated>2022-09-27T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New capabilities improve pentesting to increase attack resistance
The enhanced features drive robust security testing practices with the ability to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ryan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhance is a web standards-based HTML framework]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/3LDJ</id>
        <link href="https://enhance.dev/docs/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-27T20:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love that people are bringing HTML back to the forefront:
Our mission is to enable anyone to build multi-page dynamic web apps while staying as close to the platform as possible. Enhance fills in the gaps to make building for the backend, and the browser a seamless experience for web authors and consumers.
Modern JavaScript frameworks bring more problems than they solve; recreating native web platform features adding unnecessary weight and complexity, which is challenging to unravel.
Enhance provides a dependable foundation built on standards-based web platform features, allowing developers to create web applications that are lightweight, flexible, and future-proof.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 195: Production data labeling workflows]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1860</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/195"/>
        <updated>2022-09-27T19:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s one thing to gather some labels for your data. It’s another thing to integrate data labeling into your workflows and infrastructure in a scalable, secure, and useful way. Mark from Xelex joins us to talk through some of what he has learned after helping companies scale their data annotation efforts. We get into workflow management, labeling instructions, team dynamics, and quality assessment. This is a super practical episode!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Mark Christensen – LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Xelex.ai
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In defense of apps that don’t need updates]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/7YJQ</id>
        <link href="https://vivqu.com/blog/2022/09/25/outdated-apps/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-27T19:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vivian Qu states her case as to why Apple’s decision to remove outdated apps from the App Store is dumb, especially for indies like her.
Never mind the fact that my app has a 5-star rating and was still being downloaded, with no complaints from any of my users. Also disregard the fact that I had other highly-rated apps up on the App Store, some of which had been updated much more recently than July 2019, clearly showing that I have not abandoned these apps entirely. If there had been an actual reviewer who checked my outdated app, they would have discovered that I architected the app from the beginning to dynamically scale the UI so it resizes to fit the latest iPhone devices. All these could be signals that indicate to Apple that this is not a garbage-filled scam app that is lowering the quality of their App Store.
She goes on to tell the entire saga that she (and others) were put through to keep their apps on the store. Sometimes an app isn’t outdated, it’s just complete. Ya know?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 years of progress on the Go runtime]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/2lkV</id>
        <link href="https://go.dev/blog/go119runtime"/>
        <updated>2022-09-27T15:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Knyszek:
Since our last blog post about the Go GC in 2018 the Go GC, and the Go runtime more broadly, has been steadily improving. We’ve tackled some large projects, motivated by real-world Go programs and real challenges facing Go users. Let’s catch you up on the highlights!
Lots of invisible changes/improvements, but Michael focuses in on a new knob that he’s encouraging gophers to play with: the soft memory limit
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[58 bytes of CSS to look great nearly everywhere]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/6rQn</id>
        <link href="https://gist.github.com/JoeyBurzynski/617fb6201335779f8424ad9528b72c41"/>
        <updated>2022-09-26T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a great starter snippet for any web page:
main {
  max-width: 38rem;
  padding: 2rem;
  margin: auto;
}

The linked post explains the why behind these rules and expands with a 100 byte alternative and the comments have a bunch of variants and conversation about each specific rule.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News: Firefox supports blockers, NATS is great, Uber's MFA fatigue, OAuth2 drawn in cute shapes & an aging programmer]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1859</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/news-2022-09-26"/>
        <updated>2022-09-26T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla says Firefox will continue to support current content blockers, Nabeel Suleiman thinks NATS is great and recommends you check it out, InfoQ breaks down Uber’s recent security breach, Klemen Sever explained OAuth2 by drawing cute shapes & Jorge Manrubia reflects back as an aging programmer.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Firefox will continue to support current content blockers
Nats: You Need it Now!

Dwayne Bradley’s comment
Multi-Factor Authentication Fatigue Key Factor in Uber Breach
OAuth2 explained with cute shapes

🎧 [Aaron Parecki on The Changelog #456])(https://changelog.fm/456)
A nice Twitter review
Aging programmer
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contribute to open source: the right way 3rd edition (Free 📘)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/lO8m</id>
        <link href="https://daniele.tech/2022/09/contribute-to-open-source-the-right-way-3rd-edition/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-26T13:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This book is my condensed personal experience in the last 12 years in various projects, communities and roles in Open Source. Including my best practice, tips and a lot of examples and resources.
After 2 years a new edition is here with new stuff and also available on Amazon Kindle.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniele Scasciafratte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A web-based implementation of The Matrix's digital rain]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/5jz1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/Rezmason/matrix"/>
        <updated>2022-09-26T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This project is a web implementation of the raining green code seen in the Matrix franchise. It’s built right on top of the upcoming graphics API WebGPU, but falls back to the functional WebGL wrapper, REGL; its previous Three.js version is maintained in a separate branch.
I used to spend countless hours in college scouring the web for the best digital rain screen saver for my laptop. Sounds like the author is with me on that:
The number of implementations out there of this effect is a testament to the size of the film’s impact on popular culture. For decades, I’ve enjoyed searching for and comparing them from time to time. That’s probably how you arrived here— it’s fun to see what kinds of solutions different people come up with to a problem, when the process is purely recreational and its success is subjective.
This one’s really nice and even has a 3D mode. The README says it’s “made with love”, but from what I can tell it’s almost entirely JavaScript. 😜

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>