<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-01-12T12:19:27.645Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selecting HTTP version (three)]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=21282</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/01/12/selecting-http-version-three/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T07:38:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest HTTP version is called HTTP/3 and is being transferred over QUIC instead of the old classic TCP+TLS duo. An attempt of an architectural drawing could look like this: Remember: experimental HTTP/3 support in curl is still experimental so we do reserve the right to change names, behavior and functionality during development. We aim … Continue reading Selecting HTTP version (three) →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 85: The hard parts of platform engineering]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1952</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/85"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marcos Nils has been into platform engineering for the best part of the last decade. He helped architect & build developer platforms using VMs & OpenStack, containers with Docker, and even Kubernetes. He did this at startups with 10 people, as well as large, publicly traded companies with 1000+ software engineers.
Today we talk with Marcos about the hard parts of platform engineering.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 17 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

    
Featuring
Marcos Nils – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Gerhard Lazu – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responsible AI: Looking back at 2022, and to the future]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/ai/responsible-ai-looking-back-at-2022-and-to-the-future/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/responsible-ai-looking-back-at-2022-and-to-the-future/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking back at Google’s 2022 progress in principled AI innovation and ahead to 2023 and beyond.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Nubank’s main headquarters in Pinheiros, Sao Paulo/Brazil]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=20053</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/nubank-office-pinheiros/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T17:40:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we created a workplace that reflects our values
The post Meet Nubank’s main headquarters in Pinheiros, Sao Paulo/Brazil appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building an internet scale meme search engine]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/mlVP</id>
        <link href="https://findthatmeme.com/blog/2023/01/08/image-stacks-and-iphone-racks-building-an-internet-scale-meme-search-engine-Qzrz7V6T.html"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T17:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an incredibly detailed and fun story producing a system architecture that includes Postgres, Elasticsearch & an OCR service running on a cluster of iPhones.
How much effort will one man put in to help himself and others find that meme!

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Names should be cute, not descriptive]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/dqOa</id>
        <link href="https://ntietz.com/blog/name-your-projects-cutesy-things/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T16:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A long-standing debate between me and a peer at work has been how we should name services. His position was always that services should be named something descriptive, so that you can infer from the name what it does. My position is that the name should definitely not be descriptive, but should be something cute and wholly disconnected from the purpose. And I think this applies more broadly to projects and companies, too.
Nicholas’ reason for cute names winning comes down to the inevitably of change in a service/project’s function and the difficulty in renaming things. I hadn’t thought of that argument, but I already agreed with the premise.
We also apply this thinking to podcast episode names, which can be a mixed bag because descriptive titles certainly help when it comes to discovery. As Adam and I discussed on our recent State of the “log” episode, if you see use a descriptive title, it’s most likely because we couldn’t think of a good cute/interesting one.
But that’s just our opinion about episode naming. What do you prefer?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Passwordless deployments to the cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69409</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-01-11-passwordless-deployments-to-the-cloud/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T16:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discovering passwords in our codebase is probably one of our worst fears. But what if you didn’t need passwords at all, and could deploy to your cloud provider another way? In this post, we explore how you can use OpenID Connect to trust your cloud provider, enabling you to deploy easily, securely and safely, while minimizing the operational overhead associated with secrets (for example, key rotations).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Reddington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Examples and guides for using the OpenAI API]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/5jmg</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/openai/openai-cookbook"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T15:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apropos of nothing, you may be considering starting a new AI-related project. The OpenAI folks inferred this fact and created a repo full of example code and prompts to get started with their API.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 206: ChatGPT goes prime time!]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1964</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/206"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel and Chris do a deep dive into OpenAI’s ChatGPT, which is the first LLM to enjoy direct mass adoption by folks outside the AI world. They discuss how it works, its effect on the world, ramifications of its adoption, and what we may expect in the future as these types of models continue to evolve.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
ChatGPT
OpenAI Blog:  ChatGPT
Illustrating Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF)
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing required workflows and configuration variables to GitHub Actions]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69396</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-01-10-introducing-required-workflows-and-configuration-variables-to-github-actions/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T19:37:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now, you can standardize and enforce CI/CD best practices across all repositories in your organization to reduce duplication and secure your DevOps processes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashok Kirla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am not a supplier]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/jqQb</id>
        <link href="https://www.softwaremaxims.com/blog/not-a-supplier"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T17:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Depierre, writing about the concept of the Software Supply Chain in the context of open source development:
We are not suppliers. All the people writing and maintaining these projects, we are not suppliers. We do not have a business relationship with all these organisations. We are volunteers, writing code and putting it online under these Licences. And yes, we put it online for people to use them. But we do not get anything from it.
He goes on to discuss how, importantly, licenses such as the MIT point this out (in all caps):
If you use this, I owe you nothing. At all. We have no relationship. I put this up online on the condition that if you use it, all the risks are on you… So all your Software Supply Chain ideas? You are not buying from a supplier, you are a raccoon digging through dumpsters for free code. So I would advise you to put these rules in the same dumpster. And remember. I am not a supplier.
That raccoon line reminds me of a now-ancient meme you might still enjoy…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a single dev dropped AWS costs by 90%, then disappeared]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/EqjY</id>
        <link href="https://scribe.rip/@maximetopolov/how-a-single-developer-dropped-aws-costs-by-90-then-disappeared-2b46a115103a"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T16:37:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a must-read thriller!
Costs were dropping by 90% as promised. He was paid 50K$. Then he disappeared. Completely.
The happy IT director wanted to give more assignments to this genius. But he vanished. Didn’t answer emails, voicemail on the phone number closed LinkedIn account. Gone.
The truth, sometimes, is stranger than fiction…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft wants to acquire a 49% stake in ChatGPT]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/LWw4</id>
        <link href="https://watcher.guru/news/microsoft-plans-to-acquire-a-49-stake-in-chatgpt-owner-openai"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T15:46:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This escalated quickly. I don’t know about you, but I’m a daily user of ChatGPT. Just yesterday, I asked “What options does Linux offer for fast RAID 0 software RAID?” and I had an entire conversation that settled on Btrfs as a good option and I learned how to create and configure the array, mount it, and most importantly scrub it for errors. I’ll still use ZFS, of course. But, I’ve never had that experience using Google (nor can you).
…according to a report by Semafor, Microsoft Corp is discussing the possibility of acquiring OpenAI, the parent company of ChatGPT. The tech-industry giant is ready to pay upwards of $10 billion for the acquisition.
Clearly, Microsoft sees the bigger picture here for Bing, Microsoft 365, GitHub Copilot, and more. This also speaks to the conversation we had with Swyx about AI’s future being tied to capitalism and eventually being controlled by the FAANGs.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My weekly report on email]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=21298</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/01/10/my-weekly-report-on-email/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T14:44:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting this week, you can subscribe to my weekly report and receive it as an email. This is the brief weekly summary of my past week that I have been writing and making available for over a year already. It sums up what I have been doing recently and what I plan to do next. … Continue reading My weekly report on email →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Twitter uses rasdaemon for hardware reliability]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2023/how-twitter-uses-rasdaemon-for-hardware-reliability"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T12:18:22.752Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Twitter, our on premise data centers contain hundreds of thousands of hardware servers and millions of server hardware components.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Human Security Testing Helps the U.S. Government’s Zero Trust Mandate]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/security-compliance/how-human-security-testing-helps-us-governments-zero-trust-mandate</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/security-compliance/how-human-security-testing-helps-us-governments-zero-trust-mandate"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One major reason for the progress is a May 2021 Executive Order that pushes federal agencies to speedily embrace the “never trust; always verify”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ilona Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Discussions just got better with Category Forms!]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69339</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-01-09-github-discussions-just-got-better-with-category-forms/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T21:54:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Category Forms allow maintainers to create templates for their GitHub Discussions, which means that users can start new discussions with all the necessary information already included.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhinav Vadrevu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News: A simpler alternative to deleted_at, rules of thumb for better software, faking it until you automate it, the only civilized way to read online & AI and the big five]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1966</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/news-2023-01-09"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T21:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brandur Leach’s easy, alternative soft deletion strategy, Lane Wagner’s zen of proverbs, Nicolas Carlo says fake it until you can automate it, Felix A. Crux thinks feeds are the only civilized way to read online & Ben Thompson analyzes AI and the big five tech companies.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Notes and Links
Easy, alternative soft deletion
The Zen of Proverbs
Fake it until you automate it
Feeds: The Only Civilised Way to Read Online
AI and the Big Five
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Default setup: A new way to enable GitHub code scanning]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69330</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-01-09-default-setup-a-new-way-to-enable-github-code-scanning/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T18:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Default setup is a new way to automatically set up code scanning on your repository, without the use of a .yaml file.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Walker Chabbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brand Ambassador Announcement]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/brand-ambassador-announcement</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/brand-ambassador-announcement"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T16:06:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2022 just came to an end. We hope you found plenty of bugs, collected a lot in bounties, and are ready to set goals for this new year. As we turn th]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agile isn't about speed, it's about direction]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Jg6b</id>
        <link href="https://tim.mcnamara.nz/post/705779065607618560/agile"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T16:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tim McNamara makes an important distinction that is often lost on us:
Agile doesn’t make your team magically speed up its ability to close tickets. Instead, it speeds up the team’s decision-making process. It’s about orientation, not velocity. An agile workflow is one where you are able to quickly adjust direction based on short feedback cycles.
Mat, Natalie & I touched on this when they dragged me on to Go Time last summer to share some thoughts on velocity. Worth a (re)listen if you’re in to such things.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over-squashing, Bottlenecks, and Graph Ricci curvature]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/over-squashing--bottlenecks--and-graph-ricci-curvature</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/over-squashing--bottlenecks--and-graph-ricci-curvature"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T12:17:45.971Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over-squashing is a common plight of Graph Neural Networks. In this post, we discuss how this phenomenon can be understood and remedied through the concept of Ricci curvature.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Sparrow tackles data storage challenges of scale]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/twitter-sparrow-tackles-data-storage-challenges-of-scale</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/twitter-sparrow-tackles-data-storage-challenges-of-scale"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T12:17:45.940Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we discuss the scale at which Twitter operates through Project Sparrow, an initiative that shifted the architecture of our data pipelines from a batch event approach to streaming.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Twitter conversations: A Wordle case study]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/understanding-twitter-conversations--a-wordle-case-study</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/understanding-twitter-conversations--a-wordle-case-study"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T12:17:45.924Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the Data Science team, a piece of our job is understanding how conversations are happening on Twitter. In this blog, we use Wordle as a case study to showcase how we think about similar analyses.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copyright without years]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=21201</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2023/01/08/copyright-without-years/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-08T22:56:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like so many other software projects the curl project has copyright mentions at the top of almost every file in the source code repository. Like Copyright (C) 1998 - 2022, Daniel Stenberg ... Over the years we have used a combination of scripts and manual edits to update the ending year in that copyright line … Continue reading Copyright without years →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 521: Don't sleep on Ruby & Rails]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1932</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/521"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to 2023 — we’re kicking off the year talking to Justin Searls about the state of web development and why he just might write a “You Might Not Need React” post. He’s been so productive using Turbo and Stimulus (and tailwind) in Rails 7 that we had to talk about the state of Rails development today and a bunch of other fun topics around building for the web in 2023.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 16 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn continuously about their applications - from the frontend to the backend. Use the code CHANGELOG and get the team plan free for three months.

    
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s business needs. Learn more at changelog.com/square to dive into the docs, APIs, SDKs and to create your Square Developer account — tell them Changelog sent you.

    
Featuring
Justin Searls – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Notes and Links
SO PRODUCTIVE in Rails 7
Shaking my head big time at The Changelog #509
What excites you about Ruby on Rails in 2022?
The Changelog #509
Ship It #44
Searls says:
For liner notes purposes, @hsbt and @ko1 have indeed both contributed to ruby.debug but it was clearly Koichi’s baby.
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 257: New Year's Party 🪩]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1935</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/257"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T17:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s our 4th annual New Year’s party! Jerod & the gang review our (failed) resolutions from last year, discuss what’s trending in the web world, make a few predictions of our own & even set some new (probably failed) resolutions for this year.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 2 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

    
Ship It! – A podcast about getting your best ideas into the world and seeing what happens. Listen to an episode that interests you and subscribe today.

    
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Divya – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Kevin Ball – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Feross Aboukhadijeh – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Take our latest Frontend Feud survey!
NUC (Next Unit Computing)
ConstitutionDAO
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is it like being a Product Manager at Nubank?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19774</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/product-manager-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T16:14:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A look into the career of a Product Manager at Nubank, the scope of work and the main differences with other Product positions.
The post What is it like being a Product Manager at Nubank? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacqueline Yumi Asano - Senior Product Manager - Credit Card Financing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we improved our documentation]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Mbm5</id>
        <link href="https://medusajs.com/blog/how-we-improved-our-documentation/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T15:29:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shahed Nasser shares how she and the technical writing team at Medusa went about improving their docs:
The most essential change that helped us implement all improvements is how we manage the documentation. In most software companies, documentation has less of a priority compared to the software, and it is handled as an afterthought.
At Medusa, we early on came to realize that documentation is what can actually drive further adoption of Medusa.
There’s a lot to learn from their process that you can apply to your own, but I think the biggest winner Shahed shares is the mindset change of thinking about documentation itself as a product, not as something that augments or attaches to the product.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transform Gist into your personal key/value data store]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/3LWw</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/TimMikeladze/gist-database"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T14:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes all a project needs is the ability to read/write small amounts of JSON data and have it saved in some persistent storage. Imagine a simple data-model which receives infrequent updates and could be represented as JSON object. It doesn’t demand a full-blown database, but it would be neat to have a way to interact with this data and have it persist across sessions.
This is where gist-database comes in handy, by leveraging the power of the gist api you can easily create a key/value data-store for your project.
This is a perfect solution for low write / high read scenarios when serving static site content with Next.js and using Incremental Static Regeneration to keep your cached content fresh.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 261: A special New Year's fireside chat]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1949</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/261"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mat and the gang ring in the new year by gathering around a make believe fireplace and discussing what they’re excited about in 2023, their new years resolutions & a little bit of Go talk, too. But only a little.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 4 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

    
Practical AI – Making artificial intelligence practical, productive & accessible to everyone!

    
Featuring
Mat Ryer – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jon Calhoun – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Kris Brandow – Twitter, GitHub
Ian Lopshire – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
user-defined iteration using range over func values
📼 City of Hilliard Leaf Collection
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree views in CSS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9lzN</id>
        <link href="https://iamkate.com/code/tree-views/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T17:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kate Rose Morley:
A tree view (collapsible list) can be created using only html and css, without the need for JavaScript. Accessibility software will see the tree view as lists nested inside disclosure widgets, and the standard keyboard interaction is supported automatically.
TIL!
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 84: Bare metal meets Talos Linux (the K8s OS)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1951</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/84"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T16:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to 2023! A new year is the perfect time to start with a fresh perspective. Given a few bare metal hosts with fast, local storage, how would you run your workloads on them? Would you cluster them for redundancy? What operating system would you choose?
Steve Francis, CEO at Sidero Labs and Andrew Rynhard, CTO at Sidero Labs join us today to talk about running Talos Linux on bare metal.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 2 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases close to your users. In minutes you can run your Ruby, Go, Node, Deno, Python, or Elixir app (and databases!) all over the world. No ops required. Learn more at fly.io/changelog and check out the speedrun in their docs.

    
Practical AI – Making artificial intelligence practical, productive & accessible to everyone!

    
Featuring
Andrew Rynhard – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Steve Francis – GitHub, LinkedIn
Gerhard Lazu – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
🎬 Hack Sesh: K8s@Home Edition - April, 2022
🎬 DevOps Toolkit - Talos: Linux Designed For Kubernetes - March, 2022
🎬 Sidero Metal Webinar - January, 2022
🎬 I am Installing Talos OS (Sidero) at Home - October, 2021
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes to Disclosure Assistance]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/changes-disclosure-assistance</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/changes-disclosure-assistance"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T16:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HackerOne is excited to announce the revamp of our Disclosure Assistance program! Our goal is to reset expectations and realign with the hacker comm]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to rotate any secrets you have stored in CircleCI]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Pp7R</id>
        <link href="https://circleci.com/blog/january-4-2023-security-alert/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T14:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The headline is the nut of this story, but here’s CircleCI CTO Rob Zuber with the announcement:
We wanted to make you aware that we are currently investigating a security incident, and that our investigation is ongoing. We will provide you updates about this incident, and our response, as they become available. At this point, we are confident that there are no unauthorized actors active in our systems; however, out of an abundance of caution, we want to ensure that all customers take certain preventative measures to protect your data as well.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ready for Growth]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/ready-for-growth/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/ready-for-growth/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello from CES 2023. We don’t have a new product this year, because the comma three is already everything you want. Did you see the taco drive?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sailboat UI – a framework for Tailwind]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/AX73</id>
        <link href="https://sailboatui.com/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T21:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[150+ open source Tailwind components.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You want modules, not microservices]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/GW7A</id>
        <link href="http://blogs.newardassociates.com/blog/2023/you-want-modules-not-microservices.html"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A solid rundown of the discrepency between what we hope from microservices and what we often get instead. TLDR:
Architecture is hard sometimes–people keep offering up some new idea that quickly becomes the mainstream “way to do it” without any context or nuance, and the industry, desperate to find ways to improve their architecture, snaps it up without hesitation. Microservices was the latest in the trend, and it’s time we dissected the idea and got to the real root of what’s going on.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Customer Service to Software Engineer: how Nubank enabled me to make a career transition in 2 years]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=20001</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/from-customer-service-to-software-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T18:54:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2019, I joined Nubank as a Customer Service Analyst. In two years, I entered the Technical Writing team. Discover how!
The post From Customer Service to Software Engineer: how Nubank enabled me to make a career transition in 2 years appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Georgia Anunciação - Technical Writer at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: December 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69291</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2023-01-04-github-availability-report-december-2022/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T17:20:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In December, we did not experience any incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services. This report sheds light into an incident that impacted customers using GitHub Packages and GitHub Pages in November.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RustScan is a modern take on the port scanner]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/eEjY</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/RustScan/RustScan"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T14:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This thing scans all 65k ports in 3 seconds, is scriptable with Python, Lua & Shell, “learns” based on your usage, and automatically pipes ports into Nmap.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 205: NLP research by & for local communities]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1959</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/205"/>
        <updated>2023-01-03T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While at EMNLP 2022, Daniel got a chance to sit down with an amazing group of researchers creating NLP technology that actually works for their local language communities. Just Zwennicker (Universiteit van Amsterdam) discusses his work on a machine translation system for Sranan Tongo, a creole language that is spoken in Suriname. Andiswa Bukula (SADiLaR), Rooweither Mabuya (SADiLaR), and Bonaventure Dossou (Lanfrica, Mila) discuss their work with Masakhane to strengthen and spur NLP research in African languages, for Africans, by Africans.
The group emphasized the need for more linguistically diverse NLP systems that work in scenarios of data scarcity, non-Latin scripts, rich morphology, etc. You don’t want to miss this one!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Just Zwennicker – LinkedIn
Andiswa Bukula – Twitter
Rooweither Mabuya – Twitter
Bonaventure Dossou – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
EMNLP 2022 papers from the guests:
Towards a general purpose machine translation system for Sranantongo
MasakhaNER 2.0: Africa-centric Transfer Learning for Named Entity Recognition
AfroLM: A Self-Active Learning-based Multilingual Pretrained Language Model for 23 African Languages
Other links relevant to the discussion:
Masakhane
Lanfrica
The South African Centre for Digital Language Resources (SADiLaR)
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Docker on macOS is slow and how to fix it]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/1Wqz</id>
        <link href="https://www.paolomainardi.com/posts/docker-performance-macos/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-03T16:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t normally include how-tos in Changelog News, but I’m making an exception for this post because a) it goes deep on how Docker works on macOS, and b) this is a problem that plagues so many of us that I thought it worth pointing to a solution.
There’s also a nice bit about Development Containers at the end, which are quite promising, indeed.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React components for interactive math]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/D1a0</id>
        <link href="https://mafs.dev/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-03T15:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Very cool! Here’s the code for plotting a simple sin curve:
import { Mafs, CartesianCoordinates, FunctionGraph } from "mafs"

function HelloFx() {
  return (
    <Mafs>
      <CartesianCoordinates subdivisions={4} />
      <FunctionGraph.OfX y={(x) => Math.sin(x)} />
    </Mafs>
  )
}


Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog News: Clipboard, unbundling tools for thought, microfeed, prepare to be productive & a look inside Matrix]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1958</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/news-2023-01-02"/>
        <updated>2023-01-02T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jackson Huff’s clipboard powertool for the command line, Fernando Borretti thinks tools for thought should be unbundled, Listen Notes helps you run a microfeed on Cloudflare, Martin Rue says to be productive, be prepared & Paul Sawers takes TechCrunch readers inside Matrix and features its recent adoption wins.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Notes and Links
Clipboard
Unbundling Tools for Thought
microfeed.org
To be productive, be prepared
Inside Matrix
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Jupyter Notebooks inside NeoVim]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/gw0J</id>
        <link href="https://www.maxwellrules.com/misc/nvim_jupyter.html"/>
        <updated>2023-01-02T17:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guillem Ballesteros:
I have reached Vim nirvana with my latest setup. I can finally bring all the advantages of working within Jupyter to my favorite text editor. You get the code cells and interactive development with a fine-tuned editor and plain text files which can be put through linters and code formatters.
He goes on to share the plugins and config that make the nirvana happen.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The wordcel's guide to git]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/qM1D</id>
        <link href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2022-12-14-wordcels-guide-to-git/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-02T16:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re better with words than you are with shapes, this git guide by Zach Musgrave may help you get out of the “I memorized N git commands but I have no idea how any of this works” phase.
Here’s how Zach describes it:
The git commit graph and its relationship to common git workflows explained using simple English and easy to understand diagrams. Also some jokes.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An alternative to `deleted_at` for soft record deletion]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/X18e</id>
        <link href="https://brandur.org/fragments/deleted-record-insert"/>
        <updated>2023-01-02T16:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve probably done the whole deleted_at thing to mark records as deleted without actually deleting them from the database. That strategy is fraught for a few reasons.
In this post, Brandur Leach proposes an alternative strategy with the following endorsement:
Speaking from 30,000 feet, programming is all about tradeoffs. However, this is one of those rare places where as far as I can tell the cost/benefit skew is so disproportionate that the common platitude falls flat.
Anytime your fellow developer can make that statement in earnest, whatever they’re talking about is worth a try…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub and the Ekoparty 2022 Capture the Flag]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69278</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-30-github-and-the-ekoparty-2022-capture-the-flag/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-30T17:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about the design behind, and solutions to, several of GitHub’s CTF challenge for Ekoparty’s 2022 event!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Logan MacLaren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An m1 for curl]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=21147</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/30/an-m1-for-curl/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-29T23:04:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A generous member of the wider curl community stepped up and donated an unused Mac mini m1 model to me to be used for curl development. Today it arrived at my home. An 8C CPU/16GB/1TB/8C GPU/1GbE model as per the sticker on the box. Apple is not helping Apple has shipped and used curl in … Continue reading An m1 for curl →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub’s top 10 blog posts of 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69252</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-29-githubs-top-10-blog-posts-of-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-29T17:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the year winds down, we're highlighting some of the incredible work from GitHub’s engineers, product teams, and security researchers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Lindeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google's 2022 year in review]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/inside-google/2022-at-google/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/inside-google/2022-at-google/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-29T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recap of Google’s top announcements and initiatives in 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl -w certs]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20805</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/28/curl-w-certs/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-28T08:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a client connects to a TLS server it gets sent one or more certificates during the handshake. Those certificates are verified by the client, to make sure that the server is indeed the right one: the server the client expects it to be; no impostor and no man in the middle etc. When such … Continue reading curl -w certs →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[At 17000 curl commits]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20286</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/27/at-17000-curl-commits/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-27T21:44:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, another 1,000 commits have been recorded as done by me in the curl source code git repository since November 2021. Out of a total of 29,608 commits to the curl source code repository, I have made 17,001. 57.42%. The most recent one was PR #10019. In 2022, I have done 56% of all the … Continue reading At 17000 curl commits →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s with all the ducks?]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69198</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-23-whats-with-all-the-ducks/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T17:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What in the world do rubber ducks have to do with programming? And why were they everywhere at GitHub Universe? A lot of you asked, so I’m here to help explain.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 520: State of the "log" 2022]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1884</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/520"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our 5th annual year-end wrap-up episode! Sit back, relax, pour a glass of your favorite beverage and join us for listener voice mails, our favorite episodes, some must-listens, and of course the top 5 most listened to episodes of the year. Thanks for listening! 💚
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Notes and Links
Listener favs:
Go Time #250: Mat’s GopherCon EU diary
Ship It! #44: Fundamentals with Kelsey Hightower
The Changelog #454: The return of Richard Hipp
Backstage #18: Tenet with heavy spoilers
Backstage #23: The Oban Pro with Parker Selbert
The Changelog #464: This insa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The curl fragment trick]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20985</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/23/the-curl-fragment-trick/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T13:44:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[curl supports globbing in the sense that you can provide ranges or lists in the URL that will make curl iterate, loop, over all the different variations and do a separate transfer for each. For example, get ten images in a numeric range: curl "https://example.com/image[1-10].jpg" -O Or get them when named after some weekdays: curl … Continue reading The curl fragment trick →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graph machine learning with missing node features]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/graph-machine-learning-with-missing-node-features</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/graph-machine-learning-with-missing-node-features"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T12:15:57.586Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post discusses how feature propagation can be an efficient and scalable approach for handling missing features in graph machine learning applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring the impact of Twitter network latency with CausalImpact]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/measuring-the-impact-of-twitter-network-latency-with-causalimpac"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T12:15:57.570Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share how we adopted the CausalImpact package from Google on a Twitter edge network experiment to measure the impact of improving Twitter's latency on customer engagement and revenue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling data access by moving an exabyte of data to Google Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/scaling-data-access-by-moving-an-exabyte-of-data-to-google-cloud</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/scaling-data-access-by-moving-an-exabyte-of-data-to-google-cloud"/>
        <updated>2022-12-22T12:16:47.278Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we approached migrating an exabyte of data to Google Cloud to make it easier for our Tweeps to analyze and visualize data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NuBolão: How we built Nubank’s first social feature in less than six months]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19803</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/how-nubank-built-nubolao/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T22:35:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In less than six months, a small team of 6 Software Engineers, 2 Designers, 1 Business Analyst, 1 PM, 1 PMM and 1 Tech Manager built Nubank’s first social feature.
The post NuBolão: How we built Nubank’s first social feature in less than six months appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BU Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visualizing Live Hacking Events: Hackers Break Records at H1-702]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/visualizing-live-hacking-events-hackers-break-records-h1-702</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/visualizing-live-hacking-events-hackers-break-records-h1-702"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T22:02:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Checkout this infographic for a more detailed look at stats, hacker perspectives, and highlights of our event. Be sure to checkout all of our H@ckti]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2022 curl security audit]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=19480</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/21/the-2022-curl-security-audit/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T21:57:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[tldr: several hundred hours of dedicated scrutinizing of curl by a team of security experts resulted in two CVEs and a set of less serious remarks. The link to the reports is at the bottom of this article. Thanks to an OpenSSF grant, OSTIF helped us set up a curl security audit, which the excellent … Continue reading The 2022 curl security audit →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Gives 2022: Creating positive, lasting contributions in our communities]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69259</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-21-github-gives-2022-creating-positive-lasting-contributions-in-our-communities/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T16:06:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year, we took GitHub Gives, our company-wide giving campaign, to new heights and wanted to share our learnings to provide best practices in programming a successful hybrid giving campaign for employees.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toya East</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A drive to Taco Bell]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/taco-bell/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/taco-bell/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delivering on our first Twitter promise!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl 7.87.0]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20937</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/21/curl-7-87-0/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T07:12:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Numbers the 212th release5 changes56 days (total: 9,042)155 bug-fixes (total: 8,492)238 commits (total: 29,571)0 new public libcurl function (total: 91)2 new curl_easy_setopt() option (total: 302)1 new curl command line option (total: 249)83 contributors, 40 new (total: 2,771)42 authors, 20 new (total: 1,101)2 security fixes (total: 132)Bug Bounties total: 48,580 USD Release presentation At 10:00 CET … Continue reading curl 7.87.0 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brain Science 33: Your brain on burnout]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/13/1183</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/brainscience/33"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re back! This is from our “lost episodes” — This is your brain…and this is your brain on burnout, any questions? OK, but seriously, burnout effects everyone, even if they/you don’t admit it. Burnout is a state of physical, emotional, and mental exhaustion caused by prolonged stress. It can affect ANYONE, but it is especially common among high-performers who push themselves to the limit. In this episode, we dive into the latest research on burnout and its effects on the brain, as well as offer practical advice for preventing and managing burnout. If you’re heading into 2023 feeling overwhelmed and drained, this episode is for you.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!
Featuring
Mireille Reece, PsyD – LinkedIn
Adam Stacoviak – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Notes and Links
Burnout and the Brain
Alexandra Michel, MPH on Twitter
Are you headed towards burnout?
Simple Burnout Triage
Brain Science #30: I’m just so stressed
Recovering from burnout
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Increase developer productivity, save time on developer onboarding, and drive ROI in 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69237</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-20-increase-developer-productivity-save-time-on-developer-onboarding-and-drive-roi-in-2023/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T18:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forrester's Total Economic Impact™ study dives into how GitHub Enterprise Cloud and GitHub Advanced Security help businesses drive ROI, increase developer productivity, and save time on developer onboarding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeimy Ruiz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not just flightless birds: How EMUs secure and scale identity and access management for your GitHub Enterprise]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69213</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-20-emus-more-than-just-flightless-birds/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T18:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Enterprise has evolved to support the needs of enterprise administrators, corporate security teams, and individual developers who contribute to open source.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessi Moths</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we use GitHub to be more productive, collaborative, and secure]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69220</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-20-how-we-use-github-to-be-more-productive-collaborative-and-secure/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T17:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our engineering and security teams have done some incredible work in 2022. Let’s take a look at how we use GitHub to be more productive, build collaboratively, and shift security left.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Hanley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automatic retraining for machine learning models: tips and lessons learned]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19930</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/automatic-retraining-for-machine-learning-models/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T22:40:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post we'll go over some of the lessons we learned over the last years retraining models in an automatic fashion at Nubank.
The post Automatic retraining for machine learning models: tips and lessons learned appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felipe Almeida - Machine Learning Engineer at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Video] How has open source changed in the last 10 years?]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69175</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-19-video-how-has-open-source-changed-in-the-last-10-years/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T15:14:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What’s the state of open source and how has it changed over the last decade? GitHub’s VP of Developer Relations, Martin Woodward, tackles that question and more in a 2022 keynote.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Woodward</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl sighting: Tschugger]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=21134</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/19/curl-sighting-tschugger/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T07:22:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the Swiss crime comedy TV series Tschugger, season two episode two at roughly 25:20, there is a shot with a curl command line in a terminal window using an unnecessary –request option. Following the curl line is what looks like an interactive login procedure, which certainly is not something a real curl would present. … Continue reading curl sighting: Tschugger →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Quality Automation at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/data-quality-automation-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2022-12-17T12:14:40.752Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we share how Twitter implemented a Data Quality Platform that gave customers the ability to have automated data quality checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Powering real-time data analytics with Druid at Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/powering-real-time-data-analytics-with-druid-at-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/powering-real-time-data-analytics-with-druid-at-twitter"/>
        <updated>2022-12-17T12:14:40.738Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share an overview of Twitter’s Druid ecosystem and discuss our work towards a unified ingestion experience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 519: GPT has entered the chat]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1947</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/519"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To wrap up the year we’re talking about what’s breaking the internet, again. Yes, we’re talking about ChatGPT and we’re joined by our good friend Shawn “swyx” Wang. Between his writings on L-Space Diaries and his AI notes repo on GitHub, we had a lot to cover around the world of AI and what might be coming in 2023.
Also, we have one more show coming out before the end of the year — our 5th annual “State of the log” episode where Adam and Jerod look back at the year and talk through their favorite episodes of the year and feature voices from the community. So, stay tuned for that next week.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 16 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps and databases clos…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · November 2022 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=68919</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-16-release-radar-nov-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T19:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We promised we’d be back soon and here we are! There has been an incredible amount of open source projects shipping major version releases before the year wraps up. I can’t believe we are all saying that now. “When the year wraps up!” or “See you next year!” What happened to 2022? Well, we know […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is functional programming and how do we use that technology at Nubank?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19819</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/functional-programming-technology-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T18:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Find out what is a functional paradigm, how it differs from other paradigms and how we use that technology at Nubank.
The post What is functional programming and how do we use that technology at Nubank? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bruno Rodrigues - Senior Engineering Manager at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 256: Big news in Deno Land]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1922</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/256"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deno creator Ryan Dahl goes one-on-one with Jerod to discuss their new npm support, why he’s so excited about JavaScript containers, Deno Deploy’s present & future, what he thinks about alternative runtimes like Bun, WinterCG, how Wasm fits into the story & more!
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resolve problems quicker, and learn continuously about their applications - from the frontend to the backend. Use the code CHANGELOG and get the team plan free for three months.

    
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
Lolo Code – If you’re familiar with building severless apps, think of Lolo Code as your backend with a visual editor that lets you think and build at the same time. All this without having to provision or manage servers. Use the visual editor to build your app, connect nodes, and add any npm libraries you need. You can even write your own integrations. This makes Lolo Code very Zapier-ish, but for devs. Try it free today with no credit card required at lolo.co/jsparty

    
Featuring
Ryan Dahl – GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Notes and Links
Ryan on The Changelog #443
Deno 1.28 announcement
JavaScript ShadowRealms
JavaScript Containers
WinterCG
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability AI plans to let artists opt out of Stable Diffusion 3 image training]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ZoQk</id>
        <link href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/12/stability-ai-plans-to-let-artists-opt-out-of-stable-diffusion-3-image-training/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T15:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Wednesday, Stability AI announced it would allow artists to remove their work from the training dataset for an upcoming Stable Diffusion 3.0 release. The move comes as an artist advocacy group called Spawning tweeted that Stability AI would honor opt-out requests collected on its Have I Been Trained website. The details of how the plan will be implemented remain incomplete and unclear, however.
This seems like a step in the right direction, but it appears that artists will have to proactively register and manually flag matched images in the database. Ain’t nobody got time for that!
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and scalability for search]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2022/stability-and-scalability-for-search"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T12:15:55.027Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss how we power real-time search for Tweets, Users, Direct Messages and more using Elasticsearch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 260: Making Go more efficient]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1944</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/260"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T22:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mat invites Bartłomiej Płotka, Kemal Akkoyun & Christian Simon to discuss how to make Go code more efficient through modern observability practices.
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members get a bonus 12 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
Ship It! – A podcast about getting your best ideas into the world and seeing what happens. Listen to an episode that interests you and subscribe today.

    
Featuring
Bartlomiej Płotka – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Kemal Akkoyun – Mastodon, Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn
Christian Simon – Twitter
Mat Ryer – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Notes and Links
Bartek’s “Efficient Go” Book
Vitess Benchmark
Tools for Monitoring Applications Logs
Prometheus library for Go
Profiling Go Programs
pprof tool (also available in go tool pprof)
pkg.go.dev/net/http/pprof
pkg.go.dev/runtime/pprof
Building a Go Profiler using Go
Liz Rice on eBPF
Arena proposal
Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python magic methods you haven’t heard about]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/zDmn</id>
        <link href="https://martinheinz.dev/blog/87"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T17:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Python’s magic methods - also known as dunder (double underscore) methods - can be used to implement a lot of cool things. Most of the time we use them for simple stuff, such as constructors (__init__), string representation (__str__, __repr__) or arithmetic operators (__add__/__mul__). There are however many more magic methods which you probably haven’t heard about and in this article we will explore all of them (even the hidden and undocumented).
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Heinz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked a secret? Check your GitHub alerts…for free]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69128</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-15-leaked-a-secret-check-your-github-alerts-for-free/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T17:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub now allows you to track any leaked secrets in your public repository, for free. With secret scanning alerts, you can track and action on leaked secrets directly within GitHub.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mariam Sulakian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Advanced Security customers can now push protect their custom patterns]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69126</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-15-github-advanced-security-customers-can-now-push-protect-their-custom-patterns/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T17:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With just one click, admins in GitHub Advanced Security organizations can protect their custom patterns on push.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mariam Sulakian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expanding the App Defense Alliance]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/12/app-defense-alliance-expansion.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/12/app-defense-alliance-expansion.html"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T16:59:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Brooke Davis, Android Security and Privacy Team 
The App Defense Alliance launched in 2019 with a mission to protect Android users from bad apps through shared intelligence and coordinated detection between alliance partners.  Earlier this year, the App Defense Alliance expanded to include new initiatives outside of malware detection and is now the home for several industry-led collaborations including Malware Mitigation, MASA (Mobile App Security Assessment) & CASA (Cloud App Security Assessment). With a new dedicated landing page at appdefensealliance.dev, the ADA has an expanded mission to protect Android users by removing threats while improving app quality across the ecosystem. Let’s walk through some of the latest program updates from the past year, including the addition o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacker AFK: Jason Haddix]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/hacker-afk-jason-haddix</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/hackerone-community-blog/hacker-afk-jason-haddix"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T16:34:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's hacker Jason Haddix 
JXoaT: So, what was your first experience with the word hacker? 
Jason: My first exposure was similar to ot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSH server hardening]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Jgeb</id>
        <link href="https://ittavern.com/ssh-server-hardening/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T16:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you operate an SSH server that receives connections from the public, you owe it to yourself to read this list of things you can do to lock that sucker down.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A framework for building SQLite extensions in Rust]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Qp78</id>
        <link href="https://observablehq.com/@asg017/introducing-sqlite-loadable-rs"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T15:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[sqlite-loadable-rs is a new framework for writing fast, performant, and mostly-safe SQLite extensions in Rust. These extensions are nearly as fast those written in C, with the added benefit of Rust’s memory safety features, easy access to thousands of 3rd party crates and packages on crates.io, all while maintaining a splendid developer experience.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 83: 🎄 Planning for failure to ship faster 🎁]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1934</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/83"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eight months ago, in 🎧 episode 49, Alex Sims (Solutions Architect & Senior Software Engineer at James & James) shared with us his ambition to help migrate a monolithic PHP app running on AWS EC2 to a more modern architecture. The idea was some serverless, some EKS, and many incremental improvements.
So how did all of this work out in practice? How did the improved system cope with the Black Friday peak, as well as all the following Christmas orders? Thank you Alex for sharing with us your Ship It! inspired Kaizen story. It’s a wonderful Christmas present! 🎄🎁
Discuss on Changelog News
Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!
Sponsors
Sourcegraph – Transform your code into a queryable database to create customizable visual dashboards in seconds. Sourcegraph recently launched Code Insights — now you can track what really matters to you and your team in your codebase. See how other teams are using this awesome feature at about.sourcegraph.com/code-insights

    
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make sure you are quickly notified of the errors, crashes, and front-end performance issues that matter most to you and your business. Set thresholds for your alert based on an increase in error count, a spike in load time, or new issues introduced in the latest deployment. Start your free 14-day trial at Raygun.com

    
Featuring
Alex Sims – Twitter, LinkedIn
Gerhard Lazu – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links



  


  


Something missing or broken? PRs welcome!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing SvelteKit 1.0]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/qM1e</id>
        <link href="https://svelte.dev/blog/announcing-sveltekit-1.0"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T18:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congrats to the entire Svelte team (and contributors) for this release, which culminates two years of effort:
We’re so excited to share this release with you. It’s the culmination of thousands of hours of work, both from the Svelte core team and the wider community, and we think it’s the most enjoyable way to build production-grade websites, whether you’re a solo developer working on a small project or part of a large team.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raising the bar for software security: next steps for GitHub.com 2FA]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=69113</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-12-14-raising-the-bar-for-software-security-next-steps-for-github-com-2fa/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T17:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub will require all users who contribute code on GitHub.com to enable one or more forms of two-factor authentication (2FA) by the end of 2023. Learn more about our approach, when we’ll begin our rollout, and what you can expect as we begin requiring 2FA.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Swanson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple's Swift rewrite of its Foundation framework will be open source]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/V173</id>
        <link href="https://www.swift.org/blog/future-of-foundation/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T16:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Parker writing on Swift’s blog:
When Swift began life as an open source project, we wanted to open not just the language itself, but the ecosystem around it. Foundation has been instrumental in the success of decades of software and has been an integral part of the Swift developer experience from the beginning, and we knew it had to be included in the open source offering.
Historically, Apple’s open source efforts have varied in just how open they are when it comes to community. On that topic, this is an uplifting bit of prose:
Open source projects are at their best when the community of users can participate and become a community of developers. A new, open contribution process will be available to enable all developers to contribute new API to Foundation.
This new Foundation project is slated to launch on GitHub in 2023.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is It like being a Product Designer at Nubank?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19782</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/product-designer-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T15:59:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Product Designers are responsible for designing solutions that leave a positive impact using thorough understanding of the clients' and the business's needs. Check out more about this career:
The post What is It like being a Product Designer at Nubank? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Campanha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to rebuild social media on top of RSS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/y71e</id>
        <link href="https://tfos.co/p/rebuild-social-media/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T15:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jacob O’Bryant’s “Grand Vision For How Social Media Ought To Be”:
there should be a bunch of different:
publishing services, like Substack and Ghost
reading apps, like Gmail and Matter
community platforms, like Slack and Discord
and we should look for ways to make these reading, publishing, and community services all play nicely together. I’m calling this model “the unbundled web,” and I think RSS should be the primary method of interop.
Where do I sign up? 😉
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Rails from Docker for easy start to development]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Jg5d</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/rails/docked"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T13:57:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up Rails for the first time with all the dependencies necessary can be daunting for beginners. Docked Rails attempts to flatten the onboarding curve by only requiring a working Docker installation in order to get started making a new Rails application, working with that application during development, and running a basic server. All based on pre-configured commands and dependencies living in a Docker image.
Getting started is as easy as:
docker volume create ruby-bundle-cache
alias rails='docker run --rm -it -v ${PWD}:/rails -v ruby-bundle-cache:/bundle dhh37/rails'
alias rails-server='docker run --rm -it -v ${PWD}:/rails -v ruby-bundle-cache:/bundle -p 3000:3000 dhh37/rails server -b 0.0.0.0'

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IDN is crazy]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=20978</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/12/14/idn-is-crazy/"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T07:59:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IDN, International Domain Names, is the concept that lets us register and use international characters in domain names, and by international we of course mean characters outside of the ASCII range. Recently I have fought some battles against IDN and IDN decoding so I felt this urge to write a lot of words about it … Continue reading IDN is crazy →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>