<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-12-03T12:07:22.778Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scala Hands-On: a path to build and manage queries in Spark]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30520</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/scala-hands-on-a-path-to-build-and-manage-queries-in-spark/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-26T19:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover Nubank's approach to data transformation and governance using Scala and Spark
The post Scala Hands-On: a path to build and manage queries in Spark appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking down CPU speed: How utilization impacts performance]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81409</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/engineering/architecture-optimization/breaking-down-cpu-speed-how-utilization-impacts-performance/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-25T17:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Performance Engineering team at GitHub assessed how CPU performance degrades as utilization increases and how this relates to capacity.
The post Breaking down CPU speed: How utilization impacts performance appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Strikos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scala Hands-On: a path to build and manage queries in Spark]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30756</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/scala-hands-on-a-path-to-build-and-manage-queries-in-spark-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-25T14:11:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover Nubank's approach to data transformation and governance using Scala and Spark
The post Scala Hands-On: a path to build and manage queries in Spark appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple macOS kernel extension fuzzing in userspace with IDA and TinyInst]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/11/simple-macos-kernel-extension-fuzzing.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/11/simple-macos-kernel-extension-fuzzing.html"/>
        <updated>2024-11-21T17:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[@import url(https://themes.googleusercontent.com/fonts/css?kit=4mNYFHt_IKFsPe52toizH4mR01TXY79of1zCqFsVTVk);.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-5>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-5,lower-roman) ". "}.lst-kix_novl1in5rjiw-1>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-3>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-3,decimal) ". "}.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-4>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-4,lower-latin) ". "}.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-2>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-2,lower-roman) ". "}.lst-kix_novl1in5rjiw-0>li:before{content:"-  "}ol.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-0.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-0 0}.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-0>li:before{content:"" counter(lst-ctn-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-0,decimal) ". "}.lst-kix_sm5qq1cfkkfw-1>li:before{conte…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Students: Start building your skills with the GitHub Foundations certification]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81277</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/news-insights/company-news/students-start-building-your-skills-with-the-github-foundations-certification/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-21T16:23:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Foundations Certification exam fee is now waived for all students verified through GitHub Education.
The post Students: Start building your skills with the GitHub Foundations certification appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Morgan Ersery</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make Storybook Interactions respect user motion preferences]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81231</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/engineering/user-experience/how-to-make-storybook-interactions-respect-user-motion-preferences/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-20T17:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With this custom addon, you can ensure your workplace remains accessible to users with motion sensitivities while benefiting from Storybook’s Interactions.
The post How to make Storybook Interactions respect user motion preferences appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kendall Gassner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leveling Up Fuzzing: Finding more vulnerabilities with AI]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/11/leveling-up-fuzzing-finding-more.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/11/leveling-up-fuzzing-finding-more.html"/>
        <updated>2024-11-20T16:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Oliver Chang, Dongge Liu and Jonathan Metzman, Google Open Source Security Team


Recently, OSS-Fuzz reported 26 new vulnerabilities to open source project maintainers, including one vulnerability in the critical OpenSSL library (CVE-2024-9143) that underpins much of internet infrastructure. The reports themselves aren’t unusual—we’ve reported and helped maintainers fix over 11,000 vulnerabilities in the 8 years of the project. 



But these particular vulnerabilities represent a milestone for automated vulnerability finding: each was found with AI, using AI-generated and enhanced fuzz targets. The OpenSSL CVE is one of the first vulnerabilities in a critical piece of software that was discovered by LLMs, adding another real-world example to a recent Google discovery of an exploi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing GitHub Secure Open Source Fund: Help secure the open source ecosystem for everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81135</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/news-insights/company-news/announcing-github-secure-open-source-fund/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-19T17:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Applications for the new GitHub Secure Open Source Fund are now open! Applications will be reviewed on a rolling basis until they close on January 7 at 11:59 pm PT. Programming and funding will begin in early 2025.
The post Announcing GitHub Secure Open Source Fund: Help secure the open source ecosystem for everyone appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Woodward</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Gen AI: Copilot's new multi-file editing]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-11</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-11"/>
        <updated>2024-11-19T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A very powerful new coding assistance feature made its way into GitHub
       Copilot at the end of October. This new “multi-file editing” capability
       expands the scope of AI assistance from small, localized suggestions to
       larger implementations across multiple files. Birgitta
       Böckeler tries out this new capability and finds
       out how useful its changes tend to be, and wonders about what feedback
       loops are needed with them.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Empowering Latin America through innovation: Nu highlights at the George UX Conference 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30785</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/empowering-latin-america-through-innovation-nubank-george-ux-conference/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-19T15:16:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At George UX 2024, Nubank explored the role of design in simplifying finance and empowering over 110M customers in Latin America.
The post Empowering Latin America through innovation: Nu highlights at the George UX Conference 2024 appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Required Skills to be a Business Analyst at Nubank]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30737</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/required-skills-to-be-a-business-analyst-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-18T17:18:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To be a Business Analyst at Nubank, it's essential to combine different skills. This guide demonstrates how to tackle complex problems and turn challenges into strategic solutions.
The post Required Skills to be a Business Analyst at Nubank appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software is a team sport: Building the future of software development together]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81137</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/news-insights/company-news/software-is-a-team-sport-building-the-future-of-software-development-together/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-18T17:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft and GitHub are committed to empowering developers around the world to innovate, collaborate, and create solutions that’ll shape the next generation of technology. 
The post Software is a team sport: Building the future of software development together appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mario Rodriguez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does GitHub Copilot improve code quality? Here’s what the data says]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81151</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/news-insights/research/does-github-copilot-improve-code-quality-heres-what-the-data-says/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-18T16:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Findings in our latest study show that the quality of code written with GitHub Copilot is significantly more functional, readable, reliable, maintainable, and concise. 
The post Does GitHub Copilot improve code quality? Here’s what the data says appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jared Bauer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrofitting spatial safety to hundreds of millions of lines of C++]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/11/retrofitting-spatial-safety-to-hundreds.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/11/retrofitting-spatial-safety-to-hundreds.html"/>
        <updated>2024-11-15T17:42:00.015Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Alex Rebert and Max Shavrick, Security Foundations, and Kinuko Yasuda, Core Developer





Attackers regularly exploit spatial memory safety vulnerabilities, which occur when code accesses a memory allocation outside of its intended bounds, to compromise systems and sensitive data. These vulnerabilities represent a major security risk to users. 



Based on an analysis of in-the-wild exploits tracked by Google's Project Zero, spatial safety vulnerabilities represent 40% of in-the-wild memory safety exploits over the past decade:



Breakdown of memory safety CVEs exploited in the wild by vulnerability class.1
Google is taking a comprehensive approach to memory safety. A key element of our strategy focuses on Safe Coding and using memory-safe languages in new code. This leads to a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: October 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81131</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/news-insights/company-news/github-availability-report-october-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-14T23:41:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In October, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services. 
The post GitHub Availability Report: October 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Oleksy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How developers spend the time they save thanks to AI coding tools]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=81120</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/ai-and-ml/generative-ai/how-developers-spend-the-time-they-save-thanks-to-ai-coding-tools/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-14T17:32:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers tell us how GitHub Copilot and other AI coding tools are transforming their work and changing how they spend their days.
The post How developers spend the time they save thanks to AI coding tools appeared first on The GitHub Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klint Finley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safer with Google: New intelligent, real-time protections on Android to keep you safe]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2024/11/new-real-time-protections-on-Android.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2024/11/new-real-time-protections-on-Android.html"/>
        <updated>2024-11-13T17:59:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Lyubov Farafonova, Product Manager and Steve Kafka, Group Product Manager, Android


User safety is at the heart of everything we do at Google. Our mission to make technology helpful for everyone means building features that protect you while keeping your privacy top of mind. From Gmail’s defenses that stop more than 99.9% of spam, phishing and malware, to Google Messages’ advanced security that protects users from 2 billion suspicious messages a month and beyond, we're constantly developing and expanding protection features that help keep you safe.


We're introducing two new real-time protection features that enhance your safety, all while safeguarding your privacy: Scam Detection in Phone by Google to protect you from scams and fraud, and Google Play Protect live threat detect…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Posting on Bluesky, and other thoughts on social media]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/2024-social-media.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/2024-social-media.html"/>
        <updated>2024-11-13T17:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the recent uptick in tech activity on Bluesky, I've decided that
       I will start posting there in addition to
       my current locations.
I've also put together my general thoughts on the state of social
       media, and how I'm using it, now that it's two years since The Muskover. 
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Prepare for a Case Interview? (Part 3)]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30685</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/how-to-prepare-for-a-case-interview-part-3/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-13T13:10:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical Preparation for the Case Interview: Fundamental Tools and Concepts
The post How to Prepare for a Case Interview? (Part 3) appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix’s Distributed Counter Abstraction]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/8d0c45eb66b2</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/netflixs-distributed-counter-abstraction-8d0c45eb66b2?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2024-11-12T20:45:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By: Rajiv Shringi, Oleksii Tkachuk, Kartik Sathyanarayanan]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Prepare for a Case Interview? (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30672</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/how-to-prepare-for-a-case-interview-part-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-12T17:12:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Master the Essential Concepts and Stand Out in Case Interviews
The post How to Prepare for a Case Interview? (Part 2) appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crack the case: How the case interview works for the Business Analysis role at Nubank (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30658</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/crack-the-case-how-the-case-interview-works-for-the-business-analysis-role-at-nubank-part-1/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-11T16:32:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A practical guide with examples and annotated answers for those in the selection process
The post Crack the case: How the case interview works for the Business Analysis role at Nubank (Part 1) appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does a BA, or Business Analyst, do at Nubank?]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=19326</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/what-does-a-ba-or-business-analyst-do-at-nubank/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-06T21:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are looking for people to help build the purple future with Nubank
The post What does a BA, or Business Analyst, do at Nubank? appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assessing the results of using the Strangler Fig on a Mobile App]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/strangler-fig-mobile-apps.html#Results</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/strangler-fig-mobile-apps.html#Results"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew Foster and John Mikel Amiel
       Regida finish their account of how they incrementally modernized
       a mobile application by looking at the results of their work. They
       achieved a significant shortening of time to new value, and found that
       changes in the new application could be prepared in about half the time
       it took on the old codebase.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Nubank uses Spark to process data]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=30543</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/how-nubank-uses-spark-to-process-data/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-04T21:51:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Primarily designed for Big Data processing, Spark is notable for being completely open source
The post How Nubank uses Spark to process data appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>