<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-02-16T12:14:00.441Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://feed.ramonmedeiros.dev/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Enterprise Server 3.4 improves developer productivity and adds reusable workflows to CI/CD]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=63223</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-15-ghes-3-4-developer-productivity-reusable-workflows-ci-cd/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T23:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Enterprise Server 3.4 release candidate delivers enhancements to make life easier and more productive, from keyboard shortcuts to auto-generated release notes!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 168: One algorithm to rule them all?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1588</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/168"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From MIT researchers who have an AI system that rapidly predicts how two proteins will attach, to Facebook’s first high-performance self-supervised algorithm that works for speech, vision, and text, Daniel and Chris survey the AI landscape for notable milestones in the application of AI in industry and research.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
The first high-performance self-supervised algorithm that works for speech, vision, and text
DeepMind says its new AI coding engine is as good as an average human programmer
Artificial intelligence system rapidly predicts how two proteins will attach
Seeing Theory]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Version 100 in Chrome and Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47607</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/02/version-100-in-chrome-and-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T18:05:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome and Firefox will reach version 100 in a couple of months. This has the potential to cause breakage on sites that rely on identifying the browser version to perform business logic.  This post covers the timeline of events, the strategies that Chrome and Firefox are taking to mitigate the impact, and how you can help.
The post Version 100 in Chrome and Firefox appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karl Dubost</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GitHub Stars in our eyes ⭐️]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=63146</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-15-the-github-stars-in-our-eyes/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T17:17:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past year, the GitHub Stars have made a tremendous impact in the community with their influence, inspiring and building communities and creating content to help everyone.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anisha Pindoria</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Balanced Portfolio: Rebalancing]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/the-balanced-portfolio-rebalancing</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/the-balanced-portfolio-rebalancing"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T17:04:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Monthly purchases and changes to the asset allocation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 480: Git your reset on]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1578</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/480"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Annie Sexton, UX Engineer at Render, to talk about her blog post titled Git Organized: A Better Git Flow that made the internet explode when she suggested using reset instead of rebase for a better git flow. On this show we talk about the git flow she suggests and why, how this flow works for her when she’s hacking on the Render codebase (and when she uses it), the good and the bad of Git, and we also talked about the cognitive load of Git commits as you work.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry helps teams see what actually matters, resol…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the 2022 MLH Fellowship Cohort, powered by GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=63095</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-15-announcing-2022-mlh-fellowship-cohort-powered-by-github/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T15:58:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MLH Fellowship, powered by GitHub, is a 12-week internship alternative for aspiring software engineers. Meet the 2022 cohort!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bass</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we lost (when we went remote)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/eZnD</id>
        <link href="https://randsinrepose.com/archives/what-we-lost/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T15:45:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rands asking himself some tough questions about our “new normal” remote work environments:
Relative to the Pandemic, the single biggest work question I’ve been asking myself for two years is: what did we lose? What is the measurable and objective loss for teams not working in close proximity? I’ve been looking for cracks. I’ve been looking for leading indicators of future doom. The Great Resignation seems like a proper crack, right? But are people quitting their jobs because they can’t work together or because their current job sucks and all this terror in the air has given them a new appreciation of what really matters?
A sobering perspective.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implications of Wordpress joining the Block Protocol]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/RRnG</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2022/02/implications-wordpress-joining-block-protocol/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T14:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leonardo Losoviz is pretty excited that Matt Mullenweg expressed interest in having WordPress’s editor comply with the Block Protocol:
My excitement comes from what happened with GraphQL, where the release of servers, clients, and tools adhering to a common specification has produced a rich ecosystem; and from my own development of a plugin that could support new features through the protocol.
Don’t fret if you’re new to this “Block Protocol” concept, like myself: Leonardo starts off this (long) article with a nice explainer before he gets into the potential outcomes of WordPress’s involvement.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing your own sudo]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/73b9</id>
        <link href="https://rtpg.co/2022/02/13/your-own-sudo.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T21:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how sudo works by writing your own version in Python!
One might think that sudo is actually some binary deeply integrated into the kernel, relying on a special purpose-built system call to achieve its functionality. After all, it lets you use root without even providing the password for that account! But thanks to one bit inside file permissions, sudo can exist without any of this.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The great curl roadmap 2022 webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18421</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/02/14/the-great-curl-roadmap-2022-webinar/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T17:26:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the beginning of every year I jot down a couple of “larger things” I would like to work on during the year. Some of the ideas are more in the maybe category and meant to be tested on the audience and users to see what others think and want, others are features I believe … Continue reading The great curl roadmap 2022 webinar →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[🌹 Roses are red, Violets are blue 💙 Giving leets 🧑‍💻 more sweets 🍭 All of 2022!]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/02/roses-are-red-violets-are-blue-giving.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/02/roses-are-red-violets-are-blue-giving.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T17:07:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Eduardo Vela, Vulnerability Matchmaker 

Until December 31 2022 we will pay 20,000 to 91,337 USD for exploits of vulnerabilities in the Linux Kernel, Kubernetes, GKE or kCTF that are exploitable on our test lab.
We launched an expansion of kCTF VRP on November 1, 2021 in which we paid 31,337 to 50,337 USD to those that are able to compromise our kCTF cluster and obtain a flag. We increased our rewards because we recognized that in order to attract the attention of the community we needed to match our rewards to their expectations. We consider the expansion to have been a success, and because of that we would like to extend it even further to at least until the end of the year (2022).
During the last three months, we received 9 submissions and paid over 175,000 USD so far. The sub…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Include diagrams in your Markdown files with Mermaid]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=63053</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-14-include-diagrams-markdown-files-mermaid/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T16:57:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A picture tells a thousand words. Now you can quickly create and edit diagrams in markdown using words with Mermaid support in your Markdown files.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Woodward</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The life of MS-DOS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/O2nL</id>
        <link href="https://b13rg.github.io/Life-of-MS-DOS/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T15:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief (6 minutes to read) history of MS-DOS:
First released on August 12, 1981, MS-DOS became the foundation for business computing for almost two decades. MS-DOS stood for Microsoft Disk Operating System and was often referred to simply as “DOS”. It is the software that helped build Microsoft, becoming the foundation Microsoft built the Windows operating system on. It went through 8 (and a half-ish) major revisions, with the final version being shipped with Windows ME in September, 2000.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNNs through the lens of differential geometry and algebraic topology]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2021/graph-neural-networks-through-the-lens-of-differential-geometry-</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2021/graph-neural-networks-through-the-lens-of-differential-geometry-"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T12:14:05.461Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we show how tools from the fields of differential geometry and algebraic topology can be used to reinterpret GNNs and address some of their common plights in a principled way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A hybrid approach to personalize notification volume]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/a-hybrid-approach-to-personalize-notification-volume</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/a-hybrid-approach-to-personalize-notification-volume"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T12:14:04.880Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we’ll share how we use machine learning techniques to ensure people see the right amount of relevant and timely notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speeding up Transformer CPU inference in Google Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2021/speeding-up-transformer-cpu-inference-in-google-cloud</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2021/speeding-up-transformer-cpu-inference-in-google-cloud"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T08:59:12.513Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog post shares optimization findings to speed up Transformer-based models’ CPU inference and improve computational demand in Google Cloud.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forecasting SQL query resource usage with machine learning]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2021/forecasting-sql-query-resource-usage-with-machine-learning</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2021/forecasting-sql-query-resource-usage-with-machine-learning"/>
        <updated>2022-02-13T12:12:33.673Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we apply machine learning techniques at Twitter to forecast SQL query resource utilization during the development and maintenance of our large-scale SQL system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founders Talk 87: Building an investment platform for everyone]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/4/1484</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/founderstalk/87"/>
        <updated>2022-02-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Adam is joined by Joe Percoco — the Co-CEO of Titan, a premier investment manager for everyone. Titan is an investment company, a media, and a tech company, all rolled into one. Mid last year, they closed a $58 million Series B round led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) at a $450 million valuation. They currently have $750 million in assets managed and more than 35,000 clients.
Why should Titan exist? In Joe’s words, “Wall Street ignores everyday investors, and caters only to the ultra wealthy. This divide doesn’t sit well with us. So, we built Titan.” On today’s show Joe shares the journey, the why’s, the how’s, and the sequencing it might take to get to a $1 trillion of assets managed.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and mak…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backstage 21: Long-time listener, first-time code contributor]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/12/1586</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/backstage/21"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Simey de Klerk recenty dove head-first into our transcripts repo and coded up a super-cool feature that’s been on Jerod’s wishlist for awhile now. So, of course, we invited him Backstage to tell the tale!
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Featuring
Simey de Klerk – Twitter
Adam Stacoviak – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
The issue: A GitHub Action to auto-improve transcripts
The post: Auto-improved transcripts with GitHub Actions
The script: format.js
Our survey-game repo
Eric Normand talks FP with us]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 39: Haunted codebases & complex ops]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1539</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/39"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we are talking to Robin Morero, the person behind fabled.se, a DevOps consultancy from Gothenburg, Sweden. Their motto is “move faster and prosper”, which Gerhard prefers to the initial “move fast and break things”.
Fabled works with startups primarily, and after 26 years, Robin has a few interesting insights to share. What do you think, are haunted codebases real? At what point do pull requests become harmful? What about k3s running on KVM as a simple starting point for production? If this reminds you of #7, and the follow-up YouTube stream with Lars, it’s no coincidence.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Shortcut – The first project management platform for software development that bring…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with project planning on GitHub]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=63029</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-11-getting-started-with-project-planning-on-github/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T17:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stop context switching. Keep your team’s project planning next to your code.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 212: A deep-dive on Vite]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1563</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/212"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amal and Nick load up on coffee for a not-so-vite (lame joke!) conversation with Evan You all about Vite – a batteries included next-generation frontend tooling library. Vite continues to push the ecosystem forward with even stronger defaults, super speedy local development workflows, and a highly extensible universal plugin API. Need we say more?!
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Retool – Retool is a low-code platform built specifically for developers that makes it fast and easy to build internal tools. Instead of building internal tools from scratch, the world’s best teams, from startups to Fortune 500s, are using Retool to power their internal apps. Learn more and try it for free at retool.com/c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next generation data insights using natural language queries]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/next-generation-data-insights-using-natural-language-queries</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/next-generation-data-insights-using-natural-language-queries"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T12:13:04.332Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog, we share details about how we built an in-house product called Qurious, which allows our internal customers to get answers to their analytical queries through natural language questions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to start using reusable workflows with GitHub Actions]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62982</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-10-using-reusable-workflows-github-actions/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T17:56:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reusable workflows offer a simple and powerful way to avoid copying and pasting workflows across your repositories.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Douglas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 216: Building and using APIs with Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1565</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/216"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Natalie and Johnny are joined by the co-founders of APIToolkit for a deep-dive on the topic. We discuss building them, maintaining them, how can we all be better users, and much more along the way.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
SignalWire – Build what’s next in communications with video, voice, and messaging APIs powered by elastic cloud infrastructure. Try it today at signalwire.com/video and mention “JS Party” to receive an extra 5,000 video minutes.

    
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service catalogs, respond to incidents, communicate through status pages, and learn with retrospectives. Try FireHydrant free for 14 days at firehydrant.io

    
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Smile Egbai – Twitter, GitHub
Anthony Alaribe – Twitter, GitHub
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
APIToolkit.io
Do schools kill creativity? | Sir Ken Robinson]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulnerability Reward Program: 2021 Year in Review]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/02/vulnerability-reward-program-2021-year.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/02/vulnerability-reward-program-2021-year.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T17:00:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Sarah Jacobus, Vulnerability Rewards Team 


Last year was another record setter for our Vulnerability Reward Programs (VRPs). Throughout 2021, we partnered with the security researcher community to identify and fix thousands of  vulnerabilities – helping keep our users and the internet safe. 

Thanks to these incredible researchers, Vulnerability Reward Programs across Google continued to grow, and we are excited to report that in 2021 we awarded a record breaking $8,700,000 in vulnerability rewards – with researchers donating over $300,000 of their rewards to a charity of their choice. 

We also launched bughunters.google.com in 2021, a public researcher portal dedicated to keeping Google products and the internet safe and secure. This new platform brings all of our VRPs (Googl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A walk through Project Zero metrics]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2022/02/a-walk-through-project-zero-metrics.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2022/02/a-walk-through-project-zero-metrics.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T16:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ol.lst-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-3.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-3 0}.lst-kix_sr4t049r1bof-6>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_sr4t049r1bof-6}.lst-kix_ygk8qly5wagc-7>li:before{content:"\0025cb  "}.lst-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-6>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-6}.lst-kix_ygk8qly5wagc-6>li:before{content:"\0025cf  "}.lst-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-7>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-7}ol.lst-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-0.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_p008n8rtcs1c-0 0}.lst-kix_ygk8qly5wagc-8>li:before{content:"\0025a0  "}ol.lst-kix_sr4t049r1bof-1.start{counter-reset:lst-ctn-kix_sr4t049r1bof-1 0}.lst-kix_sr4t049r1bof-5>li{counter-increment:lst-ctn-kix_sr4t049r1bof-5}.lst-kix_7tz9dwqwiu1-5>li:before{content:"\0025a0  "}.lst-kix_7tz9dwqwiu1-4>li:before{content:"\0025cb  "}.lst-kix_7tz9dwqwiu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview questions to ask your interviewer]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/W3no</id>
        <link href="https://daveceddia.com/interview-questions-to-ask-company/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T15:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dave Ceddia shares his go-to list of questions that he (literally) printed and brought with him to interviews for that final 5-ish minutes at the end when you get a chance to ask your own questions. It does come with a small disclaimer, though:
This was years ago by the way, long before COVID, when pretty much every interview was in-person. The shock factor of pulling out 2 pages of questions wouldn’t translate so well to Zoom, haha. But still: if time runs out, you can mention that you still have a bunch of questions, and could please email them afterward.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PgBouncer rewritten in Rust]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/4Eq3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/levkk/pgcat"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T14:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PgBouncer is a popular connection pooler for Postgres. PgCat is that same functionality, only in Rust. This is alpha software and there is no worse place to run alpha software (IMHO) than in places that have direct connections to your database. Still, this is worth linking to because it’s yet another instance of open source infrastructure code getting Rusty.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My work on tool vs library]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18392</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/02/10/my-work-on-tool-vs-library/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T13:29:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m the lead developer in the curl project. We make the command line tool curl and the library libcurl, for doing Internet transfers. The command line tool uses the library for all the internet transfer heavy lifting. The command line tool is somewhat of a shell binding to access libcurl. We make these things. We … Continue reading My work on tool vs library →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coordinated vulnerability disclosure (CVD) for open source projects]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62926</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-09-coordinated-vulnerability-disclosure-cvd-open-source-projects/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T20:24:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A comprehensive guide for vulnerability reporters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nancy Gariché</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data pipeline asset management with Dataflow]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/86525b3e21ca</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/data-pipeline-asset-management-with-dataflow-86525b3e21ca?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T17:33:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[by Sam Setegne, Jai Balani, Olek Gorajek]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 167: 🌍 AI in Africa - Voice & language tools]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1584</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/167"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third of the “AI in Africa” spotlight episodes, we welcome Kathleen Siminyu, who is building Kiswahili voice tools at Mozilla. We had a great discussion with Kathleen about creating more diverse voice and language datasets, involving local language communities in NLP work, and expanding grassroots ML/AI efforts across Africa.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Kathleen Siminyu – Twitter, LinkedIn
Joyce Nabende – Twitter
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
“Introducing myself” from Kathleen
Masakhane
Common Voice
Open for Good Alliance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charts to watch #1]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/charts-to-watch-1</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/charts-to-watch-1"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T16:06:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crypto, stocks and ETFs with an interesting graphic setup]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing Digital Transformation with Vulnerability Disclosure: A Q&A with John Deere CISO, James Johnson]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/vulnerability-disclosure/securing-digital-transformation-vulnerability-disclosure-qa-john-deere</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/vulnerability-disclosure/securing-digital-transformation-vulnerability-disclosure-qa-john-deere"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To help fortify security defenses for their customers, dealers, suppliers, and employees, John Deere recently launched a public Vulnerability Disclosure Program (VDP) with HackerOne.

HackerOne recently met with James Johnson, CISO at John Deere, to learn why his security team works with ethical hackers to help identify security gaps and increase their product and data security.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevToys for macOS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/N5rd</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/ObuchiYuki/DevToysMac"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T15:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple weeks back I expressed some Windows FOMO* while linking out to a very cool Swiss Army knife for developers project. Well, FOMO-be-gone! There is now a DevToys project for we Mac users.
*I have since been informed of DevUtils.app, which is also worth a gander.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Garage - a self-hosted distributed object storage solution]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/n7b2</id>
        <link href="https://garagehq.deuxfleurs.fr/blog/2022-introducing-garage/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Garage is a distributed storage solution, that automatically replicates your data on several servers. Garage takes into account the geographical location of servers, and ensures that copies of your data are located at different locations when possible for maximal redundancy, a unique feature in the landscape of distributed storage systems.
It has an S3-compatible API and can be used as a storage backend for things like NextCloud, Matrix, and Mastodon. It’s being built by a non-profit in France that is “working to promote self-hosting and small-scale hosting.” Why do they do this?
self-hosting means running our own hardware at home, and providing 24/7 Internet services from there. We have many reasons for doing this. One is because this is the only way we can truly control who has access to our data. Another one is that it helps us be aware of the physical substrate of which the Internet is made: making the Internet run has an environmental cost which we want to evaluate and keep under control. The physical hardware also gives us a sense of community, calling to mind all of the people that could currently be connected and making use of our services, and reminding us of the purpose for which we are doing this.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RAID-Z expansion feature for ZFS goes live]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/rlpr</id>
        <link href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/blog/raid-z-expansion-feature-for-zfs-goes-live/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T22:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This major undertaking was discussed by Matt Ahrens on our recent ZFS episode. How it works:
The feature reflows existing data, essentially rewriting it onto a new arrangement of disks – meaning the original group plus a newly added disk. In so doing, a new adjacent chunk of free space is created at the end of the logical RAID-Z group and thus at the end of each physical disk.
With a disclaimer:
While all capabilities of this feature have been implemented and all tests so far have been passed, there are still a few loose ends to tie up. Specifically, there is some code cleanup to do, some verbose logging to remove, some code documentation to write, and similar relatively minor tasks. We aim for this to be integrated by Q3.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving the developer experience for Dependabot alerts]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62828</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-08-improving-developer-experience-dependabot-alerts/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T19:11:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re shipping improvements to Dependabot alerts that make them easier to understand and remediate.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin Havens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Settings are not a design failure]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/aOrD</id>
        <link href="https://linear.app/blog/settings-are-not-a-design-failure"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adrien Griveau makes the case for settings as a feature, not a design bug. He build the argument from a simple (and perhaps controversial) point: “users love settings”
There certainly are moments where I find myself on the settings page of a product because it failed to deliver the experience I really wanted. But not all settings are created equal.
There’s a difference between product settings that a product needs to get right by default and preferences that designers deliberately shouldn’t have a strong opinion on.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 479: Principles for hiring engineers]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1555</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/479"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Jacob Kaplan-Moss and we’re talking about his extensive writing on work sample tests. These tests are an exercise, a simulation, or a small slice of real day-to-day work that candidates will perform as part of their job. Over the years, as an engineering leader, Jacob has become a practicing expert in effectively hiring engineers — today he shares a wealth of knowledge on the subject.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s business needs. Learn more at developer.squareup.com to dive into the docs, APIs, SDKs and to create your …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask a Techspert: What does AI do when it doesn’t know?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.google/technology/health/ask-a-techspert-what-does-ai-do-when-it-doesnt-know/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.google/technology/health/ask-a-techspert-what-does-ai-do-when-it-doesnt-know/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As humans, we constantly learn from the world around us. We experience inputs that shape our knowledge — including the boundaries of both what we know and what we don’t know.
Many of today’s machines also learn by example. However, these machines are typically trained on datasets and information that doesn’t always include rare or out-of-the-ordinary examples that inevitably come up in real-life scenarios. What is an algorithm to do when faced with the unknown?
I recently spoke with Abhijit Guha Roy, an engineer on the Health AI team, and Ian Kivlichan, an engineer on the Jigsaw team, to hear more about using AI in real-world scenarios and better understand the importance of training it to know when it doesn’t know.
Abhijit, tell me about your recent research in the dermatology space.
We’r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AI</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving the Storage Access API in Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47599</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/02/improving-the-storage-access-api-in-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T16:59:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before we roll out State Partitioning for all Firefox users, we intend to make a few privacy and ergonomic improvements to the Storage Access API. In this blog post, we’ll detail a few of the new changes we made. 
The post Improving the Storage Access API in Firefox appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin VanderSloot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working with the Kubernetes API]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/P5ra</id>
        <link href="https://iximiuz.com/en/series/working-with-kubernetes-api/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T16:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A (WIP) series on working with the K8s API from both the command line and from code.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My thirty years of dodging repetitive work with automation tools]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/AaoP</id>
        <link href="https://www.tines.com/blog/my-thirty-years-of-dodging-repetitive-work-with-automation-tools"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T15:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conor O’Neill:
I blame my life-long work obsession with automation and avoiding repetitive drudgery on my first boss and mentor Danny in S3. He was horrified to see me doing the same thing over and over in a VAX code editor and introduced me to the magical world of macros.
From that point onwards, I was a man on a mission to save us all as much time as possible in our working days.
From Yahoo! Pipes to IFTTT to Node-RED and beyond: this is quite the journey.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Health: Now You're Thinking With Functions]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2022/02/code-health-now-youre-thinking-with.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2022/02/code-health-now-youre-thinking-with.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T17:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is another post in our Code Health series. A version of this post originally appeared in Google bathrooms worldwide as a Google Testing on the Toilet episode. You can download a printer-friendly version to display in your office. 


by Cathal Weakliam


Loops are the standard way to process collections like arrays and lists. However, some loops implement the same patterns repeatedly, leading to duplicate code. Higher-order functions—functions that use other functions as inputs or outputs—can reduce duplication by providing a simpler way to express common operations with collections.


Consider these two loops in JavaScript that decide if every object in an array meets a condition:


 
  
    
let everyRequestValid = true;
for (const request of requests) {
  if (!isValid(request)) {
  …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An all-in-one guide to getting a tech job abroad]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/zgr5</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/AndrewStetsenko/tech-jobs-with-relocation"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Stetsenko:
Relocation to a foreign country for work can be very exciting and lead to unique opportunities that couldn’t be accessed in your home country. At the same time, it’s a real challenge - I know it firsthand… Hopefully, this handbook will give you the necessary guidance. Topics covered include resume preparation, job search, salary negotiation, relocation packages, and more.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, She Codes: Nubank opens applications for the 4th edition of the software engineers hiring program]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18086</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/yes-she-codes-nubank-fourth-edition-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T16:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, She Codes is back! Applications for the program are open until February 13. See more details about the event and learn how to apply
The post Yes, She Codes: Nubank opens applications for the 4th edition of the software engineers hiring program appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PyFlow – a tool for visual and modular block programming in Python]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/RRrG</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/Bycelium/PyFlow"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T14:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s still in closed beta, but this looks like a really cool environment for data scientists and other folks who code to accomplish other goals vs code as craft. One cool thing you can do is take your Jupyter notebooks and convert them to PyFlow graphs (and vice versa).
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing a new Swift package for Apache Thrift]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2022/introducing-twitter-apache-thrift</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/open-source/2022/introducing-twitter-apache-thrift"/>
        <updated>2022-02-05T12:10:17.651Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter’s new Thrift library is an open-source, standalone, lightweight, data encoding library. In this blog, we share our library so iOS developers outside Twitter can start using Thrift data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · January 2022 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62511</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-04-release-radar-jan-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T23:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's January's top staff picks on projects that shipped major version releases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 478: Learning from incidents]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1556</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/478"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we’re joined by Nora Jones, founder and CEO at Jeli where they help teams gain insight and learnings from incidents. Back in December Nora shared here thoughts in a Changelog post titled “Incident” shouldn’t be a four-letter word - which got a lot of attention from our readers. Today we’re talking with Nora about all things incidents — the learning and growth they represent for teams, why teams should focus on learning from incidents in the first place, their Howie guide to post‑incident investigations, why the next emerging role is an Incident Analyst, and she also shares a few book recommendations which we’ve linked up in the show notes.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
InfluxData – Inf…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curl gets a --json flag]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/k2qy</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/02/02/curl-dash-dash-json/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T19:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Stenberg’s first step toward adding first-party JSON support to everyone’s favorite command-line URL transmitter is a flag that is basically a shortcut for the following flags:
--data [arg]
--header "Content-Type: application/json"
--header "Accept: application/json"

Will more come of this? Time (and the community) will tell…
The discussion has been ignited in the curl community about what, if anything, we should do in curl to make it a smoother and better tool when working with JSON. The offered opinions range from nothing (“curl is content agnostic”) to full-fledged JSON generator, parser and pretty-printer (or a combination in between).
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[People at the center of the strategy: the first step to innovation]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18070</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/matt-swann-people-at-the-center-of-the-strategy-the-first-step-to-innovation/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T18:56:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The key role of customer-centricity in creating continuous improvement cycles and mechanisms to inspect metrics, processes, and incidents, thus engaging tech teams
The post People at the center of the strategy: the first step to innovation appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Swann - Chief Technology Officer at Nubank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 211: A Solid option for building UIs]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1541</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/211"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Carniato joins Jerod, Amelia, and Nick to discuss SolidjS – a declarative, efficient, and flexible JavaScript library for building user interfaces.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make sure you are quickly notified of the errors, crashes, and front-end performance issues that matter most to you and your business. Set thresholds for your alert based on an increase in error count, a spike in load time, or new issues introduced in the latest deployment. Start your free 14-day trial at Raygun.com

    
SignalWire – Build what’s next in communications with video, voice, and messaging APIs powered by elastic cloud infrastructure. Try it today at signalwire.com/video and mention “JS Party” to receive an extra 5,000 video minutes.

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Ryan Carniato – Twitter, GitHub
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Amelia Wattenberger – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Nick Nisi – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Holla! JSConf Mexico (On YouTube)
SolidJS website
JS Framework Benchmark
Isomorphic UI Benchmark
Ryan Florence Tweet
Solid Start meta-framework
MarkoJS]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portfolio Performance review: 02.04]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/portfolio-performance-review-0204</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/portfolio-performance-review-0204"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T16:25:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Balanced and Pure Stock Portfolios]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AstroVim is an aesthetic/feature-rich Neovim config]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/wkdo</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/kabinspace/AstroVim"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T15:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ships with a file explorer, autocompletion, git integration, status line, fuzzy finding, and more.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 38: Go for the bananas]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1538</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/38"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gunnar Holwerda (Engineering Manager) and Tom Pansino (DevOps Team Lead) share with us a few stories about how the teams at opensesame.com manage AWS operational complexity. The first link in the episode show notes are the slides that Tom & Gunnar prepared for this conversation. Check them out as you hear us speak about the Inverse Conway Manoeuvre, and why you should always go for the bananas.
If you like this episode, and have a similar story to share, please reach out to us. We all love real-world stories that we can learn from, and perhaps contribute to.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Tailwind to design HTML emails]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/d38l</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/soheilpro/mailwind"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T14:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anybody who’s had to design/implement HTML emails knows how utterly painful it is. With Mailwind you get to do it the same way you’d build a site with Tailwind and then run:
mailwind --input-html email.html --output-css style.css
# or for inline styles
mailwind --input-html email.html --output-html email-inlined.html

And you’re off to the outbox! 📤
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, I can connect to a DB in CSS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/lb4W</id>
        <link href="https://www.leemeichin.com/posts/yes-i-can-connect-to-a-db-in-css.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T18:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just wow. This is an impressively hacky hack. You’re probably wondering how? As many such things do, it all starts with a new (Chrome-only) API:
A new set of APIs affectionately known as Houdini give your browser the power to control CSS via its own Object Model in Javascript. In English, this means that you can make custom CSS styles, add custom properties, and so on…
And it ends with something that looks like this:
main {
  // ...
  --sql-query: SELECT name FROM test;
}

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 215: MLOps in Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1518</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/215"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MLOps is an increasingly popular topic that is no longer just a subset of DevOps. Go is a great choice for infrastructure. What role does Go play in MLOps?
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
SignalWire – Build what’s next in communications with video, voice, and messaging APIs powered by elastic cloud infrastructure. Try it today at signalwire.com/video and mention “Go Time” to receive an extra 5,000 video minutes.

    
FireHydrant – The reliability platform for every developer. Incidents impact everyone, not just SREs. FireHydrant gives teams the tools to maintain service catalogs, respond to incidents, communicate through status pages, and learn with retrospectives. Try FireHydrant free for 14 days at firehydrant.io

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Featuring
Mike Eastham – Twitter, LinkedIn
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Johnny Boursiquot – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Uber’s Michelangelo project
What is a Feature and a Feature Store
Contribute to FEAST]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Wordle clone in less than 50 lines of bash]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/pkEM</id>
        <link href="https://gist.github.com/huytd/6a1a6a7b34a0d0abcac00b47e3d01513"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T15:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read the comments for all the bug reports and iteration. 🔥

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: January 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62836</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-02-github-availability-report-january-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T00:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In January, we experienced no incidents resulting in service downtime to our core services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott Sanders</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to build a CI/CD pipeline with GitHub Actions in four simple steps]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62762</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-02-build-ci-cd-pipeline-github-actions-four-steps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T19:48:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quick guide on the advantages of using GitHub Actions as your preferred CI/CD tool—and how to build a CI/CD pipeline with it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Douglas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New sponsors-only repositories, custom amounts, and more]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62801</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-02-new-sponsors-only-repositories-custom-amounts-and-more/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T18:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with the release of sponsors-only repositories, here’s a look at what’s new and what’s next for Sponsors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Lord</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Algorithms implemented in Go (for education)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/j5Zq</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/TheAlgorithms/Go"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T17:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A nice set of algorithms implemented with Go best practices in mind, making this a good learning resource. I wonder how much churn we’ll see on these once generics are officially added to the language… 🤔
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mizu – an API traffic viewer for Kubernetes]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/EQrQ</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/up9inc/mizu"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T17:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Think TCPDump and Wireshark re-invented for Kubernetes.”

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life of a DNS query]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/bNrW</id>
        <link href="https://wizardzines.com/comics/life-of-a-dns-query/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T15:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’d prefer code over comics, see instead her little Go program that explains the same.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CasaOS – a home cloud system based on the Docker ecosystem]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/W3ro</id>
        <link href="https://www.casaos.io/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T14:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They brand CasaOS as an operating system, but it’s really a layer on top of Linux that provides a nice UI and easy app (docker container) installation. It’s early days for the project, but we definitely need some open source options in this space, so here’s hoping they continue to progress!

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join the openpilot team!]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.comma.ai/openpilot-hiring/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.comma.ai/openpilot-hiring/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The openpilot team is one of three teams at comma. Our main goal is to provide a stable and highly reliable platform for the research team’s models to run on. This includes everything from the OS our devices run to the cars that openpilot drives. We’re looking for great engineers who want to work on all parts of that stack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>comma.ai blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrospective and Technical Details on the recent Firefox Outage]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47574</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/02/retrospective-and-technical-details-on-the-recent-firefox-outage/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T09:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On January 13th 2022, Firefox became unusable for close to two hours for users worldwide. This incident interrupted many people’s workflow. This post highlights the complex series of events and circumstances that, together, triggered a bug deep in the networking code of Firefox. What Happened? Firefox has a number of servers and related infrastructure that […]
The post Retrospective and Technical Details on the recent Firefox Outage appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Holler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl dash-dash-json]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18389</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/02/02/curl-dash-dash-json/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T08:12:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The curl “cockpit” is yet again extended with a new command line option: --json. The 245th command line option. curl is a generic transfer tool for sending and receiving data across networks and it is completely agnostic as to what it transfers or even why. To allow users to craft all sorts of transfers, or … Continue reading curl dash-dash-json →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The unreasonable effectiveness of one-on-ones]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/q0rL</id>
        <link href="https://www.benkuhn.net/11/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T22:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Kuhn is a big fan of one-on-one meeting between managers and their direct reports to discuss whatever the report wants. So, he suggested his partner try them with him to improver her graduate program experience.
In the end, they succeeded far beyond my expectations: Eve thinks our one-on-ones sped up her dissertation by about a year.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 166: Exploring deep reinforcement learning]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1568</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/166"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to being a Developer Advocate at Hugging Face, Thomas Simonini is building next-gen AI in games that can talk and have smart interactions with the player using Deep Reinforcement Learning (DRL) and Natural Language Processing (NLP).  He also created a Deep Reinforcement Learning course that takes a DRL beginner to from zero to hero.  Natalie and Chris explore what’s involved, and what the implications are, with a focus on the development path of the new AI data scientist.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Thomas Simonini – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Thomas Simonini | Hugging Face
Deep Reinforcement Learning course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tale of Two Features]]></title>
        <id>http://testing.googleblog.com/2022/02/a-tale-of-two-features.html</id>
        <link href="http://testing.googleblog.com/2022/02/a-tale-of-two-features.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T18:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By George Pirocanac


I have often been asked, “What is the most memorable bug that you have encountered in your testing career?” For me, it is hands down a bug that happened quite a few years ago. I was leading an Engineering Productivity team that supported Google App Engine. At that time App Engine was still in its early stages, and there were many challenges associated with testing rapidly evolving features. Our testing frameworks and processes were also evolving, so it was an exciting time to be on the team. 


What makes this bug so memorable is that I spent so much time developing a comprehensive suite of test scenarios, yet a failure occurred during such an obvious use case that it left me shaking my head and wondering how I had missed it. Even with many years of testing experience…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Testing Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A terrible January can be a source of opportunities]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/a-terrible-january-can-be-a-source</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/a-terrible-january-can-be-a-source"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T17:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bad start doesn't have to scare you!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code scanning and Ruby: turning source code into a queryable database]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62743</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-01-code-scanning-and-ruby-turning-source-code-into-a-queryable-database/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T17:07:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we add support for new languages to CodeQL.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Rolfe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top-100 npm package maintainers now require 2FA, and additional security-focused improvements to npm]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62786</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-02-01-top-100-npm-package-maintainers-require-2fa-additional-security/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T17:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting today, we are rolling out mandatory 2FA to all maintainers of top-100 npm packages by dependents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Borins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top-level `fetch` just landed in Node.js]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/JLO2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/nodejs/node/commit/6ec225392675c92b102d3caad02ee3a157c9d1b7"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T14:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s behind a --experimental-fetch flag for now and the Node team are seeking feedback on this very exciting feature. If you’re not well aware of the fetch API and why it’d be a productivity boon to have it in Node, check the MDN page on it.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demystifying Interviewing for Backend Engineers @ Netflix]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/aceb26a83495</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/demystifying-interviewing-for-backend-engineers-netflix-aceb26a83495?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T14:24:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Karen Casella, Director of Engineering, Access & Identity Management]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[curl with rust]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18332</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/02/01/curl-with-rust/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T08:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I did an online presentation with this name for the Rust Linz meetup, on January 27 2022. This is the recording: The individual slides are also available. Content quickly In this presentation I talk about how libcurl’s most important aspect is the stable ABI and API. If we just maintain those, we can change the … Continue reading curl with rust →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Only Solution That Scales With the Cybersecurity Challenge]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/ceo/only-solution-scales-cybersecurity-challenge</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/ceo/only-solution-scales-cybersecurity-challenge"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T21:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cybersecurity is stretched thin. We all know it, so why state it again? 

Because cybersecurity is thinner today than yesterday. Because many keep repeating the same measures that don’t work. And because there actually is a solution.

Facts are undeniable:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mårten Mickos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 477: Song Encoder: Forrest Brazeal]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1562</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/477"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Song Encoder, a special series of The Changelog podcast featuring people who create at the intersection of software and music. This episode features Pwnie Award-winning songwriter Forrest Brazeal.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Forrest Brazeal – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
168 AWS Services in 2 minutes
The Ransomware Song
That Sinking Feeling (The #HugOps Song)
Serverless v Containers
Look At You Now (The Google Cloud Song)
Kingston Trio-Merry Minuet
Big Tech ((It’s Probably Fine))
The AWS Elastic Load Balancer Yodel Rag
Song Encoder: $STDOUT]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacks Decoded: Adewale Adetona]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47585</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/01/hacks-decoded-adewale-adetona/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T17:44:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adetona Adewale Akeem, more popularly known as iSlimfit, is a Nigeria-born revered digital technologist and marketing expert. He is the co-founder of Menopays, a fintech startup offering another Buy Now Pay Later (BNPL) option across Africa. We chatted with him about founding Menopays and the impact of tech solutions developed in Nigeria. 
The post Hacks Decoded: Adewale Adetona appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xavier Harding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependency graph now supports GitHub Actions]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62734</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-31-dependency-graph-now-supports-github-actions/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T17:03:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The dependency graph helps developers and maintainers understand the code they depend on, and now includes GitHub Actions!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin Hutchings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A UX designer walks into a Tesla bar]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Lp75</id>
        <link href="https://jenson.org/tesla/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T15:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interesting exploration of Tesla’s recent update to their in-car control screen that resulted from the author not being able to find the defogger control. Here’s an example of the kind of analysis he provides:
Edward Tufte has this visual rule that 1+1=3. With a single line on the screen, you have just that single object, but adding a second line does something interesting, it adds a third ‘object’ on the screen, the negative space between the two. All good visual designers deeply understand this effect.
In UX design we have a cognitive equivalent. If you have two buttons, there is a third ‘object’ created, the decision a user must make on which button to tap. This cognitive load is invisible and rarely discussed but it can be a real source of confusion.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I discovered thousands of open databases on AWS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/bNel</id>
        <link href="https://infosecwriteups.com/how-i-discovered-thousands-of-open-databases-on-aws-764729aa7f32"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T14:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Avi Lumelsky shares his journey finding and reporting databases with sensitive data about Fortune-500 companies, hospitals, crypto platforms, startups during due diligence, and more.
His major entry point: misconfiguration
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advancing Jupyter Notebooks at Twitter - Part 1]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2021/advancing-jupyter-notebooks-at-twitter---part-1--a-first-class-d</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2021/advancing-jupyter-notebooks-at-twitter---part-1--a-first-class-d"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T12:13:24.172Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Notebook is Twitter’s internal notebook solution. It provides a first-class development environment to Data Scientist and Machine Learning practitioners at Twitter. This blog shares features o]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1,000 commit authors]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=17464</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/01/30/1000-commit-authors/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-30T22:24:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the curl project we switched to using git for source code control in March 2010. Since then we have exact tracking of every commit author to the project. In the times before git, we used CVS which doesn’t properly separate committers from authors. The number of commit authors in curl has gradually been increasing … Continue reading 1,000 commit authors →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 210: What's in your package.json?]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1557</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/210"/>
        <updated>2022-01-29T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tobie Langel, Open source strategist and Principal at UnlockOpen, joins Chris, Feross, and Amal to discuss recent widespread incidents affecting the JavaScript community (and breaking CI builds) around the globe. Two widely used npm libraries were self-sabotaged by their single maintainer, yet again, highlighting the many gaps in our OSS supply chain security, sustainability and overall practices. We explore all these topics and solution on what our ecosystem needs to be more resilient to these types of attacks in the future.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From error tracking to performance monitoring, Sentry hel…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get the daily Wordle on the first try using the tweet distribution]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/JLOA</id>
        <link href="https://www.kaggle.com/benhamner/wordle-1-6"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T16:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love how much hacking has been inspired by Wordle.
The Wordle source code contains 2,315 days of answers (all common 5-letter English words) and 10,657 other valid, less-common 5-letter English words.
We combine these to form a set of 12,972 possible words/answers.
We then simulate playing 1,000 Wordle games for each of these possible words, guessing based on the frequency of the word in the English language and the feedback received.
Then we take three measures to evaluate the observed distribution of ⬛🟨🟩 squares on Twitter according to our valid words.
The resulting code is included in the article.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two reasons Kubernetes is so complex]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Q5eM</id>
        <link href="https://buttondown.email/nelhage/archive/two-reasons-kubernetes-is-so-complex/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T15:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lots of people talk about Kubernets’ complexity, but it’s rare for someone to attempt to plumb the depths of why exactly that is.
I don’t claim to have the full answer, but this post is an attempt to commit to paper two specific thoughts or paradigms I have that I reach for as I try to understand why working with Kubernetes feels so hairy sometimes.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nine months into the DIB-VDP Pilot, nearly 1,000 valid vulnerabilities have been identified]]></title>
        <id>https://hackerone.com/customer-stories/nine-months-dib-vdp-pilot-nearly-1000-valid-vulnerabilities-have-been-identified</id>
        <link href="https://www.hackerone.com/customer-stories/nine-months-dib-vdp-pilot-nearly-1000-valid-vulnerabilities-have-been-identified"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With three months left in the 12-month pilot with the Department of Defense’s Defense Industrial Base Vulnerability Disclosure Pilot (DOD DIB-VDP Pilot), HackerOne sat down with DC3 to discuss why new DIB companies are joining the pilot and hear why hackers are a critical partner for the DOD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>HackerOne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founders Talk 86: Bringing observability superpowers to all]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/4/1561</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/founderstalk/86"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Adam is joined by Christine Yen, co-founder and CEO of Honeycomb. Christine and Adam recorded this show late last year, just after their Series C funding round. They talk about the superpower of observability for developers, how she and Charity Majors got to the place to found Honeycomb, the state of their platform today, what exactly observability is, and their goals for the future of Honeycomb.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
WorkOS – A platform that gives developers a set of building blocks for quickly adding enterprise-ready features to their application. Add Single Sign-On (Okta, Azure, Google, Microsoft OAuth), sync users from any SCIM directory, HRIS integration, audit trails (SIE…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 Transparency Report]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62686</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-27-2021-transparency-report/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T23:35:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In GitHub's latest transparency report, we’re giving you a by-the-numbers look at how we responded to requests for user info and content removal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rose Coogan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking beyond SQL injection: OWASP tips for secure database access]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62658</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-27-beyond-sql-injection-owasp-tips-secure-database-access/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T21:17:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it comes to secure database access, there's more to consider than SQL injections. OWASP Top 10 Proactive Control C3 offers guidance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alvaro Munoz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 214: Migrations without migraines]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1485</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/214"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the most common questions we receive at Go Time is how to handle schema migrations in Go. In this episode Jon is joined by Mike Fridman and Vojtech Vitek, maintainers of the popular schema migration tool pressly/goose, to discuss techniques, tools, and tips for handling schema migrations.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
GitLab – The DevOps platform that empowers organizations to maximize the overall return on software development by delivering software faster, more efficiently, while strengthening security and compliance. Identify and address blockers immediately, focus on delivering value — not maintaining integrations, automate security and compliance. Get started with their free tier (no credit card required). Learn more at about.gitlab.com/solutions/devops-platform

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Featuring
Mike Fridman – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Vojtech Vitek – Twitter, GitHub
Jon Calhoun – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
goose
migrate
squirrel]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pure Stocks Portfolio]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/the-pure-stocks-portfolio</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/the-pure-stocks-portfolio"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T17:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A model portfolio with my favorite picks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux for $15 (a Minimum Viable Computer)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/o9rm</id>
        <link href="https://bbenchoff.github.io/pages/LinuxDevice.html"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T16:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a ‘Linux Swiss Army Knife’, offering maximum utility while still being able to fit in your pocket. Is it fast? No. Can it run a GUI? Also no. But it can run scripts, ping a server, toggle a few GPIOs, and interact with a USB device.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open source startup alternatives to well-known SaaS products]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/rlry</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/RunaCapital/awesome-oss-alternatives"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The criteria for inclusion is as follows:
Its product is strongly based on an open source repo
It has a well-known closed-sourced competitor, solving a similar business problem
It is a private for-profit company, founded in the last 10 years
Its repo has 100+ stars on GitHub
I’m seeing lots of Changelog guests & friends in this awesome list. 😎
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 37: Building fully declarative systems with Nix]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1522</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/37"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vincent Ambo –the person behind nixery.dev, tvl.fyi, and a former Google engineer– shares his take on monorepos, Nix, and fully declarative systems without any Flux, Argo or Kubernetes.
While the tooling is impressive, it’s the principles behind it that captivated Gerhard’s imagination. Vincent has a rather interesting take on the monorepository idea, including one change - one version - one deploy. There are a lot of interesting links in the show notes, including all the code that Vincent uses to manage infrastructure.
As a result of this conversation, Gerhard is running Nix on one of his Macs, and also started experimenting with his first NixOS production instance.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing when to say 'no']]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/d3r2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/readme/guides/decision-framework"/>
        <updated>2022-01-26T19:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a piece that I wrote for GitHub’s ReadME project about an important aspect of software maintenance: recognizing which contributions are a good fit for a project—and which are not.
The thought process applies equally well to proprietary code bases and open source projects.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Parise</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get ready for Campus TV Season 2: 🌱 New Beginnings]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62624</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-26-get-ready-for-campus-tv-season-2-new-beginnings/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-26T17:59:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn new skills, build projects and meet like-minded students with the latest shows from the GitHub Education Stream Team.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan Pablo Flores Cortés</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The old internet shows signs of quietly coming back]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/eZrO</id>
        <link href="https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/old-internet-coming-back.html"/>
        <updated>2022-01-26T15:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Old as in old school cool not old as in passe:
Despite the new gatekeepers’ best efforts, the old Internet never completely disappeared. Personal websites created by individuals that have always been the meat of the old Internet are still around. They are still about exploration, innovation, fun, and all the rest. Try as the new gatekeepers have, they simply have not had the power to eradicate the old Internet completely. All they can do is pretend it does not exist. And, that is exactly what they do.
But…
… the old Internet seems to be slowly and quietly coming back, and it is coming back even better than before. Now it has better technology and an additional well-defined purpose that it never had before.
Some people have begun to refer to personal websites as the “indie web”, the “small Internet”, or the “smol Internet”. Some seem to reserve the last two terms exclusively for the Gemini Network, which nearly quadrupled in size last year. But, I think all three terms should also apply to some of the other networks that use alternative networking protocols–the Gopher Network, the Tor network, and the ZeroNet network, to name a few.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bug lurking for 12 years gives attackers root on every major Linux distro]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/RRe0</id>
        <link href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/01/a-bug-lurking-for-12-years-gives-attackers-root-on-every-major-linux-distro/?utm_brand=arstechnica"/>
        <updated>2022-01-26T14:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux users on Tuesday got a major dose of bad news—a 12-year-old vulnerability in a system tool called Polkit gives attackers unfettered root privileges on machines running any major distribution of the open source operating system.
Previously called PolicyKit, Polkit manages system-wide privileges in Unix-like OSes. It provides a mechanism for nonprivileged processes to safely interact with privileged processes. It also allows users to execute commands with high privileges by using a component called pkexec, followed by the command.
Oh my. It requires local access first, which is the only good news here.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 165: The world needs an AI superhero]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1564</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/165"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T22:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From drug discovery at the Quebec AI Institute to improving capabilities with low-resourced languages at the Masakhane Research Foundation and Google AI, Bonaventure Dossou looks for opportunities to use his expertise in natural language processing to improve the world - and especially to help his homeland in the Benin Republic in Africa.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Featuring
Bonaventure Dossou – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Bonaventure Dossou | Instagram
2020 — ongoing: My Year of Fame and how I joined the world of Research]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PRQL – a modern language for transforming data]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/13Qw</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/max-sixty/prql"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T19:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PRQL (pronounced “Prequel”) aims to be “a simpler and more powerful SQL”
Like SQL, it’s readable, explicit and declarative. Unlike SQL, it forms a logical pipeline of transformations, and supports abstractions such as variables and functions. It can be used with any database that uses SQL, since it transpiles to SQL.
To get an idea on PRQL’s design, they provide this SQL statement as an example:
SELECT TOP 20
    title,
    country,
    AVG(salary) AS average_salary,
    SUM(salary) AS sum_salary,
    AVG(salary + payroll_tax) AS average_gross_salary,
    SUM(salary + payroll_tax) AS sum_gross_salary,
    AVG(salary + payroll_tax + benefits_cost) AS average_gross_cost,
    SUM(salary + payroll_tax + benefits_cost) AS sum_gross_cost,
    COUNT(*) as count
FROM employees
WHERE salary + payroll_tax + benefits_cost > 0 AND country = 'USA'
GROUP BY title, country
ORDER BY sum_gross_cost
HAVING count > 200

And then translate it to PRQL, which looks like:
from employees
filter country = "USA"                           # Each line transforms the previous result.
let gross_salary = salary + payroll_tax          # This _adds_ a column / variable.
let gross_cost   = gross_salary + benefits_cost  # Variables can use other variables.
filter gross_cost > 0
aggregate by:[title, country] [                  # `by` are the columns to group by.
    average salary,                              # These are the calcs to run on the groups.
    sum     salary,
    average gross_salary,
    sum     gross_salary,
    average gross_cost,
    sum     gross_cost,
    count,
]
sort sum_gross_cost                              # Uses the auto-generated column name.
filter count > 200
take 20

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secure your GitHub account with GitHub Mobile 2FA]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62598</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-25-secure-your-github-account-github-mobile-2fa/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T16:41:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub continues to improve account security and developer experience with a new 2FA mechanism in GitHub Mobile on iOS and Android.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Berk Veral</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix: A Culture of Learning]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/394bc7d0f94c</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/netflix-a-culture-of-learning-394bc7d0f94c?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T16:23:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Tingley with Wenjing Zheng, Simon Ejdemyr, Stephanie Lane, Colin McFarland, Mihir Tendulkar, and Travis Brooks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I got pwned by my cloud costs]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/k2r2</id>
        <link href="https://www.troyhunt.com/how-i-got-pwned-by-my-cloud-costs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T15:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Troy Hunt (of Have I been Pwned fame) has been a vocal proponent of cloud-first services for awhile. Last December, that strategy came back to bite him:
It all started with my monthly Azure bill for December which was way over what it would normally be. It only took a moment to find the problem…
He goes on to tell the tale in excruciating detail. Be careful out there, cloud natives.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wordle built with Vue, aka VVordle]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/mar1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/yyx990803/vue-wordle"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T15:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rebuilding Wordle is a fun way to show off what your frontend framework is capable of (and how). Evan You has been doing just that for Vue. It’s not a 100% reproduction of the original, but it does have one cool feature the official game does NOT:
You can make your own Wordle and send it to friends by base64-encoding a word and include it as the URL query
Here’s a custom one using an acronym that many devs think about often…
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 476: Supabase is all in on Postgres]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1550</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/476"/>
        <updated>2022-01-25T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Paul Copplestone, CEO of Supabase joined us to catch us up on the next big thing happening in the world of Postgres. Supabase might be best known as “the open source Firebase alternative,” a tagline they might be reluctant to maintain. But from Adam’s perspective, he’s never been more excited about what they’re bringing to market for Postgres fans. In the last year, Supabase has gone from 0 to more than 80,000 databases on their platform — and they’re still in beta…and it’s open source. Hopefully today’s show sheds some light on why everyone is talking about Supabase.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Sentry – Working code means happy customers. That’s exactly why teams choose Sentry. From…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing Performance Regressions Before they Happen]]></title>
        <id>https://medium.com/p/eab2602b86fe</id>
        <link href="https://netflixtechblog.com/fixing-performance-regressions-before-they-happen-eab2602b86fe?source=rss----2615bd06b42e---4"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T21:49:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Netflix TVUI team implemented a robust strategy to quickly and easily detect performance anomalies before they a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Netflix Technology Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nu Impacto Manifesto: Nubank’s commitment to the adoption of ESG practices]]></title>
        <id>https://building.nubank.com.br/?p=18048</id>
        <link href="https://building.nubank.com.br/nu-impacto-manifesto/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T21:24:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To reinforce Nubank's commitment to caring for the environment, the positive social impact on people's lives, and the best corporate governance practices, today we launched a manifesto video. Watch now.
The post Nu Impacto Manifesto: Nubank’s commitment to the adoption of ESG practices appeared first on Building Nubank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nubank Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highlights from Git 2.35]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62535</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-24-highlights-from-git-2-35/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T20:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open source Git project just released Git 2.35. Here's GitHub's look at some of the most interesting features and changes introduced since last time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taylor Blau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The curse of NixOS]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/6O6d</id>
        <link href="https://blog.wesleyac.com/posts/the-curse-of-nixos"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wesley Aptekar-Cassels has been using NixOS on his main laptop for ~3 years and he’s ready to talk about it:
I don’t think that NixOS is the future, but I do absolutely think that the ideas in it are, so I want to write about what I think it gets right and what it gets wrong, in the hopes that other projects can take note. As such, this post will not assume knowledge of NixOS — if you’ve used NixOS significantly, there probably isn’t anything new in here for you.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soft Serve – a tasty, self-hostable git server for the command line🍦]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/03EQ</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/charmbracelet/soft-serve"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T16:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is just one of Charm’s various open source CLI projects.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A list of CS courses with video lectures 📽]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/lbPY</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/Developer-Y/cs-video-courses"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T15:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This repo links to dozens of courses for each of 23 categories of computing. It’s just an astounding amount of freely accessible education.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LogJ4 Security Inquiry – Response Required]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/?p=18206</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2022/01/24/logj4-security-inquiry-response-required/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T14:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Friday January 21, 2022 I received this email. I tweeted about it and it took off like crazy. The email comes from a fortune-500 multi-billion dollar company that apparently might be using a product that contains my code, or maybe they have customers who do. Who knows? My guess is that they do this … Continue reading LogJ4 Security Inquiry – Response Required →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Stenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevToys – an offline Swiss Army knife for developers]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/pknV</id>
        <link href="https://devtoys.app/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T14:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not very often that I get Windows FOMO, but DevToys is doing it for me. It provides a sweet GUI for 14 tools including a JSON/Yaml converter, a JWT decoder, a text comparer, and a hash generator.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · December 2021 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62405</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-21-release-radar-dec-2021/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T23:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many of us were wrapping up projects, emails, events, and getting ready for Christmas. While we were all busy getting ready for the festive season, our community was still hard at work shipping open source]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JS Party 209: What Cloudflare is up to]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/6/1506</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/jsparty/209"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudflare has a lot more to offer than merely DDoS protection and CDN services. On this episode, Jon Kuperman joins Amal & Jerod to talk through many of their cool new things like Workers, KV, Durable Objects, and R2 Storage. Thanks to listener Matt Mannucci for requesting this episode!
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Raygun – Never miss another mission-critical issue again — Raygun Alerting is now available for Crash Reporting and Real User Monitoring, to make sure you are quickly notified of the errors, crashes, and front-end performance issues that matter most to you and your business. Set thresholds for your alert based on an increase in error count, a spike in load time, or new issues introduced in the latest deployment. Start your free 14-day trial at Raygun.com

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Featuring
Jon Kuperman – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Amal Hussein – Twitter, GitHub
Jerod Santo – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
Workers
Workers Chat Demo
Argo Smart Routing
R2 announcement
Durable Objects
KV]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2022: False start for U.S. equities]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/2022-false-start-for-us-equities</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/2022-false-start-for-us-equities"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T16:15:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lot of pain for U.S. stocks, but there are bright spots elsewhere]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft as a k8s admin tool]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Z3De</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/erjadi/kubecraftadmin"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T15:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you landed here hoping this project isn’t serious… fear not. It’s just for fun, but it really works!
Have you ever thought to yourself: Why don’t we have an immersive 3D sandbox user interface to manage workloads on my favorite container orchestrator? No? Well here it is anyway.
Pigs are pods. Cows are ReplicaSets. Chickens are services. You get the drift.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop paying tech debts, start maintaining code]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/VJmm</id>
        <link href="https://blog.testdouble.com/posts/2022-01-20-stop-paying-debts-start-maintaining-code/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T15:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jesse O’Brien from Test Double wants us to stop using the term “Tech Debt”
There’s loads of reasons why unmaintainable code ends up running in the systems our products are built on, but none of these fit the definition of debt.
Instead, I propose we drop the term Tech Debt and start talking about maintenance tasks. Maintenance is what we’re really talking about. When parts on our car or bicycle suffers wear from driving them around, we don’t talk to our mechanic about “mechanical debt”. (Go back and re-read that sentence, but replace things with “software” and “programmers”). We talk about maintenance.
This post starts as mostly a semantic debate, and I’m not convinced by his arguments there. I think the debt metaphor is useful when you’re talking about trading quality for speed. That’s what you do when you take on debt: you trade higher cost at a future date (principle + interest) to gain access to the money today (speed).
That being said, I really like where Jesse ends this piece talking about software maintenance and methods of going about it. Lots of actionable advice there and I’m 100% onboard with talking about software maintenance early and often. One of the first things I consider when somebody approaches me with a feature idea is ask myself: what will this cost to maintain?
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A hands-on approach to getting started with Go generics]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/ykPR</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/akutz/go-generics-the-hard-way"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T14:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Kutz:
After spending some time playing with them, I began to appreciate how generics in Go have been designed and implemented with the same elegance and simplicity as Go itself. I hope you will agree, and to that end, this repository is a hands-on approach to learning all about generics in Go.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Investing in privacy enhancing tech to advance transparency in ML]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/investing-in-privacy-enhancing-tech-to-advance-transparency-in-ML</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/investing-in-privacy-enhancing-tech-to-advance-transparency-in-ML"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T12:13:58.073Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re investing in privacy-enhancing technologies (PET) to pioneer new methods of public accountability and access to data in a manner that respects and protects the privacy of people on Twitter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model-based candidate generation for account recommendations]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/model-based-candidate-generation-for-account-recommendations</id>
        <link href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/insights/2022/model-based-candidate-generation-for-account-recommendations"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T12:13:58.060Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we share how we improved account recommendations with a model-based candidate generation framework.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>English (US)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ship It! 36: Keep on-call simple]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/14/1523</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/shipit/36"/>
        <updated>2022-01-20T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gerhard loves simple ideas executed well, which is why he is excited to be speaking today with Ildar Iskhakov & Matvey Kukuy about their startup Amixr, a.k.a. Grafana OnCall.
Ildar & Matvey started with a simple idea and a simple stack - Django, Celery, RabbitMQ & MySQL - all running on Kubernetes. Because they kept their main thing their main thing, and kept improving it every day for a couple of years, now your on-call can be simple too.
This is another Big Tent philosophy story with a Black Swan moment towards the end.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
MongoDB – An integrated suite of cloud database and services — They have a FREE forever tier, so you can prove to yourself and to your team that t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eleventy v1.0.0, the stable release]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/Q5lM</id>
        <link href="https://www.zachleat.com/web/eleventy-one-point-oh/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-20T17:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eleventy creator, Zach Leatherman:
This project would not be possible without our lovely community. Thank you to everyone that built something with Eleventy (×476 authors on our web site!), wrote a blog post about Eleventy, contributed code to core or plugins, documentation, asked questions, answered questions, braved The Leaderboards, participated on Discord, filed issues, attended (or organized!) a meetup, said a kind word on Twitter ❤️.
Congrats to Zach and the entire Eleventy community on the big 1.0! 🎉
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Time 213: AI-driven development in Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/2/1399</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/gotime/213"/>
        <updated>2022-01-20T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alexey Palazhchenko joins Natalie to discuss the implications of GitHub’s Copilot on code generation. Go’s design lends itself nicely to computer generated authoring: thanks to go fmt, there’s already only one Go style. This means AI-generated code will be consistent and seamless. Its focus on simplicity & readability make it tailor made for this new approach to software creation. Where might this take us?
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
GitLab – The DevOps platform that empowers organizations to maximize the overall return on software development by delivering software faster, more efficiently, while strengthening security and compliance. Identify and address blockers immediately, focus on delivering value — not maintaining integrations, automate security and compliance. Get started with their free tier (no credit card required). Learn more at about.gitlab.com/solutions/devops-platform

    
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Featuring
Alexey Palazhchenko – Twitter, GitHub
Natalie Pistunovich – Twitter, GitHub
Notes and Links
FerretDB
OpenAI Codex
GitHub Copilot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open source creates value, but how do you measure it?]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62495</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-20-open-source-creates-value-but-how-do-you-measure-it/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-20T16:58:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When digital infrastructure is overlooked by governments, it isn't just a missed opportunity: policies may inadvertently endanger open source collaboration.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Cihon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git organized: a better git flow]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/8Ow8</id>
        <link href="https://render.com/blog/git-organized-a-better-git-flow"/>
        <updated>2022-01-20T14:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine this: you’ve been paged to investigate a production incident, and after some digging, you identify the commit with the breaking code. You decide to revert the change:
git revert 1a2b3c
Unfortunately, in doing so, a new bug is introduced! As it turns out, hidden in that old “broken” commit was some code that another part of the app depended upon, and when you reverted those lines, it left the site once again in a broken state. 🙃 Oh dear.
How can situations like this be avoided? To answer this question, we first need to examine how these types of commits come to be.
If you’ve never heard of or used git reset… this article is a must-read.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The truth about starting with microservices]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/rlPy</id>
        <link href="https://arnoldgalovics.com/truth-about-microservices/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T19:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arnold Galovics’ follow-up to his excellent monoliths are your friend post from late last year.
Starting a greenfield project with microservices is easy. The promises are wonderful but often they are far from reality. This time I’ll share my experience on the truth about microservices when starting a project from scratch.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effortless personal productivity (or how I learned to love my monkey mind)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/9Oma</id>
        <link href="https://jakobgreenfeld.com/personal-productivity"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T16:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jakob Greenfeld:
I recently discovered a simple step-by-step process that significantly increased my personal productivity and made me happier along the way.
It costs $0 and no, it’s not some note-taking or to-do list system.
The steps are:
develop meta-awareness of your state of mind.
pattern-match to identify your mind’s most common modes.
learn to pick activities that match each mode.
But that probably won’t hit home until you read through his explanation of each step.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical AI 164: Democratizing ML for speech]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/7/1560</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/practicalai/164"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might know about MLPerf, a benchmark from MLCommons that measures how fast systems can train models to a target quality metric. However, MLCommons is working on so much more! David Kanter joins us in this episode to discuss two new speech datasets that are democratizing machine learning for speech via data scale and language/speaker diversity.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Changelog++ – You love our content and you want to take it to the next level by showing your support. We’ll take you closer to the metal with no ads, extended episodes, outtakes, bonus content, a deep discount in our merch store (soon), and more to come. Let’s do this!

    
The Brave Browser – Browse the web up to 8x faster than Chrome and Safari, block ads and trackers by default, and reward your favorite creators with the built-in Basic Attention Token. Download Brave for free and give tipping a try right here on changelog.com.

    
Fastly – Our bandwidth partner. Fastly powers fast, secure, and scalable digital experiences. Move beyond your content delivery network to their powerful edge cloud platform. Learn more at fastly.com

    
Featuring
David Kanter – Twitter, GitHub
Chris Benson – Twitter, GitHub, LinkedIn, Website
Daniel Whitenack – Twitter, GitHub, Website
Notes and Links
Press Release about MLCommons datasets: MLCommons™ Association Unveils Open Datasets and Tools to Drive Democratization of Machine Learning
NeurIPS Papers:

People’s Speech Dataset
Multilingual Spoken Words Corpus (MSWC)
Gradient article: New Datasets to Democratize Speech Recognition Technology
Blog posts for more insight:

People’s Speech
Multilingual Spoken Words Corpus (MSWC)
Downloads:

People’s Speech
Multilingual Spoken Words Corpus]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing security risk in open source software with GitHub Actions and OpenSSF Scorecards V4]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62472</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-19-reducing-security-risk-oss-actions-opensff-scorecards-v4/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to announce the V4 release of the OpenSSF’s Scorecard project in partnership with Google.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jose Palafox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing Security Risks in Open Source Software at Scale: Scorecards Launches V4]]></title>
        <id>http://security.googleblog.com/2022/01/reducing-security-risks-in-open-source.html</id>
        <link href="http://security.googleblog.com/2022/01/reducing-security-risks-in-open-source.html"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T15:00:00.014Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Laurent Simon and Azeem Shaikh, Google Open Source Security Team (GOSST) 



Since our July announcement of Scorecards V2, the Scorecards project—an automated security tool to flag risky supply chain practices in open source projects—has grown steadily to over 40 unique contributors and 18 implemented security checks. Today we are proud to announce the V4 release of Scorecards, with larger scaling, a new security check, and a new Scorecards GitHub Action for easier security automation.
The Scorecards Action is released in partnership with GitHub and is available from GitHub's Marketplace. The Action makes using Scorecards easier than ever: it runs automatically on repository changes to alert developers about risky supply-chain practices. Maintainers can view the alerts on GitHub's code scanning dashboard, which is available for free to public repositories on GitHub.com and via GitHub Advanced Security for private repositories. 
Additionally, we have scaled our weekly Scorecards scans to over one million GitHub repositories, and have partnered with the Open Source Insights website for easy user access to the data. 
For more details about the release, including the new Dangerous-Workflow security check, visit the OpenSSF's official blog post here.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google Online Security Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changelog 475: Making the ZFS file system]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/1/1544</id>
        <link href="https://changelog.com/podcast/475"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Matt Ahrens joins Adam to talk about ZFS. Matt co-founded the ZFS project at Sun Microsystems in 2001. And 20 years later Adam picked up ZFS for use in his home lab and loved it. So, he reached out to Matt and invited him on the show. They cover the origins of the file system, its journey from proprietary to open source, architecture choices like copy-on-write, the ins and outs creating and managing ZFS, RAID-Z and RAID-Z expansion, and Matt even shares plans for ZFS in the cloud with ZFS object store.
Discuss on Changelog News
Join Changelog++ to support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear!
Sponsors
Square – Develop on the platform that sellers trust. There is a massive opportunity for developers to support Square sellers by building apps for today’s bu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Changelog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imperative vs declarative programming]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/eZPO</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E7Fbf7R3x6I"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an excellent explanation of the difference between these styles of programming and why declarative is all the rage these days.

Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I enjoy PostgreSQL (an infra engineer's perspective)]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/RR50</id>
        <link href="https://www.shayon.dev/post/2022/17/why-i-enjoy-postgresql-infrastructure-engineers-perspective/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T19:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post by Shayon Mukherjee is in response to the recently logged post by Mike Coutermarsh in praise of MySQL for infra folks:
This is not a MySQL vs PostgreSQL post. This is just a small summary of what I have come to appreciate about PostgreSQL as an Infrastructure Engineer.
Always good to keep in mind whenever comparing technologies: trade-offs abound and certain people in certain situations will value certain things about different technologies differently. That’s for certain. 😉
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jerod Santo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How open source is supporting NASA’s new eyes in space]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=62454</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2022-01-18-how-open-source-is-supporting-nasas-new-eyes-in-space/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T17:41:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the successful liftoff of the James Webb Space Telescope, we ask our very own Arfon Smith about the history of open source and space science.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicole Numrich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zooming in on Zero-click Exploits]]></title>
        <id>https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2022/01/zooming-in-on-zero-click-exploits.html</id>
        <link href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2022/01/zooming-in-on-zero-click-exploits.html"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T17:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-4{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-3{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-0>li:before{content:"-  "}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-2{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-1{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-1>li:before{content:"-  "}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-8{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-7{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-6{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-5{list-style-type:none}ul.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-0{list-style-type:none}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-7>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-6>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-8>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-5>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-3>li:before{content:"-  "}.lst-kix_ef7dug197aaw-2>li:before{content…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Project Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Balanced Portfolio]]></title>
        <id>https://marketradar.substack.com/p/the-balanced-portfolio</id>
        <link href="https://marketradar.substack.com/p/the-balanced-portfolio"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T16:35:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A detailed presentation of an ETF Portfolio]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Market Radar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building GitHub Apps with Go]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/k2P2</id>
        <link href="https://martinheinz.dev/blog/65"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T16:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re using GitHub as your version control system of choice then GitHub Apps can be incredibly useful for many tasks including building CI/CD, managing repositories, querying statistical data and much more. In this article we will walk through the process of building such an app in Go including setting up the GitHub integration, authenticating with GitHub, listening to webhooks, querying GitHub API and more.
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Heinz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contributing to MDN: Meet the Contributors]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47555</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2022/01/contributing-to-mdn-meet-the-contributors/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T16:07:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve ever built anything with web technologies, you’re probably familiar with MDN Web Docs. With about 13,000 pages documenting how to use programming languages such as HTML, CSS and JavaScript, the site has about 8,000 people using it at any given moment. MDN relies on contributors to help maintain its ever-expanding and up to date documentation. We reached out to 4 long-time community contributors to talk about how and why they started contributing, why they kept going, and ask what advice they have for new contributors.
The post Contributing to MDN: Meet the Contributors appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesca Minelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why infrastructure engineers prefer MySQL]]></title>
        <id>changelog.com/news/73dp</id>
        <link href="https://mikecoutermarsh.com/why-infrastructure-engineers-prefer-mysql/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T15:40:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Mike Coutermarsh:
For years I’ve been noticing this pattern of infrastructure engineers I really respect preferring MySQL and product engineers preferring Postgres. It took quite a while for me to understand it. Especially coming from my background as a product engineer. Infrastructure engineers generally…
Read on to hear why (from Mike’s perspective).
Discuss on Changelog News]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Stacoviak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>